<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-13T23:02:33+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Letters To Summer</title><subtitle>Two friends sharing the things they're reading, watching, listening to, and enjoying. In your inbox every other Thursday.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Letter 32</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/32" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 32" /><published>2020-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/32</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/32">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-goals&quot;&gt;On goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime last year, Summer and another friend and I started a monthly email thread to plan and talk about our goals for the coming month, followed by the occasional video chat for progress updates. We talked about things we wanted to accomplish in our careers, in our personal lives, and in our relationships, but we also talked about our feelings, our anxieties, the things we’re grateful for, and the things we need help with. What started as a way to voice our goals and desires and to hold each other accountable became a pleasant excuse to catch up with each other and just &lt;em&gt;talk&lt;/em&gt;. And I really can’t overstate how nice that is. We have recommended several methods for setting and tracking goals in this newsletter—including &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/6&quot;&gt;a habit-tracking app&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/4&quot;&gt;goal-tracking spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/27&quot;&gt;workbook for setting yearly goals&lt;/a&gt;, and the app mentioned below—but this is the only one that encourages community with people you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year, Oscars season approaches, and I tell myself &lt;em&gt;I will watch every film nominated for Best Picture.&lt;/em&gt; Sometimes I’ve already seen a handful in theaters, some years I haven’t seen any at all. This year was less than more, from a combination of disinterest, snubs, and general anxiety at being in Public and Seen. The best I did, before this year, was 2015 when torrenting was my friend (but of course I don’t do that anymore; I’m very cool and lawful). I’m not sure why I love awards shows, but I have since even before I loved to be mad online and wasn’t familiar with any material being awarded. I watched 15 hours of movies from Wednesday–Sunday, while still keeping my room relatively clean and putting together a viewing party with my roommate. I still didn’t see all of the Best Picture nominations, but I was satisfied with my breadth. I set a lot of goals for personal and professional development—many that I do not meet—but it’s fun to make something very &lt;em&gt;arbitrary,&lt;/em&gt; like a quota of movies, and to achieve it. Goal-setting can be fun. There can be enough time if I make enough time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-pain--glory&quot;&gt;🎥 Pain &amp;amp; Glory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was part of my Oscars binge, one of the films nominated for Best International Picture—and Antonio Banderas for Best Actor. Folks! Do you ever watch 14 hours of film directed by straight men and get exhausted, think all movies are just too long, wonder when directors stopped listening to their editors, triggering an existential spiral? And then you watch &lt;em&gt;Pain &amp;amp; Glory,&lt;/em&gt; and you are healed? I highly recommend watching this even without the saturation of indulgence beforehand. Antonio Banderas is so good, especially when I realized his most notable role for me is, in fact, &lt;em&gt;Spy Kids.&lt;/em&gt; The story follows an aging queer director, reflecting on his past and contending with his present. It is extremely tender, generous with time, and just &lt;em&gt;beautiful.&lt;/em&gt; Again, healed. Check it out, hopefully in a theater near you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tangerine&quot;&gt;📱Tangerine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tangerine.app&quot;&gt;this app&lt;/a&gt; for a few months as a beta tester, and I’m so happy that it is finally out there in the world for everyone else to use! Tangerine combines two of my favorite things—habit tracking, and mood tracking—in a beautiful and easy-to-use way. It’s made a difference in the way I approach my daily habits and routines, and has quickly become one of my most-used apps. You can download it on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/tangerine/id1468882685&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-birds-of-prey-the-fantabulous-emancipation-of-one-harley-quinn&quot;&gt;🎥 Birds of Prey: The Fantabulous Emancipation of One Harley Quinn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry, I’m recommending two movies!!!! I’ve really done nothing else since the last letter. So, I truly do not give a fuck about the DCEU, and the sparing few movies I’ve seen from that set have been pretty bad-to-mediocre. And yet! I hate that I’m basically recommending this movie because #representation, but it was really so fucking fun. A wonderfully talented cast with women of color, queer characters who get to exist besides that, a perfect soundtrack, bright colors and exciting fight scenes…there’s no reason not to see it! I love to have fun! I would die for Margot Robbie. Ewan McGregor is the best villain. Directed by Cathy Yan. Also in theaters now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-desk-lunch&quot;&gt;💌 Desk Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I (obviously) love newsletters, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.desklunchnewsletter.com&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; is one of my very favorites. Every issue of Desk Lunch is written by a different creative person about their process, their life, their journey, their thoughts. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/desklunchnewsletter/issue-97-perpetually-seeking-carolyn-yoo?e=b36865b50b&quot;&gt;latest issue&lt;/a&gt;, which I read this morning, was so good and relevant to me in particular—Carolyn Yoo writes about struggling to answer &lt;em&gt;“The Question”&lt;/em&gt; of her career path: “Perhaps I would keep searching for what I was meant to do for many more years of my life, but I could learn to embrace the spiral instead of resenting that I hadn’t reached an answer yet.” Whew. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.us16.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=9a0a385211ebb7b21b0ef828a&amp;amp;id=908a07a835&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to Desk Lunch for more great stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="💌 Newsletter" /><summary type="html">On goals</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 31</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/31" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 31" /><published>2020-01-30T16:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-30T16:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/31</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/31">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-social-media&quot;&gt;On social media&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time for my scheduled annual spiral about social media—that lovely time of year when I wonder what I’m doing on Instagram and Twitter, what I’m trying to get out of it, what I should be posting, who I actually care about following, and what it all means. The cycle goes like this: I decide I want to spend less time feeling bad on social media, so I unfollow a bunch of accounts that aren’t contributing to my life in a meaningful way to clear up my feed and make it easier to less time scrolling and more time seeing only the content I care about; a week later, I get bored and decide I’m not getting enough out of social media, so I find and follow a bunch of new accounts that are exciting or inspiring to me in some way; then, the cycle continues. Maybe the trick is to make peace with this ebb and flow of being very online, instead of feeling weird and bad about it. Maybe the trick is just &lt;em&gt;not overthinking it&lt;/em&gt;. For now, I still don’t really know what I’m doing and I still feel very conflicted about the way I use social media—but if I figure it out, I’ll let you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve lived most of my life online. I found my first internet friends when I was 10, feeling alone, caring too much about too many things; I’m 22 now, and sort of the same. My friends are far away, my boyfriend is far away, my family is far away. I’ve loved so many people from such a distance. As social media becomes part of everyone’s social habits, inextricable from the “real world,” those friendships are stronger, but they’re intertwined with everything that sucks. I read about a shooting and wish my friend a happy birthday in the same thought; I read about my people fighting for their freedom and see others celebrating a game before I finish the headline. I never want to be an old man shouting at a cloud. We can all care about so, so many things, and that is how I got here in the first place. I never want to dismiss the lifesaving connections social media has brought me. I don’t know how to navigate my escapism collapsing into what I escape from, even though it’s been happening for years—even more, I don’t know how to deal with the fact that I don’t want to escape anymore. I want to &lt;em&gt;know.&lt;/em&gt; I don’t want distance. From anyone, from anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-reconstructions-by-bradley-trumpfheller&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;strong&gt;Reconstructions&lt;/strong&gt; by Bradley Trumpfheller&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend has a chapbook and it’s one of the most stunning things you will read in 2020. (I don’t care that it’s only January!) Bradley is ridiculously talented. Each of their poems just feels in love with the medium, in love with the page, trying to run off of it—there’s an elegance to the weight of just how  &lt;em&gt;impressive&lt;/em&gt; their work is. I read it on a plane &amp;amp; studied it for hours after. It deserves so, so much attention. You can buy &lt;em&gt;Reconstructions&lt;/em&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://siblingrivalrypress.bigcartel.com/product/reconstructions-by-bradley-trumpfheller&quot;&gt;Sibling Rivalry Press website!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-how-to-do-nothing&quot;&gt;📖 How To Do Nothing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think everyone should be required to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781612197494&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt;, full stop. I highlighted lines on nearly every page, but here is a favorite, from the introduction, that will give you a sense of what this book is all about: “The point of doing nothing, as I define it, isn’t to return to work refreshed and ready to be more productive, but rather to question what we currently perceive as productive.” This is not just a book about birdwatching and quitting Facebook—it is a book about collective action and shared public spaces and attention and art and community. If you’ve read it, DM me so we can talk. If you haven’t, you need to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-high-school-musical-the-musical-the-series&quot;&gt;📺 High School Musical: The Musical: The Series&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RlaV8sJGhfc&quot;&gt;trailer dropped&lt;/a&gt; for this show, all I could think was &lt;em&gt;this is for me.&lt;/em&gt; I’m a survivor of the Glee fandom (as is Jillian), and yes! It did warp my brain! I am hungry for disaster surrounded by a song (this explains why I can’t stop thinking about &lt;em&gt;CATS (2019),&lt;/em&gt; too)!  I wanted this show to be like &lt;em&gt;Riverdale,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Nancy Drew,&lt;/em&gt; just absurd and a good time and makes you think &lt;em&gt;wait, am I so irony-poisoned that I’ve turned this into my favorite show?&lt;/em&gt; BUT! TWIST! This show is actually fucking great! No irony! Full seriousness! It holds all of the camp and cradles it, it acknowledges its predecessors (&lt;em&gt;HSM&lt;/em&gt; as much as &lt;em&gt;Glee&lt;/em&gt; as much as all other teen comedies), and does so, so good by its teens. Basically everyone gets complexity, everyone gets a full life, they are kind, they are mean, and they are jealous, but never cartoonishly or destructively. They sing well but it doesn’t feel like, &lt;em&gt;oh ok cool we love 30-year-old Broadway veterans&lt;/em&gt;. There are characters of color, there are queer characters (QPOC, even!) There’s a Palestinian flag! Just! In the background of a scene? Yes, reader, I cried! Watch it on Disney+, my reluctant ally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-shrill&quot;&gt;📺 Shrill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked through our archives to see if we had already mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hulu.com/series/shrill-54eab813-3a9b-496d-9d7e-908597ad8d1a&quot;&gt;this show&lt;/a&gt;, because I was &lt;em&gt;sure&lt;/em&gt; we had—but somehow, no! Which is a problem, because this show is brilliant and funny and makes me feel so good. The second season just came out on Hulu, and we are all so lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="📺 TV" /><summary type="html">On social media</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 30</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/30" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 30" /><published>2020-01-16T15:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-16T15:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/30</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/30">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-procrastination&quot;&gt;On procrastination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredibly appropriate that I waited until the very last minute to write this. Like, if you’re reading this right after it went up, I probably just finished writing this ten minutes ago. Even now, I am doing my very best to avoid writing this by doing other work instead. I would love to say that we draft this newsletter days before we send it out (and sometimes we do!) but more often than not we are scrambling to put it together the day of. You never stop procrastinating, even as an adult—even when the thing you are procrastinating is something like doing laundry or making plans with a friend you haven’t seen in a while, instead of the kinds of things you avoided doing in high school, like math homework and studying for finals. When I was a kid, I thought procrastinating meant I was lazy, or a bad student. I didn’t learn to recognize it as a symptom of anxiety until later. (And listen: sometimes it’s both. Sometimes I very much am just lazy.) The only thing I know for sure about procrastination is that it isn’t the big, scary monster it sometimes feels like; everyone procrastinates, it’s fine, we’re all fine, and it will feel so much better once you just do the thing you’re avoiding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very critical of myself, blame myself for a lot of things that are maybe not fault, suffer from depression—I’m not great at getting things done on time! Leaving school has given me a different perception of time, truly, and the types of tasks I put off, and why I’m putting them off; starting an assignment was always such a chore, but putting away my laundry is, too, deep-cleaning my room, grocery shopping, all of the above. Nothing is as bad if you just start. I create my own time and deadlines now, and instead of working towards a degree I’m working towards my health. I don’t want to put off cleaning my room because then the dust builds up and my lungs hurt, my lungs hurt and I don’t want to clean, the vicious cycle. I put off writing poems until I feel better. I end up doing almost nothing at all, mechanically going to work, coming home, brushing my teeth, going to bed. Procrastination means something different, less risking a grade and my sense of achievement and more something more severe, but I am doing it less. I am sticking to some schedules, following through in some ways. It feels better to know I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-hustlers&quot;&gt;📽️ Hustlers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started this movie about ten minutes before the Golden Globes were over, feeling exhausted as I normally do while watching the Golden Globes. While the Oscars nominations didn’t fix that (Jennifer Lopez robbed! &lt;em&gt;Uncut Gems&lt;/em&gt; robbed!), movies are still good! Halfway through, my roommate and I looked at each other and said, “Perhaps this is the best movie ever made? Perhaps, favorite film of all time?” The needle drops are magical, Jennifer Lopez and Constance Wu are so fucking strong, the supporting cast is brilliant, and just throughout you feel the thriving competence! Motherhood is complex! Fuck the systems that harm you! Women!!!!! Oscar for Lorene Scafaria!!!! It’s available to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lT_ot9Lud4c&quot;&gt;rent&lt;/a&gt; on a few streaming platforms, but I’m probably gonna go get the DVD to put into my non-existent DVD player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-pastel-nintendo-switch-joycons&quot;&gt;🎮 Pastel Nintendo Switch joycons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very tentative recommendation, because it involves voiding the warranty on your Switch, using tiny screwdrivers to take apart your joycons, messing with the tiny, fragile pieces that make the joycons work, and somehow putting it all back together again properly. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jilliangmeehan/status/1216410858991116289&quot;&gt;I did it&lt;/a&gt;, and it took two tries, but it turned out great and now I have a very cute, pastel Switch. Proceed with caution! Do your research! Find tutorials to follow along with! (And probably only do this if you have a backup pair of joycons, lbr.) Oh, and here are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/eXtremeRate-Handheld-Controller-Replacement-Nintendo/dp/B07NVLH8PR&quot;&gt;joycon shells&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/eXtremeRate-Nintendo-Switch-Handheld-Controller-Replacement/dp/B07NVMXNM8/ref=pd_sim_b2b_5/144-3376423-1654755?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=B07NVMXNM8&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=2676276a-9bfd-49b2-beb9-cc74e71d294a&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=95Hgh&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=fM8QG&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=a07701e4-f565-442a-b97f-93ab23cbb7ef&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=8EDC70YF06AVQZMJCPYQ&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=8EDC70YF06AVQZMJCPYQ&quot;&gt;backplate&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/GeekShare-Silicone-Sakura-Joystick-Caps-Switch-nintendo/dp/B07W6L39V6/ref=pd_bxgy_147_3/144-3376423-1654755?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=B07W6L39V6&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=2676276a-9bfd-49b2-beb9-cc74e71d294a&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=VdBhM&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=fM8QG&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=09627863-9889-4290-b90a-5e9f86682449&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=8EDC70YF06AVQZMJCPYQ&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=8EDC70YF06AVQZMJCPYQ&quot;&gt;joystick caps&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/eXtremeRate-Replacement-Direction-Nintendo-Included/dp/B07PLXN2JZ/ref=pd_sim_b2b_1/144-3376423-1654755?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=B07PN35QG4&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=2676276a-9bfd-49b2-beb9-cc74e71d294a&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=95Hgh&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=fM8QG&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=a07701e4-f565-442a-b97f-93ab23cbb7ef&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=8EDC70YF06AVQZMJCPYQ&amp;amp;refRID=8EDC70YF06AVQZMJCPYQ&amp;amp;th=1&quot;&gt;button replacements&lt;/a&gt; that I used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-my-year-in-mensa&quot;&gt;🎙️ My Year in Mensa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recommended &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamieloftusisinnocent.com/&quot;&gt;Jamie Loftus’s&lt;/a&gt; work a few times on this letter, but here we go again! On January 1st she dropped a &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/jamie-loftus&quot;&gt;4-episode podcast series&lt;/a&gt; about her year in the Smart People Club? Eugenics society? Mensa! It is, expectedly, hilarious, but it’s also a really interesting history, truly riveting because you fear for her safety, and a nice dive into &lt;em&gt;people who think differently than you&lt;/em&gt; that, spoiler, doesn’t end with you being told to sympathize with people who want to cause you harm!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-listen-to-animal-crossing-music-while-you-work&quot;&gt;🎶 Listen to Animal Crossing music while you work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or while you’re not working, whatever, that works too. &lt;a href=&quot;http://tane.us/ac/&quot;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; plays the Animal Crossing soundtracks from whichever version of the game you want on a constant loop, changing the music depending on the time. Personally, I prefer the original Gamecube soundtrack for maximum nostalgic vibes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="🎙️ Podcast" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><summary type="html">On procrastination</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 29</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/29" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 29" /><published>2020-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/29</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/29">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-gratitude&quot;&gt;On gratitude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time thinking about gratitude this year, actually recognizing it as a tool in my life for the first time, actively practicing the act of feeling grateful and letting it transform the way I think and feel. I wrote down the things I am grateful for, and thought about those things, instead of dwelling on what hurt me. I won’t list all of those things here, but I will say that, above all, I have felt the most grateful for the feeling of &lt;em&gt;home&lt;/em&gt; that I have found in my life. Finding gratitude has made me happier—that seems like such a simple way of putting it, but it’s true. Here is a simple thing to do that will have an impact on your life: think about what are you are grateful for today, write it down, say it out loud, commit it to memory, recognize it. Do it again tomorrow, and the next day, and the day after that, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the first day of the year &amp;amp; I’ve seen a thousand wrap-up threads full of people’s accomplishments. I have very little to link people to besides this letter as an object of things I have finished, and I am okay with it. I almost said I didn’t accomplish anything, but that is not true—I wrote a thesis, I was on a slam team, I graduated, I got a job, I was honest with my feelings again &amp;amp; again &amp;amp; again. But really, I am really, truly thankful to be surrounded by an immense amount of talented people. I toyed with doing a gratitude thread, just publicly thanking the dozens of people who made me feel safe &amp;amp; loved in 2019, but it felt silly; I can just tell them personally! In the last year or so, I’ve gotten into the habit of telling people when I think of them even if we haven’t spoken in a while, generally checking-in by text, etc. I’m not sure if the practice has improved any of my relationships but it does feel nice to feel free telling people they are on your mind. I want to continue this, push it further. I’m grateful for my friends, but I want to be specific with it, and everything else moving forward. Tell people you love them!!!!! It’s so so good!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-little-women-2019&quot;&gt;🎥 Little Women (2019)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel bold recommending this without having read the book nor seeing any other adaption, but folks! This movie was a warm hug but also not like, necessarily comforting. Maybe more like a solemn “yeah,” a nod, and a pat on the back. It was beautiful. I am in love with every cast member. I think about Greta Gerwig and all of the discourse her name carries (just ask if you don’t know, lol) almost constantly these days, and since seeing &lt;em&gt;Little Women&lt;/em&gt; my thoughts have been basically all positive. If you were on the fence about seeing it, go have fun! Cry a little! Yearn for poofy skirts &amp;amp; leather bound-books!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-conversations-with-friends-by-sally-rooney&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;Conversations with Friends&lt;/em&gt; by Sally Rooney&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9780451499066&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; destroyed me. I feel like I am the last person on earth to read &lt;em&gt;Conversations with Friends&lt;/em&gt;, but I would feel silly not mentioning it in a newsletter about things I love, because I truly loved it. It’s exactly as good as everyone says, and as soon as I started reading it I could feel all of my friends laughing at me, because it felt like it was engineered in a lab to be exactly the book I needed to read. Maybe it’s exactly the book you need to read, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-mandalorian&quot;&gt;📺 The Mandalorian&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;em&gt;The Rise of Skywalker&lt;/em&gt; the day it came out and it was awful, for reasons I do not need to get into right now, but personally the worst part of my viewing was perhaps 3/4ths of the way through when all I could think was, “Wait…maybe all &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; are bad? Have I been caught in a nostalgia loop since the earlier 2000s?” But no! &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; is good, camp is good, etc etc. And this show! Reinforces how much I love that franchise! It gives a nice look at places in the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; universe without it always being life-or-death and, strangely, explores a very healthy father-son relationship. Pedro Pascal is so good!!!! And he’s in a big hunk of metal suit the whole time!!!! I WILL die for The Child!!! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.disneyplus.com/welcome/the-mandalorian?cid=DSS-Search-Bing-71700000059616291&amp;amp;s_kwcid=AL!%208468!10!79439826966918!79440062238821&amp;amp;msclkid=b11e59106ae311c23f93071e43432922&amp;amp;gclid=CJaH89a55eYCFdEEiAkd6i4N0Q&amp;amp;gclsrc=ds&quot;&gt;Watch it&lt;/a&gt; on your brother’s Disney+ account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-welcome-to-union-glacier&quot;&gt;📽️ Welcome to Union Glacier&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over a week ago, I was reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25776682-the-abundance&quot;&gt;The Abundance&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of Annie Dillard essays, and the final chapter was a bit from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12534.Teaching_a_Stone_to_Talk&quot;&gt;Teaching a Stone to Talk&lt;/a&gt; about Antarctica. Something about the way she wrote about antarctic exploration and expeditions made me hungry for more (isn’t it fun to get suddenly very into a niche topic like this?) and my boyfriend recommended &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/107231188&quot;&gt;this documentary&lt;/a&gt; about Union Glacier and the small team of people who work there. I watched it on a cold day in my apartment, feeling cozy on the couch with a cup of tea, and I loved it. And please, if you have any of your own recommendations for Antarctica-related content, send it my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="📺 TV" /><summary type="html">On gratitude</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 28</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/28" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 28" /><published>2019-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/28</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/28">&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-2019-favorites&quot;&gt;Our 2019 favorites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe we’ve been doing this newsletter for over a year, but here we are! For our last letter of 2019, we took a look back at everything we recommended this year and chose our absolute favorites to revisit. Here are the ten things we still really love—maybe you’ll love them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-reems-muhammara-recipe&quot;&gt;🍽 Reem’s Muhammara Recipe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talk about Reem’s all of the time, and I think about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aramcoworld.com/Articles/July-2019/Flavors-Reem-s-Muhammara&quot;&gt;this muhammara&lt;/a&gt; everyday; I won’t make it again until I have a bigger food processor, but I treasure the experience, weirdly, of peeling the red bell peppers while they cool down, sort of blistering my hands, knowing how much I truly love making food. You can read my original recommendation &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/18&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-youper&quot;&gt;📱 Youper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past year, I’ve gotten really into journaling and mood tracking, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youper.ai/&quot;&gt;this app&lt;/a&gt; has been my daily companion in both. I loved it when I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/13&quot;&gt;my original recommendation&lt;/a&gt;, and I still love it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-hard-damage-by-aria-aber&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;Hard Damage&lt;/em&gt; by Aria Aber&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started re-reading this the other day, cementing it as my favorite of 2019; Aria is brilliant and heartbreaking. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nebraskapress.unl.edu/university-of-nebraska-press/9781496215703/&quot;&gt;Buy her book&lt;/a&gt;, and read my original recommendation &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/20&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-xoxo&quot;&gt;🎉 XOXO&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have gone to Portland for &lt;a href=&quot;https://xoxofest.com/&quot;&gt;XOXO&lt;/a&gt; two years in a row, and I feel very certain that I will continue going every year for as long as possible. When I &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/22&quot;&gt;first shared it&lt;/a&gt; in this newsletter, I had just gotten back from my second time attending this weird, wonderful conference, and I was already looking forward to going back. So I’ll say it again: if you have the opportunity, please go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-polygons-unraveled&quot;&gt;📺 Polygon’s Unraveled&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLaDrN74SfdT7Ueqtwn_bXo1MuSWT0ji2w&quot;&gt;Brian David Gilbert&lt;/a&gt; continues to make me laugh when I am very, very, sad. The videos just keep getting more elaborate and have given me comfort most consistently throughout 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/11&quot;&gt;I’m saying nothing new!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-no-knead-bread&quot;&gt;🍽️ No-knead bread&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a lot of bread this year, and almost all of it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-noknead-bread-home-109343&quot;&gt;this no-knead bread&lt;/a&gt; that I am still in love with. It’s easy, great for beginners, and very delicious. &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/8&quot;&gt;My original recommendation&lt;/a&gt; still rings true—this bread has never let me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-kingdom-animalia-by-aracelis-girmay&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Animalia&lt;/em&gt; by Aracelis Girmay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll never shut up about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9780140559965?aff=PublishersWeekly&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt;! I read it in June and I read it in August and I’ll read it again and again and again and again once I get my own copy! I am chasing that feeling of &lt;em&gt;overwhelmed&lt;/em&gt; with every piece of media I engage with and this one will never stop giving. I love it. Read my first recommendation &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/22&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cute-ify-your-calendar&quot;&gt;📱 Cute-ify your calendar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using a calendar app (I am using three, because I’m me) you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/14&quot;&gt;put some effort into making it nice to look at&lt;/a&gt;. All of my event names have emojis in them, and my calendars are light pinks, purples, and peaches—because default colors are boring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-rilo-kileys-the-execution-of-all-things&quot;&gt;🎶 Rilo Kiley’s The Execution of All Things&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, Rilo Kiley didn’t end up being one of my Spotify wrapped top 5 artists. However, many of the songs from the album were on my top 100 playlist—&lt;em&gt;A Better Son / Daughter&lt;/em&gt; near the top. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/23EqcK0ZR1ravQaEsGpQyH&quot;&gt;This album&lt;/a&gt; came near the end of my 2019 when I truly needed a new way to communicate certain feelings. It helped and it continues to help. If you want my raw, spiral-y reaction, &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/23&quot;&gt;that’s in Letter 23&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-how-to-not-always-be-working-by-marlee-grace&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;How to Not Always Be Working&lt;/em&gt; by Marlee Grace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Not-Always-Working-Creativity/dp/0062803670/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1554865512&amp;amp;sr=8-1https://www.amazon.com/How-Not-Always-Working-Creativity/dp/0062803670/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1554865512&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;This book&lt;/a&gt; has stayed with me every day since I read it. If you are struggling under the weight of projects and side-hustles and to-do lists, this book is for you. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/24&quot;&gt;mentioned earlier&lt;/a&gt; that I took notes while I read it, and I still revisit those notes from time to time, whenever I need to remind myself to take a break from work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="🎉 Event" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><summary type="html">Our 2019 favorites</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 27</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/27" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 27" /><published>2019-12-05T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-05T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/27</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/27">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-letting-go&quot;&gt;On letting go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m having a hard time articulating why, but I feel calmer than usual lately. December is a weird month—there’s so much I feel like I need to squeeze in before the holidays come and the year ends, but I don’t feel frantic or anxious about it at all. I sort of feel like, &lt;em&gt;who cares?&lt;/em&gt; As I wrote in an email to Summer last week, &lt;em&gt;I just want to do nothing and be comfy until January.&lt;/em&gt; I’m ready to hunker down until the new year comes so I can re-emerge and start over, let go of all the things that aren’t working for me, make space for gratitude instead of guilt, etc. etc. etc. I’m trying not to ask too much of myself right now, which probably should not be a December-specific intention, but I’m welcoming it nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve discovered I do, in fact, keep grudges. I didn’t super know that about me. I thought I was a cool, chill girl. Nope! The other day I saw a Twitter account of an ex-friend and felt bitter. I saw a different one a few days later and felt the same, then frustrated. We mostly drifted, and yet I was letting the simple act of &lt;em&gt;maybe someone doesn’t love you&lt;/em&gt; make me feel just awful. And now I am giving space to that feeling in this letter, and communicating it to all of you—I am very bad at deciding &lt;em&gt;I’m not going to let this bother me&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;I don’t want to talk about this anymore&lt;/em&gt; but actually just, talking about it more, only, exclusively, loudly. I want to learn how to process The Bad. I am lucky to have a lot of people in my life who let me shout and complain and encourage my anger, almost, but I feel like a broken record; I can scream about the same thing forever, over and over, mostly because the things I scream about are linked to Bigger World Injustices (lol) but also I’m not sure how to truly &lt;em&gt;process.&lt;/em&gt; Let go. Transform anger or bitterness. I want to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cordite-94-bayt&quot;&gt;📖 Cordite 94: Bayt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zeina Hashem Beck curated this incredible issue of writers of Arab heritage for &lt;em&gt;Cordite&lt;/em&gt;. There are 42 poems, a mini-chapbook, and a few essays. People I love dearly, dearly, dearly have work in this issue and there is very little I love more than poems &amp;amp; my friends. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;http://cordite.org.au/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-tiny-spells&quot;&gt;✉️ Tiny Spells&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyspells.xyz&quot;&gt;Tiny Spells&lt;/a&gt; is a short, daily newsletter about self care—and not the &lt;em&gt;use-my-affiliate-link-to-buy-an-essential-oil-diffuser&lt;/em&gt; kind of self care. (Valid! But not what we’re talking about here.) Tiny Spells lands in your inbox every day with three small, manageable things you can do to take care of yourself, like “Plan how you’re going to get your water intake up,” “Think about the smells that surround you,” and “Please book that doctor’s appointment you’ve been dodging.” And if you don’t need another newsletter, you can find them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tiny_spells&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-fargo-tbakhis-essay-watching-the-last-black-man-in-san-francisco-as-a-palestinian-american&quot;&gt;🔗 Fargo Tbakhi’s essay “Watching ‘The Last Black Man in San Francisco’ as a Palestinian-American”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be double-dipping with the recommendations this week since Fargo also has a poem in the issue above, but listen! My friend is the smartest person in the world. This essay is part of my favorite genre of film writing—review by way of personal essay, a synthesis of all of the things we think about when experiencing something wonderful. He does such an incredible job linking so many different types of texts and relaying both the active experience of &lt;em&gt;watching&lt;/em&gt; but also the more ever-present desire to relate, connect, map. It’s a great read regardless of whether or not you’ve seen the movie or whether or not you are Palestinian. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://gay.medium.com/watching-the-last-black-man-in-san-francisco-as-a-palestinian-american-b0b67eca5931&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-haley-housemans-tackling-2020-workbook&quot;&gt;🔗 Haley Houseman’s Tackling 2020 Workbook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love setting goals, and I love following directions. Naturally, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hedhouseman.com/store/p1/Tackling_2020_Workbook.html#/&quot;&gt;this goal-setting guide&lt;/a&gt; by the brilliant Haley Houseman is my new favorite thing. It is extremely thorough, and was made to walk you through the process of reflecting on 2019 and setting yourself up for a good 2020, whatever that means for you. I’ve been slowly making my way through it for a few days, and it’s tough, but it’s eye-opening—in comparing where I was at the beginning of the year to where I am now, I’m starting to see more clearly what’s really important to me, and where my energy will be best spent next year. The workbook is currently on sale for $5, go give Haley your money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><summary type="html">On letting go</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 26</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/26" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 26" /><published>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/26</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/26">&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;🎉 &lt;em&gt;Today is our newsletter’s first birthday! We sent out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/1&quot;&gt;first letter&lt;/a&gt; exactly a year ago—pretty cool. Thanks for being here with us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week, we knew we had to talk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://swordshield.pokemon.com/en-us/&quot;&gt;Pokemon Sword and Shield&lt;/a&gt;, which is pretty much all either one of us has been thinking about for the past week. Remember when we had that long chat about Animal Crossing for &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/16&quot;&gt;Letter 16&lt;/a&gt;? This is another one of those. You’re welcome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Ummm ok so to start us off&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;When we planned to do this, I wasn’t planning on buying the new Pokemon game&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;But then I did and I played it all weekend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;It be like that sometimes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;BUT I still have lots and lots of questions for you!!! Because you’ve been playing Pokemon for a long time and I’ve pretty much never played a Pokemon game before&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;My first question for u: a few weeks ago, you tweeted “I don’t think any starters should be available in different gens gjsodnsodnf”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;What dis mean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Thank you for that direct quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;So! Every pokemon game kind of has the same formula. You’re a 10 year old kid and that means you’re old enough to have a pokemon of your own! The inciting incident to getting your first pokemon varies, but you always receive it from the professor of the region. The professor will have three pokemon for you to choose from: a grass type, a water type, or a fire type. The majority of the time, the moment in which you choose is the unique incidence of any of those pokemon throughout the game. Your rival will also choose one of the three. These pokemon have pretty steady level growth, balanced stats, good moves, and are cute! You can’t catch them in the wild. You get them from the professor. They are SPECIAL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Ohhhhh ok&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;You form such a lovely bond with your starter! It’s your FIRST pokemon and they occur in EVERY generation. Like, yes we get it, everyone loves Charizard. I do too! So much! But it doesn’t need to be available all of the time. Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-sword-shield-guide/2019/11/15/20965465/scorbunny-evolutions-moves-levels-best&quot;&gt;Scorbunny&lt;/a&gt;. There are other cool fire types in this generation. The nostalgia pull seems unnecessary and sort of takes away from the specialness of a starter if they are obtainable across generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Hmmmm does this tie into the drama about some Pokemon not being available in the new game or am I getting ahead of myself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;WE CAN GO THERE FOR SURE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Lmao we WILL go there&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;How do you want to get into the drama?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;I don’t really know much about the drama other than…….there was some&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Specifically with the release of Sword and Shield&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Which is odd to me because it seems like such a great game that all my friends love, but I’m also viewing that from the perspective of someone who doesn’t really have any ties to the franchise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;So I wanna hear about it from your perspective&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Tell me about the drama babyyy!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Basically, after you beat the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Elite_Four&quot;&gt;elite four&lt;/a&gt; in the majority of pokemon games, you get a thing called a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/National_Pokédex&quot;&gt;national dex&lt;/a&gt; that has spaces for EVERY POKEMON that exists rather than those exclusive to that region/game. SWSH doesn’t have a national dex and people are super upset! On the one hand, I get it, when the catchphrase is “gotta catch em all.” However.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;The deep, deep entitlement of gamers is soooo toxic. I’m not a big completionist type, but there’s still a pokedex to fill up. There are so many other lovely things to enjoy and we had so much to look forward to with this game—the fact that people were so violently upset with this decision was really disheartening&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Hmmm ok so you’re telling me I can’t get every pokemon that’s ever existed in this new game, but there’s still like……a lot of pokemon in it anyway&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;YES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;I also think people are upset their specific favorites aren’t available, but it’s been like that across every game! You have to trade from weird places, across consoles even! (In the GBA era, to finish the national dex you had to hook up to the gamecube)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;I kind of understand where people are coming from, especially if they have deep nostalgic ties to certain pokemon that they’ve taken with them over many generations of the game, etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;But also there are so many cuties and sweeties in this game! And it’s kind of exciting to see all the new ones!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Are there any specific pokemon that aren’t in this game that you miss?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Honestly, no. I barely notice what isn’t available. I try to just use new pokemon on my team? Because I want to familiarize myself with the region. I’ve been pleasantly surprised at what IS available, actually. I saw a video on Twitter of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/lucario/&quot;&gt;Lucario&lt;/a&gt; in SWSH and freaked out because I LOVE LUCARIO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;I do fully understand the instinct to distrust and critique big game studios, right? But I’m also really tired of the stereotypical toxic gamer who can’t just enjoy a cute, fun game without complaining about all of the reasons it isn’t exactly what they wanted!!! I’m not sure how to balance those two feelings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;BUT I think we’ve established that the game is good and fun and people should calm down and enjoy it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;We’ve both been playing it a lot since it came out so I can definitely endorse it as Good and Fun. Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Absolutely! And I have some criticisms, but nothing that is keeping me from being so overjoyed that I have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;I was kind of struggling with deciding which game to get, once I decided I wanted to play it. I went with Sword mostly because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/zacian/&quot;&gt;sword dog&lt;/a&gt; but also because you picked Shield. Why did you decide to get Shield?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;This is the most I’ve ever struggled with picking a version, strangely enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Oooh why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;I, too, love sword dog and was immediately enamored. But there were a few version exclusives that I was into—like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/2019/11/15/20965032/how-to-catch-galarian-ponyta&quot;&gt;Galarian Ponyta&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-xy/704.shtml&quot;&gt;Goomy&lt;/a&gt;—but mostly, it was because of my brother! We have, traditionally, always gotten opposing versions. And we’ve never even had a problem deciding who got what—generally we were always drawn to different legendaries. But he really wanted Sword because of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-sword-shield-guide/2019/11/15/20966671/where-to-get-galarian-farfetchd-sirfetchd&quot;&gt;Sirfetch’d&lt;/a&gt; and it felt wrong to not continue our sibling tradition, even though we don’t live together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Omg aw that’s very cute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;We did pick the same starter for the first time!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Wait who did you pick I don’t remember&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-sword-shield-guide/2019/11/15/20965412/grookey-evolution-moves-levels&quot;&gt;Grookey&lt;/a&gt; 🐵&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Ahhhhhh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;All the starters are extremely cute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;I am very happy with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-sword-shield-guide/2019/11/15/20965513/pokemon-sword-shield-sobble-evolution-moves-guide-levels&quot;&gt;Sobble&lt;/a&gt; that I refuse to evolve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;In their first forms, I agree. I did choose Grookey because his last form was the least terrifying, to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;That’s such a good way to do it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Ok what was the first pokemon game you ever played&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;So! I would play my brother’s copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Pokémon_Red_and_Blue_Versions&quot;&gt;Pokemon Blue&lt;/a&gt;, but he wouldn’t let me restart it so I would just catch &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Rattata_(Pokémon)&quot;&gt;Rattatas&lt;/a&gt; and I didn’t know how to save so I would just turn the power off. That doesn’t super count, I guess, and maybe neither does &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Pokémon_Stadium_(English)&quot;&gt;Pokemon Stadium&lt;/a&gt; for N64, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Pokémon_Ruby_and_Sapphire_Versions&quot;&gt;Pokemon Ruby&lt;/a&gt;!!! 3rd gen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Wow you go alllllll the way back huh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;What’s your FAVORITE pokemon game&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;And least favorite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Oof. My nostalgia brain wants to say &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Pokémon_Emerald_Version&quot;&gt;Pokemon Emerald&lt;/a&gt;, since it has some of the best post-game and I know that generation inside-out. I also love all three of those starters, even if I choose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-xy/255.shtml&quot;&gt;Torchic&lt;/a&gt; more often than not. I think &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Pokémon_X_and_Y&quot;&gt;XY&lt;/a&gt; is my least favorite—the graphics were so cool and the pokemon were also great, but I thought the new mechanics made it too easy and I was really frustrated. There’s not a lot of post-game either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Generally I feel like I will love a pokemon no matter what? So what makes a game for me is the story—and I think difficulty level is built into that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Do you often replay pokemon games?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Or do you just keep playing one forever? Or do you let it end and wait for the next one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;I’ve played gen 1-4 over an EXCEPTIONAL amount of times, especially Gen 1 by way of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pokémon_FireRed_and_LeafGreen&quot;&gt;FireRed&lt;/a&gt;. I clocked soooo many hours on Emerald specifically, even in the post-game—not super sure what I was doing, to be honest, but when you’re roughly 10 you have so much patience to do so many things. Replaying was great because there were so many new team combinations to explore!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;This sort of touches on something that I was wondering, especially now that I’m in the trenches of a pokemon game, which is: do pokemon games…….end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;I guess it depends on how you define winning? You can beat the elite four, which technically makes you the champion, as many times as you want. Gens 3 and 4 had “&lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Pokémon_Contest&quot;&gt;pokemon contests&lt;/a&gt;”, which were like beauty pageants in a few different categories; each pokemon can compete and get ribbons and stuff, etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Completing your pokedex is another definition people have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Theoretically, I can be happy with rechallenging the elite four over and over again, which is what I was doing in XY and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pokemonletsgo.pokemon.com/en-us/&quot;&gt;Let’s Go&lt;/a&gt;. And in something like FireRed/LeafGreen, being the champion opens up a whole new set of areas to explore! So that’s not always the conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;So you can pretty much keep going forever?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;Basically! Each game has different ways to make it interesting, but yeah. The final boss battle will always be open to you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;nice, I like that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Do you think SW/SH is a good pokemon game for beginners? Or would you recommend starting somewhere different?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;I think it is, and I think it’s definitely designed to be easy to grasp as possible. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Hop&quot;&gt;Hop&lt;/a&gt; is a constant tutorial character, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;He is………….annoying&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;In a brotherly way I guess&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;HE IS!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Pls give me your tips for pokemon newbies like myself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;I strongly encourage having a balanced team and understanding typing as well as you can. I also recommend reading the pokedex online and familiarizing yourself with a region! I get people don’t like spoilers, but it’s really beneficial to learn what pokemon you want early on and where to find them, so there are no regrets. I get really attached to pokemon and am reluctant to make team adjustments, so knowing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-sword-shield-guide/2019/11/20/20972677/what-else-can-you-do-with-an-applin-besides-eating-it&quot;&gt;apple dragon&lt;/a&gt;, for example, existed was good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Summer I am literally reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/&quot;&gt;pokedex&lt;/a&gt; RIGHT NOW because of you!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;I think we both know how I feel about “spoilers” in video games which is: look up as much stuff as you want, who cares, I just like to follow directions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;I want to end this the same way we ended our conversation about animal crossing which is: tell me about your favorite pokemon memory!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;THIS IS SO HARD! Pokemon is my whole life. My first thought was playing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pokemongo.com/en-us/&quot;&gt;Pokemon Go&lt;/a&gt; with my brother when it first came out, and our UTTER JOY at seeing a goddamn sandshrew on our driveway with the AR function. We were literally jumping in glee!!!! We are adults!!!! I used pokemon to make friends when I moved to California. My closest friends all gave me pokemon plushies as a present when I left Michigan. I got two Pikachu-based gifts when I graduated college. I have love tied to every aspect of the franchise: the games, the anime, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;I am so happy you have joined this journey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;I’m super happy to be on this pokemon journey too&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Thank u for teaching me stuff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;I am here to answer every question. I have to do something with all of this knowledge in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;this was fun but the whole time I was like……I can’t wait to……play pokemon after this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;RIGHT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-summer&quot;&gt;My switch was charging….it’s time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-summer&quot;&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;Ok I’m gonna go do that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bubble-jillian&quot;&gt;❤️❤️❤️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;name-jillian&quot;&gt;Jillian&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🎮 Video game" /><summary type="html">🎉 Today is our newsletter’s first birthday! We sent out our first letter exactly a year ago—pretty cool. Thanks for being here with us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 25</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/25" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 25" /><published>2019-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/25</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/25">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-coziness&quot;&gt;On coziness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I was in Powell’s looking for an entirely different book when I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harpercollins.com/9780062654151/cozy/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cozy&lt;/em&gt; by Isabel Gillies&lt;/a&gt;—I had to buy it. I read it slowly, savoring the short but satisfying chapters dedicated to picking apart an activity, a place, or an object and exploring what makes it cozy. Even the book itself is cozy, with its hard cover and blue ink and deckle edge pages, and reading it was a lesson in finding the coziness in everything. I started a note on my phone of things in my apartment that are cozy (you should do this) and looking at it makes me feel warm and safe: the light above the stove, the magnets on the fridge, the light coming in through the linen curtains in the morning, the wood floors, the rice cooker, the eucalyptus in the shower, the noise the dishwasher makes, the kitchen shelf with mugs, the doorbell that nobody knows about, the pink dutch oven that sits on top of the fridge, the candles that I light every night. Cozy is a feeling and a place and a mood and a state of being all at once—and it’s everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write this from the perspective of a fragile Californian, but: I am cold. I wake up, more reluctant than ever to throw the covers off and start my day. A few days ago, I was having more trouble than usual leaving my apartment when I remembered this overwhelmingly large, cushy, black cardigan I have (with nice big pockets that sag if you put anything in them), and felt able to go. Coziness is akin to warmth is akin to safety, and there’s nothing that signals safety more than wrapping yourself up. I do not dislike the cold; I have so much affection for the wind, particularly the way it whips my face and how I imagine it filling the bags under my eyes. This, however, only emphasizes the need for comfy things more—if I am to interact with my favorite weather, I have to be prepared. Scarves; it’s keffiyeh season, and I pair my Palestine necklaces with a more obvious symbol around my neck. Sweaters; body dysmorphia does not get solved with a new outfit, but I have always loved turtlenecks. Warm drinks; a constant, but more appropriate than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-the-bechdel-cast&quot;&gt;🎙️ The Bechdel Cast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this podcast! Jamie Loftus and Caitlin Durante discuss the portrayal of women in movies (and all of the things that go along with that discussion). They are funny, fair, smart, and recognize their points of ignorance as two white women. I’ve made my way through every episode in the main feed that discusses a movie I’ve watched, am now subscribed to the Patreon (Matreon, excuse me), and have gotten to the point of re-listening to episodes to fall asleep to. Which is true love for me and a podcast, basically. They make me happy and I do think I’ve started watching movies differently. They do a great job of balancing criticism and recognizing that sometimes you just like things, too!!!! I’d recommend starting with their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bechdelcast.com/podcasts/booksmart-with-vanessa-chester.htm&quot;&gt;Booksmart&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bechdelcast.com/podcasts/good-will-hunting-with-ayo-edebiri.htm&quot;&gt;Good Will Hunting&lt;/a&gt; (a movie I haven’t seen, but I’ll listen to anything with Ayo Edebiri) episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-jenny-slates-stage-fright&quot;&gt;📺 Jenny Slate’s Stage Fright&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenny Slate is my mother and my wife and my best friend and my baby! I very deeply fell in love with her when I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vulture.com/2017/03/jenny-slate-gifted-chris-evans-breakup.html&quot;&gt;this Vulture interview&lt;/a&gt; from 2017, and then again when I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vulture.com/2019/01/jenny-slate-interview-the-sunlight-night-at-sundance.html&quot;&gt;this Vulture interview&lt;/a&gt; from earlier this year, which I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/6&quot;&gt;already mentioned&lt;/a&gt; in this newsletter and will continue to mention until the end of time. And now her comedy special, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/81027753&quot;&gt;Stage Fright&lt;/a&gt;, is on Netflix for me to watch on a weekly basis for the rest of my life, probably. It is unlike any comedy special I’ve ever watched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[note from Summer: it made me cry! that’s comedy, baby!]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-cws-nancy-drew&quot;&gt;📺 The CW’s Nancy Drew&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love Nancy Drew! She has followed me for such a long time, in so many different iterations. &lt;em&gt;Nancy Drew&lt;/em&gt; books were my in-betweens, what I would read when waiting for another book to be available at the library. Their inconsistencies bothered me to no end, but I was only ten, and never read two in a row, so why Nancy’s hair was always a different shade of blonde was a mystery I never solved. I learned more and more about the sort of sinister history of the books, their re-writes, the way Nancy was deemed “Too Cool” by a 1950s audience and thus disempowered as a protagonist. The sort of slow burn of understanding the character’s history definitely helps my utter enjoyment of the &lt;em&gt;Riverdale-&lt;/em&gt;ification of the new CW series, in which Nancy is cool as shit. There are just a few episodes, and they’re campy as hell, but the show is truly SO COMPELLING. And honestly scary! I’m a big wimp so you can argue with me on that point, but WOW. I am having an incredible time, and my boyfriend who knew nothing about Nancy Drew agrees: this show rocks. It airs Thursday nights on the CW! Please talk to me about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-cavern-of-secrets&quot;&gt;🎙️ Cavern of Secrets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/katie-jensen-2/cavern-of-secrets&quot;&gt;Cavern of Secrets&lt;/a&gt; was, I think, the first podcast I ever really loved. I remember listening to it and stifling laughter on the Northeast Regional trip on my way home from college. I was devastated when it ended, but I gradually moved on, opening myself up to an entire world of podcasts that I now listen to on a daily basis. What I’m saying is: before Cavern of Secrets, I thought podcasts had to be boring. Turns out they can be deeply funny and interesting and warm! And this one is the funniest, most interesting, and warmest of them all, imho. The extremely good news is that it is back, with six new episodes! It’s the same Cavern of Secrets that I loved in 2016, and it’s kind of wild to listen to it now and remember who I was and what I was doing when I was listening to it the first time, on that Amtrak. I highly recommend listening to the latest episodes, but I also recommend going through the back catalogue, because it has some of the most brilliant, hilarious conversations I’ve ever heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🎙️ Podcast" /><category term="📺 TV" /><summary type="html">On coziness</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 24</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 24" /><published>2019-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/24</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/24">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-routines&quot;&gt;On routines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still figuring out my relationship to routines, and I suspect I will be forever. I’ve always loved the idea of having the perfect morning or nighttime routine, but routines are hard to force. I’ve successfully replaced my habit of checking Instagram as soon as I wake up with the routine of reading a few articles in my Instapaper queue and spending a few minutes journaling before I get ready for work, but I still need a daily reminder to read a book and drink a cup of tea before I go to bed to avoid scrolling through Twitter until midnight. But my life is full of tiny routines that I don’t pay much attention to—so I made a list of them: the routine of making a cup of tea and filling up my water bottle and eating a protein bar as soon as I get to my office, the routine of listening to the same podcasts in the same order during my commute every week, the routine of folding clothes and putting them away, the routine of putting on makeup, the routine of lighting a candle with a match and then leaving the match out on the table instead of throwing it away, the routine of texting my boyfriend every night before I go to bed, the routine of washing my face in the shower while my hair sits with conditioner in for a few minutes, the routine of emptying the dishwasher in the same order every time, the routine of checking the mail when I get home. I find comfort in making lists like this, just like I find comfort in my routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m awful at routines, awful at keeping habits, awful at following through with any sort of consistency. This means I’m sort of awful at taking care of myself outside of the necessities. It’s not that I get tired of repetition, it’s just that I’m actually tired. I am my own worst enemy, keeping myself from ever repairing the damage eczema and anxiety have done to my skin because I cannot fathom the long-term exertion of caring for myself on the regular. There were points in time in which I washed my face with coconut oil, dried my budding zits with apple cider vinegar, and finished off with a carefully selected night cream; this routine was maybe too much too soon, as it fizzled out fast. The only routine I truly name a routine, rather than just an attempt at remaining a person, is making coffee. Yes, I am addicted to caffeine and will get mind-numbing headaches without it, but the mornings I forego making my own coffee (when I buy it, or know it’s available at work, etc.) always feel off. The calm of setting up my drip—the only dish I wash right away—and spooning too-many-grounds into the filter subdues my generalized morning anxiety. I begin with a sense of control. I want more to cling to, I want more things I can name part of myself, but for now? …coffee good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-it-must-be-heaven&quot;&gt;📽️ It Must Be Heaven&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt8359842/&quot;&gt;this film&lt;/a&gt; at the opening night of the Arab Film Fest in San Francisco a few weeks ago. It’s directed by Elia Suleiman, a Palestinian director from Nazareth; so you know, basically family. It’s Palestine’s entry for the Oscars this year and probably the most I’ve ever cared about a movie getting nominated. It’s a vignette-y, quiet, poetic film taking place in Nazareth, Paris, New York, and then Nazareth again with just really BEAUTIFUL moments. There’s not a lot of dialogue, but the lines that exist…buddy, am I still thinking about them! If this movie comes to theaters near you, ABSOLUTELY see it. I’m still processing some parts of it that I have questions about, and have barely anyone to talk to about it! Help me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-how-to-not-always-be-working&quot;&gt;📖 How to Not Always Be Working&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two things that I love: working on too many side projects at the same time, and books that give me homework. I scrolled past a photo of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Not-Always-Working-Creativity/dp/0062803670/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1554865512&amp;amp;sr=8-1https://www.amazon.com/How-Not-Always-Working-Creativity/dp/0062803670/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1554865512&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;How to Not Always Be Working&lt;/a&gt; on Instagram, and it stayed in my head until I finally sought it out and grabbed one of two copies at Powell’s while I was visiting Portland. This is a book for anybody who routinely blurs the line between work and not-work, and also anybody who likes to take notes and make lists, as I do. For a little over a week, I started every morning by reading a chapter from this book and writing down anything I wanted to remember—lists of what I do for work vs. what I do for me, a description of my dream workspace, affirmations to think about when I’m feeling anxious or imposter syndrome-y. It’s often harder than we think to draw a line between “work” and “life,” and this book encourages reflection and exploration to find a balance that’s right for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-bon-appetits-lemon-pound-cake&quot;&gt;🍽️ Bon Appetit’s lemon pound cake&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been making a startling amount of things in my loaf pan, to varying degrees of success. My favorite so far was a banana bread that I know I can truly never replicate—but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/lemon-pound-cake&quot;&gt;this lemon pound cake&lt;/a&gt;…it’s beautiful. Honestly, I kind of fucked up the actual cake, but the recipe itself is very good and I could &lt;em&gt;taste&lt;/em&gt; what it was &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to taste like, yknow? Anyway, no one I shared it with complained, but we all agreed it could be more lemon-y. Make sure your lemons are not tiny and sad, and also remember to wear gloves if your hands are riddled with cuts, like mine are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-notion&quot;&gt;📱 Notion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel corny saying this, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; has changed my life. It’s almost hard to explain what Notion is, because it is so many things—for me, it is a to-do list, a goal tracker, a home for various projects and notes. We use Notion to draft this newsletter and keep track of our past and future recommendations. Most recently, I used Notion to plan out a new game of Stardew Valley, because that’s just my personality. The point is, you can use it for almost anything you want, across devices. For a more coherent and professional description, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;visit their website&lt;/a&gt;. It’s great. You’re welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><summary type="html">On routines</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 23</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/23" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 23" /><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/23">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-renewal&quot;&gt;On renewal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t be happy with any of my work (or with myself, really) if I wasn’t constantly thinking about making changes and improvements, steadily moving forward and transforming. There’s just something about this time of year that amplifies that—back-to-school season has turned into Virgo season in adulthood, my birthday is around the corner, and I’ve already had my annual cold to mark the changing of seasons. I used to think I was afraid of change, but I think I was really just afraid of how much it excited me. You might notice this newsletter has a new look today—Substack gave us a good start, but we’ve decided to move over to Mailchimp so we can do bigger, better things. &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.substack.com&quot;&gt;Our Substack&lt;/a&gt; archives will stay up, but all of our future letters will live on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com&quot;&gt;brand new website&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the season of changes and renewal. Are you excited?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that adulthood would be marked by several things, one of the stranger ones being not racking up library fines. I’ve had fines at every library I’ve ever gotten books from, except elementary schools. I love the concept of libraries, as many do, but it’s been a long time since I’ve actually held love for a library instead of panic. I’m thankful my education did not totally destroy my positive relationship to reading, but it did alter how I feel in libraries; the sense of urgent productivity, the way your time with a book is not really yours when someone else needs it for research, etc etc etc. Now that I’ve moved, I’ve decided: new city, new rules. Read more, read wider, and use community resources. Jill and I do monthly goal check-ins together, and with her I established September as a reset. The most consistent habit I have is writing this newsletter, and I love it, but I need to do more for myself. October is for rediscovering healthy habits I let go of a long, long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-rilo-kileys-the-execution-of-all-things&quot;&gt;🎶 Rilo Kiley’s &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2019, where sometimes you’ll be listening to St. Vincent and Spotify will be like &lt;em&gt;hey how about these related artists?&lt;/em&gt; and it’s your usual rotation of sad girl music (Mitski, Lorde, Phoebe Bridgers) and then there’s an artist you haven’t heard before and it’s Rilo Kiley and you’re like &lt;em&gt;wow, that name sounds familiar&lt;/em&gt; because they referenced this band on &lt;em&gt;Gilmore Girls&lt;/em&gt; ALL OF THE TIME so you click on the full album and you’re getting ready for the day and “A Better Son/Daughter” plays and you just kind of stare at yourself in the mirror and cry because this is truly a soundtrack for the everyday morning struggle of inhabiting a body/being a person/existing with depression and all of those other little things that make navigating life difficult and it’s comforting to listen to something that feels very much a precursor for all of the music you like now and also something that’s kind of been present in your life as long as you’ve loved &lt;em&gt;Gilmore Girls&lt;/em&gt;, too. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/23EqcK0ZR1ravQaEsGpQyH&quot;&gt;So that’s my recommendation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-ologies&quot;&gt;🎙️ Ologies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alieward.com/ologies/phenology&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; was the first episode of Ologies that I ever listened to, and I immediately fell in love. Some backstory: I met Alie Ward earlier this year when she &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lickability.com/we-were-on-tv-281910f4b3b6&quot;&gt;came to my office&lt;/a&gt; to film a segment for her CBS show, which was extremely cool. Then, a few weeks ago, she was on an episode of &lt;a href=&quot;https://forever35podcast.com/home/2019/9/26/episode-91-alie-ward&quot;&gt;Forever 35&lt;/a&gt; where she mentioned her science podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alieward.com/ologies&quot;&gt;Ologies&lt;/a&gt;. The first episode I listened to was about phenology, the study of seasons, and it made me feel so cozy and ready for fall. Alie has a way of taking a subject like phenology—a word I had never even heard before—and making it feel familiar and accessible. This episode starts out with questions like &lt;em&gt;“Why do leaves change color?”&lt;/em&gt; and ends with a broader discussion about climate change, and it is fantastic from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-durga-chew-boses-review-of-call-me-by-your-name&quot;&gt;📝 Durga Chew-Bose’s review of &lt;em&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a culture we probably don’t care too much about &lt;em&gt;Call My By Your Name&lt;/em&gt; anymore, but it’s been on my mind this past week and so naturally, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ssense.com/en-us/editorial/culture/first-impressions-luca-guadagninos-call-me-by-your-name&quot;&gt;essay&lt;/a&gt; has been, too. I love Durga’s film writing so much and crave more of it and so I come back to this every few months to fill that need (and honestly, to study?). Her careful observations, like “[CMBYN] delivers romantic tension as it enters a home. Not feverishly as one might expect, but slowly, as if each image is rising from memory,” capture exactly what continues to draw me to the movie—despite the obvious problematic aspects—and are definitely articulated and replicated in her writing style, too. My favorite reviews are ones that parallel their love for what they are discussing in the way that they write, and gentle yearning is one of my favorite feelings—put them together, and that’s a perfect read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-this-article-about-newsletters&quot;&gt;📝 This article about newsletters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newsletters are great, and we love them. We’ve loved them for a long time, thanks to tools like Tinyletter and Buttondown and Substack that have made it easy for anyone to start their own newsletter. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2019/10/substack-revue-email-newsletter-startups-tinyletter/599557/&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; by Kaitlyn Tiffany for &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt; gives a shout out to all of the people who were writing newsletters before venture capital decided it was cool. Once you’re finished reading this, go read that instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="🎙️ Podcast" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><summary type="html">On renewal</summary></entry></feed>