<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-19T02:13:07+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Letters To Summer</title><subtitle>Two friends sharing the things they're reading, watching, listening to, and enjoying. In your inbox every other Thursday.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Letter 40</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/40" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 40" /><published>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/40</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/40">&lt;p&gt;There’s no personal note from either of us this time. Instead, we’d like to direct you to letter &lt;a href=&quot;/39&quot;&gt;#39&lt;/a&gt; for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theokraproject.com&quot;&gt;The Okra Project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glitsinc.org&quot;&gt;GLITS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-last-black-man-in-san-francisco&quot;&gt;📽️ Last Black Man in San Francisco&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This movie had been on my list for an achingly long time, and I finally watched it on my birthday. It was so fucking good, and so different than what I expected. The &lt;em&gt;energy&lt;/em&gt; of this movie. Time can pass and you don’t really notice it, or time can drag on and you notice it, but this film pulls you in such a way that you feel like viewing itself is momentum. What a tragedy it got so little awards recognition. I don’t know a person that watched this movie that didn’t think it was spectacular. The cinematography is ridiculously cool—there are so many weird, surreal shots that make the weirdness so stunning? The performances are endearing and just spectacular. Highly recommend, especially for folks in the bay, especially if you’re a transplant. You can watch it on Amazon or Kanopy if your library participates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cardcaptor-sakura&quot;&gt;📺 Cardcaptor Sakura&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched all of Cardcaptor Sakura for the first time a few months ago, right when the city was starting to shut down and I suddenly had a lot more time to myself. I was contemplating a rewatch of Sailor Moon, which I have always found comforting to have on in the background while puttering around in my apartment, but started watching Cardcaptor Sakura at the suggestion of a friend instead and quickly fell in love with it. It’s cute and fun and joyful and I promise it will make you feel good. And it’s on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/70309056?trackId=200257858&quot;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; now, so you really have no choice but to fall in love with it, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-permadeath-by-marlin-m-jenkins&quot;&gt;🔗 Permadeath by Marlin M. Jenkins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://therumpus.net/2020/06/permadeath/&quot;&gt;This essay&lt;/a&gt; is exactly the type of writing I aspire to, and the type of writing I want to see in the world—Marlin is always so good at identifying the &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; in a game, that &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; that makes you attached and emotional, and making you reflect on what those attachments look like, what they mean—whether or not you’ve actually played the game being discussed. The prose is also just so fucking beautiful. More good video game writing! More treating video games like the art they are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-eat-a-snack&quot;&gt;🍽️ Eat a snack!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I struggled a lot trying to think of a second recommendation this week. We always tend toward recommending media that we’re enjoying, which I love, because sharing a book or a movie or a video game with your friends is one of the greatest joys there is. But right now I want to recommend that you eat a snack, because that feels like the most honest and true recommendation I can give—eat a snack, or drink a glass of water, or take a shower, or go for a short walk outside, or do whatever other tiny thing you can do right now to take care of yourself. (My favorite snacks today have been cheez-its and blackberries. In case you wanted to know.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><summary type="html">There’s no personal note from either of us this time. Instead, we’d like to direct you to letter #39 for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend The Okra Project and GLITS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 39</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/39" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 39" /><published>2020-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/39</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/39">&lt;p&gt;We’re forgoing our regular format this week, since what we’re doing recreationally isn’t important right now. Instead, we’d like to encourage you all to donate to folks on the ground protesting the murders of George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and the countless other Black folks who have been killed by police violence. Educate yourselves and your loved ones on police abolition, and take care of your communities however you can. We’d also like to emphasize that police violence in the US is ongoing and not just something happening in this moment—the violence that Black folks face is not trendy! Hold onto this energy and continue to donate to anti-racist organizations and bail funds even after the protests slow down. Become aware of community organizations dedicated to fighting oppressive structures. Find your niche in how you can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send emails to your government officials.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.email2act.com&quot;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; has several easy-to-use email templates that you can use to email officials in different cities about the actions of their police. All you have to do is plug in your name and hit send. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://defund12.org/nyc&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; has email templates for urging your representatives to defund the police department and redirect those funds to education and social services.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate to bail funds.&lt;/strong&gt; Protestors are doing extremely important work right now, and local bail funds ensure that they can continue doing that work. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bailfunds.github.io&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a list of bail funds across the country that could use your help, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.actblue.com/donate/bail_funds_george_floyd&quot;&gt;here’s&lt;/a&gt; a link to split a donation between over 70 of them at once. Several cities that have gotten a massive amount of support over the past week are asking folks to send their donations elsewhere, so please make sure to do your research first!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate to mutual aid funds.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t forget: we’re in a pandemic. People need supplies, and people on the ground need to be safe, too. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thegirlwithfood/status/1267572248149442562&quot;&gt;This thread&lt;/a&gt; has links nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refrain from spreading cop propaganda.&lt;/strong&gt; Officers at various marches have joined protestors, but without actual actions/consequences, this is meaningless because the harmful structures that led us here stay in place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join or support abolition organizations.&lt;/strong&gt; Here are a few to start: &lt;a href=&quot;https://survivedandpunished.org/about/&quot;&gt;Survived &amp;amp; Punished&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area &amp;amp; NYC), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antipoliceterrorproject.org/&quot;&gt;Anti-Police Terror Project&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area), &lt;a href=&quot;https://humanimpact.org/&quot;&gt;Human Impact&lt;/a&gt; (does work through a public health lens), &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peoplesbreakoak?lang=en&quot;&gt;People’s Breakfast&lt;/a&gt; (Oakland, also does free meals program), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.api-rise.org/&quot;&gt;API Rise&lt;/a&gt; (Los Angeles), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asianprisonersupport.com/&quot;&gt;Asian Prisoner Support Committee&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom-inc.org/&quot;&gt;Freedom Inc.&lt;/a&gt; (Madison). These are geographically centered on just a few places, and some culturally specific—please send us organizations in your location and we can include them in future letters!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue to educate yourself on abolition.&lt;/strong&gt; Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1HUpCPvOwUJElxtUP4mCysAY9GyZrSmUk&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; with flyers that present alternatives to policing. MPD15, an organization working toward a police-free Minneapolis, has a helpful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mpd150.com/faq/&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; on their website. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usprisonculture.com/blog/essential-pic-reading-list/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; are some other essential readings to get you started! &lt;a href=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/59ead8f9692ebee25b72f17f/t/5b65cd58758d46d34254f22c/1533398363539/CR_NoCops_reform_vs_abolition_CRside.pdf&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a helpful graphic from &lt;a href=&quot;http://criticalresistance.org/abolish-policing/&quot;&gt;Critical Resistance&lt;/a&gt; that breaks down the difference between reform and abolition.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep going!&lt;/strong&gt; This work doesn’t end today. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blacklivesmatters.carrd.co&quot;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; has tons more resources and ways you can take action. Call and email your representatives regularly. Set up recurring donations. Attend protests and vigils in your city if you can. Share helpful, informative posts with your friends, family, and followers. Continue to listen, and continue to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="💡 Idea" /><summary type="html">We’re forgoing our regular format this week, since what we’re doing recreationally isn’t important right now. Instead, we’d like to encourage you all to donate to folks on the ground protesting the murders of George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and the countless other Black folks who have been killed by police violence. Educate yourselves and your loved ones on police abolition, and take care of your communities however you can. We’d also like to emphasize that police violence in the US is ongoing and not just something happening in this moment—the violence that Black folks face is not trendy! Hold onto this energy and continue to donate to anti-racist organizations and bail funds even after the protests slow down. Become aware of community organizations dedicated to fighting oppressive structures. Find your niche in how you can help.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 38</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/38" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 38" /><published>2020-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/38</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/38">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-video-games&quot;&gt;On video games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most mornings, in between making my first cup of tea of the day and sitting at my desk to work, I play Animal Crossing in bed to ease myself awake. I go through my daily chores in the game (watering my flowers, digging up fossils, talking to my neighbors, checking the shops) before I’m ready to tackle my daily chores in real life. Once I finish working for the day, I’m eager to return to my students in Fire Emblem Three Houses (which &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/21&quot;&gt;Summer recommended in this newsletter&lt;/a&gt; before I was ready to hear it). And all the moments in between, I spend plenty of time watching Twitch streams, liking tweets about Breath of the Wild, and sending Summer way too many Discord messages about the games we’re playing. I’d like to say something here about how video games are a place to “find solace” in these “unprecedented” and “trying” times, whatever that means. Instead, I will point you to two essays that I keep returning to that say it better than I can: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2020/02/video-games-are-a-to-do-list-you-play.html&quot;&gt;“Video Games Are a To-Do List That You Play”&lt;/a&gt; is required reading to understand me, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/5/12/21241735/nintendo-switch-animal-crossing-video-games-coronavirus-quarantine&quot;&gt;Alanna Okun’s recent piece&lt;/a&gt; about playing video games in quarantine hit me especially hard. Here’s a quote from the latter: “I want a place that’s not here, a set of problems that aren’t these, something I can talk about with my friends and co-workers and strangers that isn’t going to claw me apart with anxiety.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been just a year since I graduated college, which means it’s been just a year since a month-long period began in which I did very little each day besides play Breath of the Wild. I was so exhaused. I was getting sicker each day, from some mysterious dust in my apartment (I’m ok now, I use my inhaler and everything). I was anxiously waiting to hear back from a few jobs but had no energy to apply to others. Really, there was nothing else for me besides playing. The only major story point I had left was to defeat Ganon. And for a month, I didn’t; instead, I wandered. I felt too scared to fight the last battle without a friend with me. I’m not trying to make this into some sort of grand metaphor about how I wasn’t ready to move onto the next phase of my life in the interim of graduating and an office job, but the wandering in Breath of the Wild helped soothe my anxiety about urgency; the big things could wait, and handling the…side quests of life?…was valid, for now. There isn’t a time in my life in which video games did not assist that urgency to do More, and there isn’t a time in which video games didn’t improve other aspects of my life. Games made my brother and I have a good relationship, helped me make friends, and continue to help me come down from stressful events. Jill and I talk about video games basically every day, and like her, Animal Crossing is part of my morning routine—it was part of my morning routine when I was eight, too, and when I was fourteen, when there was no pandemic and I just carried general anxiety and stress about the world. It’s a constant that’s not actually a constant. And I need it! I love video games. Always have and always will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-sex-and-the-city&quot;&gt;📺 Sex and the City&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sex and the City is under the “comfort viewing” section on HBO. I thought I was tuning into an adult Gossip Girl&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; dealing with the absolutely bonkers stakes rich people create for themselves but instead it’s actually? Comfortable? Oh to go to brunch with your friends, oh to walk the New York streets at night in your $400 shoes, oh to be part of a campy group of friends that are archetypal yet fleshed out. The disconnect from my actual life—Carrie mentions meeting Mr. Big at 9 o’clock to which I said &lt;em&gt;god that’s so late,&lt;/em&gt; to my boyfriend’s amusement—is just strong enough to not remind me that I can’t drink wine and laugh with my friends without a computer screen. Normally I don’t recommend something I haven’t finished, but I’m flying through season 2, and having a very good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cleaning-your-desk&quot;&gt;💡 Cleaning your desk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not have the greatest week, to be honest. A bad combination of PMS and anxiety left me feeling absolutely horrible for a few days, and while I’m still not feeling great, I did manage to take advantage of a slight burst of energy to clean off some of the clutter on my desk and rearrange things in a way that’s making my brain feel a little bit better. I replaced the haphazard piles of sticky notes with a daily planner! I moved anything I don’t use on a daily basis out of sight! The thing is: cleaning up your workspace is not a perfect, permanent solution to any of the bad stuff, but it’s probably one of the only things in your control right now, so it definitely doesn’t hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-carly-rae-jepsens-dedication-side-b&quot;&gt;🎶 Carly Rae Jepsen’s &lt;em&gt;Dedication Side B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up pretty sad this morning and guess what! Carly helped! We love a complex album that tracks a relationship and mixes the upbeat with the sad! I’m still in my initial listens, but as someone who got into CRJ relatively late—this is my suggestion to you: go have fun! &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7oHKKCXCFIv3J1Yh5F08pu&quot;&gt;Go to Spotify!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-rebecca-solnit-on-hope&quot;&gt;📖 Rebecca Solnit on hope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most comforting things I’ve read so far during all this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/07/what-coronavirus-can-teach-us-about-hope-rebecca-solnit&quot;&gt;Rebecca Solnit’s essay&lt;/a&gt; in The Guardian about &lt;em&gt;what the coronavirus can teach us about hope.&lt;/em&gt; I suggest you read it, too. And when you’ve finished that and want some more, you can read her book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781608465767&quot;&gt;Hope in the Dark&lt;/a&gt;, which explores how hope and human compassion can be catalysts for change in moments like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="💡 Idea" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="📖 Read" /><summary type="html">On video games</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 37</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/37" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 37" /><published>2020-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/37</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/37">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-nostalgia&quot;&gt;On nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if it’s because I’m bored, or because I’m desperately searching for new coping mechanisms in the middle of all of this, but I’ve been spending a lot of time thinking about a reaching for experiences I had growing up. Last night, after a couple glasses of wine, I went down a rabbit hole searching for all the old MMORPGs I used to play. (Pixie Hollow, anyone? Virtual Magic Kingdom? Toontown? Bring them back!) I’ve been heavily considering joining Summer as she rewatches Glee from the beginning. And now I guess Stephanie Meyer is publishing Midnight Sun, which, alright! Nostalgia is not always a good thing, but I’m finding it comforting these days, when little else is. It makes sense that we’d want to turn our minds to a past in which we could go outside without masks on, and enjoy the things that occupied our time when we were younger and had less to worry about—I think it’s okay to let yourself lean into the nostalgia a little bit! Make a playlist of songs you loved in high school. Revisit your favorite movies and TV shows and books and games, even if they aren’t as good now, just to scratch the itch. And then return to the present, because there is nothing more important than paying attention to what is happening around us right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re 7-ish weeks into quarantine, which means I’ve been rewatching a lot of TV. Nostalgia used to feel like an ugly word, a feeling I would wrinkle my nose at when I heard people talk about past eras. I now know this is because I was truly too young, and most of the nostalgia my peers had was constructed by media that told them to feel nostalgic for a time they never experienced. It felt artificial and white-washy, like &lt;em&gt;why would you want to experience a time in which the world was noticeably so much worse.&lt;/em&gt; Revisiting things from 2009 or 2012, though, I find myself nostalgic not for the Obama era (lmao) but the way that media carried me. Mostly, I’m thinking about shows like Glee, where I can trace so much of my fandom lineage, and that I can thank for so many of my friends (like Jillian 😀), the way I think about media, and the way I process discourse and conflict—my patience was never tested more than hiatus weeks, but the absolute &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt; those breaks generated. Unparalleled. I wasn’t in a great place mentally back then, but I can still pull fondness when I think about my shows. Something to be excited about. Something to make you feel something. I’m trying to hold onto things to be excited about—and right now, that manifests in reliving my urgency for a new episode of Glee each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-zaina-alsouss-a-theory-of-birds&quot;&gt;📖 Zaina Alsous’s &lt;em&gt;A Theory of Birds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend a lot of poetry in this newsletter, to the point where it seems like I’ve probably never read a novel, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://zainaalsous.com/&quot;&gt;Zaina’s&lt;/a&gt; collection gave me the feeling of reading a very immersive piece of fiction—not saying her work reads as prose in anyway, nor is it escapism, but there’s this incredible balance between intricacy and simplicity. Those words are not necessarily at odds, but the weight of Zaina’s work never feels overwhelming, rather gravitational. I was excited to turn each page, excited to see what else she had in store for her reader. This is a work I will revisit over and over and over again—I read each poem twice, wanting to give them all of my time, poking at Hazem to read along with me several times so that they got the attention they deserved. It’s brilliant. It’s brilliant. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781682261040&quot;&gt;Indiebound&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/a-theory-of-birds-poems/9781682261040&quot;&gt;Bookshop.org&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uapress.com/product/a-theory-of-birds/&quot;&gt;publisher’s website&lt;/a&gt; to get your copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-the-creative-independent-newsletter&quot;&gt;✉️ The Creative Independent newsletter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content that The Creative Independent puts out is always fantastic—beautiful essays about writing and other types of creative work; interviews with artists, musicians, and creators of all sorts; and guides for just about everything (from &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/guides/how-to-write-a-poem/&quot;&gt;how to write a poem&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/guides/how-to-lose-someone/&quot;&gt;how to lose someone&lt;/a&gt;)—but their &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/&quot;&gt;daily newsletter&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite way to experience what they have to offer. My most recent favorite featured an &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/jenny-odell-on-taking-the-time-you-need-to-notice-think-and-grow/&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Jenny Odell, author of &lt;em&gt;How To Do Nothing&lt;/em&gt;, which we have also &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/31&quot;&gt;recommended&lt;/a&gt;. Go read it immediately, and then subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-never-have-i-ever&quot;&gt;📺 Never Have I Ever&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly, I was hesitant to begin this show after the last few seasons of The Mindy Project, but that all faded away after the first episode. I love seeing high school shows that do away with strict caste (especially in contrast to the Glee I’ve been watching) and instead focus on the realistic fluidity of relationships; familiarity is present among basically everyone, it’s easy to be friends and find common ground with pretty much anyone when you’re in the same classes. Devi is a fantastic character—ridiculously funny and every mistake feels earned (again, in contrast to Glee). The side characters are precious and have stories I’m excited about, too—they are not set-dressing, so much the opposite in fact that assuming so is an addressed conflict. The Sherman Oaks setting is used with such a wonderful specificity and I am a sucker for anything in LA suburbs. Also there are a lot of hot people! It’s on Netflix, go enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-acnh-travel-guide&quot;&gt;🎮 ACNH Travel Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably isn’t news to anyone, but I’ve been playing a lot of Animal Crossing New Horizons lately. I want to give a shout-out to &lt;a href=&quot;http://acnhtravelguide.com&quot;&gt;this super nice companion app&lt;/a&gt; that I’ve been using that makes it easy to see which bugs and fish are in season (and available at the time you’re playing), what you’ve already found and donated to the museum, what events are coming up, and tons more. It also has links to other great community resources, so you can test out new island tunes or track and predict your turnip prices without leaving the app. Download for iOS &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/app/id1502818559&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><summary type="html">On nostalgia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 36</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/36" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 36" /><published>2020-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/36</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/36">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-quarantine&quot;&gt;On quarantine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told Summer there were two directions we could go in this week: we could write about quarantine, or we could write about something else. We both agreed it felt wrong to choose the latter, at least right now. So we’re writing about it—it’s just that writing about it is hard. Maybe because it’s no longer new; it’s been 39 days, for me, of feeling anxious every time I go outside for groceries, wearing a mask and gloves and staying as far away from other people as I can. Part of me is worried I’ll forget what it feels like to go outside without thinking about it—or that I’ll never be able to again. I am making peace with it, but that doesn’t always mean I feel good. Some days are okay, and other days I carry the heavy weight of anxiety around in my chest no matter what I do. There’s no way to put it lightly: this sucks. I am trying to take it one day at a time, and to look for small moments of joy: the sound of rain outside through an open window while I sleep, dancing in my kitchen while I make dinner, the way the sun hits my bedroom wall just right in the afternoon, underlining a line in a book that makes me feel good. (Also: I am still revisiting our &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/35&quot;&gt;last newsletter&lt;/a&gt; for suggestions of ways to feel better right now—maybe that’s something you need, too.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quarantine is really the only angle I can think about things, which I’m sure many people can relate to. I’m still working, from home, trying to keep normal business hours. I wake up, drink coffee with my boyfriend, check my turnip prices, and check my e-mail. I’ve broken the “no working in bed” rule many times these past weeks—it’s the most comfortable place to be. Every workplace annoyance feels worse, every headache or stomach pain the end of the world. I dropped half a banana today and almost cried. I’ve always been dramatic, quick to jump to the worst conclusions, ruled by anxiety, but some of it doesn’t feel as irrational now. We are making do; I’m lucky I’m with people I love, and I have others to reach out to often. Every time I am outside I am grateful in a way I wasn’t before, too. Picking produce at the grocery store a few weeks ago felt like a deeply precious thing and I love the taste of everything fresh, so much. It’s weird, it’s fucking weird, it’s tragic, and don’t let anyone make you feel weird for thinking it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-clue-1985&quot;&gt;📽️ Clue (1985)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whodunnits are just the best! I’d be wanting to see this movie for quite a bit, but it’s finally streaming on Prime Video and Kanopy. This movie is based off of the boardgame, Clue, which may not be a big selling point, but listen. It’s perfect! It’s perfect. It’s so fucking hilarious, everyone in the cast is a gem, it uses its source material very creatively, campy as hell, and has the best last line of any film in history. Nothing is better! Please go have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-collaborative-playlists&quot;&gt;🎶 Collaborative playlists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/cassiebirb&quot;&gt;Cassie&lt;/a&gt; asked a few of us to pick ten songs each to put on a collaborative playlist that we could all listen to. Picking just ten songs was surprisingly difficult, but it was fun to come up with a mix of songs that I’ve liked for a while and newer songs that I’ve been listening to a lot lately—and I loved seeing what my friends added. I won’t share our playlist, because I like that it’s just for us, but I do recommend making collaborative playlists as a really cute way to connect with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-birthright-by-george-abraham&quot;&gt;📖 Birthright by George Abraham&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/3&quot;&gt;George’s work&lt;/a&gt; has been among the &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/27&quot;&gt;batches&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/12&quot;&gt;poems&lt;/a&gt; I’ve recommended before, but their full length debut is finally here—&lt;em&gt;Birthright!&lt;/em&gt; It is a stunning, heart-wrenching, brilliant collection that I am so, so happy to finally hold in my hands. George is an absolute mastermind with form. They know how to communicate intensely and intricately, and there’s nothing more I want to do than spend hours and hours and hours with their work. You can buy it from &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttonpoetry.com/product/birthright/&quot;&gt;Button Poetry&lt;/a&gt; (make sure to check out the blurb I co-wrote with other friends, hehe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-the-morning-report&quot;&gt;✉️ The Morning Report&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hedhouseman.substack.com/p/potential-hauntings?token=eyJ1c2VyX2lkIjo5Mjc0LCJwb3N0X2lkIjozNjQyMzYsIl8iOiI4ejdKOCIsImlhdCI6MTU4NzY3ODQ2MCwiZXhwIjoxNTg3NjgyMDYwLCJpc3MiOiJwdWItNTUwMiIsInN1YiI6InBvc3QtcmVhY3Rpb24ifQ.yxQArScDu1nUUbm-sAxSwyKKYrQ50x8KWc2_2vok3NM&quot;&gt;The Morning Report&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favorite newsletters right now. It started as a series of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?src=typd&amp;amp;q=hedhouseman%3A%20%22morning%20report%22&quot;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/hedhouseman&quot;&gt;Haley Houseman&lt;/a&gt; about things she saw on early-morning walks with her dog, and is now a beautiful, occasional newsletter that is mostly about nature but is sometimes about other things, too. The most recent one, titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://hedhouseman.substack.com/p/potential-hauntings?token=eyJ1c2VyX2lkIjo5Mjc0LCJwb3N0X2lkIjozNjQyMzYsIl8iOiI4ejdKOCIsImlhdCI6MTU4NzY3ODQ2MCwiZXhwIjoxNTg3NjgyMDYwLCJpc3MiOiJwdWItNTUwMiIsInN1YiI6InBvc3QtcmVhY3Rpb24ifQ.yxQArScDu1nUUbm-sAxSwyKKYrQ50x8KWc2_2vok3NM&quot;&gt;“Potential hauntings,”&lt;/a&gt; made me feel all kinds of things, but I suggest you read &lt;a href=&quot;https://hedhouseman.substack.com/p/what-is-the-morning-report&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; to start with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><summary type="html">On quarantine</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 35</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/35" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 35" /><published>2020-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/35</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/35">&lt;p&gt;Hi, friends. This one is going to be a little different! Different because things are weird and bad right now, and it is hard to make something and put it out into our current world without acknowledging that. So here are some recommendations from us for things you can do to feel less weird and bad, and ways you can help other people who are feeling weird and bad right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re still getting paid, &lt;a href=&quot;https://berniesanders.com/lessons-coronavirus-bernie-sanders-addresses-nation/coronavirus-relief-funds/&quot;&gt;donate to someone who isn’t&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hels/status/1242498327838629888?s=21&quot;&gt;Support local businesses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do something with your hands. Water your plants. &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/20&quot;&gt;Tie dye some socks&lt;/a&gt;. Clean out your drawers and re-fold all your clothes. Learn how to knit with &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/u/1/d/1Loto44Apui8OrTth2sh9MauzxVqlEqDfvNy3gtY3o4U/mobilebasic&quot;&gt;this helpful guide&lt;/a&gt; from Alana Okun. Doodle something on whatever paper you have lying around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep in touch with your creative community by attending online poetry readings, open mics, and workshops from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/posts/poetry-online-35261720&quot;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; compiled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/arianathepoet&quot;&gt;Ariana Brown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vote.org/absentee-ballot/&quot;&gt;Apply for an absentee ballot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make some comfort food. You can find some of our favorite recipes in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/tags/food/&quot;&gt;Food&lt;/a&gt; tag (like this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-noknead-bread-home-109343&quot;&gt;no-knead bread&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/bas-best-chocolate-chip-cookies&quot;&gt;these chocolate chip cookies&lt;/a&gt;). Bon Appetit has rounded up a ton of recipes for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bonappetit.com/gallery/cooking-at-home-coronavirus&quot;&gt;“Cooking at Home in the Time of Coronavirus.”&lt;/a&gt; And &lt;a href=&quot;https://wearefoodbloggersnow.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;this collaborative food blog&lt;/a&gt; is a joy to scroll through.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lift the blinds &amp;amp; open the window.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Clean up your space. It’s easier to feel mentally clear if your space is clear.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read something—something that’s not Twitter or pandemic news. Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;https://indoor-voices.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;Indoor Voices&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative blog about quarantined life. Or maybe one of the book and poetry recommendations in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/tags/read/&quot;&gt;Read&lt;/a&gt; tag. You might already have your own massive to-read pile, but if you want to buy something new, considering ordering online from a local indie bookstore if you have the option. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcnallyjackson.com&quot;&gt;McNally Jackson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.powells.com&quot;&gt;Powell’s&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://em-wolfman-books.square.site/&quot;&gt;Wolfman&lt;/a&gt;  are some of our favorites that could use your support right now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neonrated/status/1243207001225564161&quot;&gt;Watch Portrait of a Lady on Fire on Hulu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you like doing yoga (or if you’ve been meaning to try it!) see if your local yoga studios are doing online classes right now, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skyting.com/tv/live/&quot;&gt;Sky Ting Live&lt;/a&gt;. And if you have a favorite instructor, consider Venmo-ing them right now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find a new routine. Get up and shower in the morning. Put on comfy clothes that are not the ones you slept in. If you’re working from home, try not to work in your bed. Get up and move around throughout the day. Find an activity to mark the transition from work to leisure time, like listening to a podcast or reading a book. Recognize that this is hard, but you can find small ways to make it easier.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Check in with your friends. Text them, call them, FaceTime them, schedule a Zoom call with them, visit their &lt;a href=&quot;https://animal-crossing.com/new-horizons/&quot;&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/a&gt; island, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="💡 Idea" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="📽️ Watch" /><category term="🧠 Wellness" /><summary type="html">Hi, friends. This one is going to be a little different! Different because things are weird and bad right now, and it is hard to make something and put it out into our current world without acknowledging that. So here are some recommendations from us for things you can do to feel less weird and bad, and ways you can help other people who are feeling weird and bad right now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 34</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/34" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 34" /><published>2020-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/34</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/34">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-patience&quot;&gt;On patience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mornings, I get myself out of bed and into the kitchen, and I turn on the electric kettle to heat up some water, and while the water is heating up I put a small tea strainer into a big mug, and then I pour the hot water over it and I set a timer and wait for the tea to brew for five minutes. And every morning, I know it will take just five minutes. And I know that when the five minutes is up, I’ll have a cup of tea to drink, and I’ll be able to start my day. I am not patient, because to be patient, you have to be ok with waiting for things that are out of your control, and I have a hard time with things that are out of my control. To be patient, you have to be ok with not knowing how things will turn out, and I have a hard time with not knowing how things will turn out. (Are we seeing a pattern here?) I think it is good, if you are an impatient and anxious person like me, to have some things in your life that you can count on, that you know will be there for you on a certain or at a certain time or in a certain place—things that you don’t need to wait for. I am not patient and I don’t know how to be, but I know that in five minutes, my tea will be ready, and that comforts me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am impatient, I am anxious, I do not like waiting for things; I am always way too early or running late and barely have a concept of how much time has passed. I’ve only begun to focus on managing this in the last two years, and my first step was mastering caramelizing onions. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hels&quot;&gt;Helen Rosner&lt;/a&gt; tweeted once about how all recipes lie to you about how long it takes to caramelize onions. They do! I felt dumb! But they were just lying! In the summer of 2018, I became obsessed with putting them in everything. I didn’t realize, at first, they would take upwards of an hour to cook, and any impatience in their cooking (bumping up the temperature) would basically lead to burnt onions, instead. But I did it, to varying degrees of success: notably, a quiche I made for a Bachelor in Paradise viewing, had a chorus of “oh, Summer, these onions kind of taste caramelized.” The true first success, though, was when I had a friend coming over to make a meal, had very little else to do beforehand, and just started prepping; I chopped onions, and there was an hour before they would arrive. I put them on the stove. I had no rush, and so I didn’t need them to be caramel-y sooner. The final meal tasted fantastic. I’ve caramelized onions dozens of times since, some times better than others. A lot of my anxiety comes from thinking I do not have enough time left. I want to learn to give myself that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-capable-monsters-by-marlin-m-jenkins&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;Capable Monsters&lt;/em&gt; by Marlin M. Jenkins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two things I love—Pokemon and poems—so as you’d expect, this chapbook is perfect for me. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Marlin_Poet&quot;&gt;Marlin&lt;/a&gt; does such a good job at capturing something important to a lot of people, emotionally/mentally/sentimentally (Pokemon) and unraveling its smallest parts into these beautiful reflections that communicate just &lt;em&gt;why it hits so hard.&lt;/em&gt; I am a big fan of anything that takes something maybe a little silly and lovingly, enchantingly expands on the ways it contributes to our healing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bullcitypress.com/product/capable-monsters-by-marlin-m-jenkins/&quot;&gt;Buy this book from Bull City&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-threads&quot;&gt;📱 Threads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why I didn’t know &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/threads-from-instagram/id1473867767&quot;&gt;this app&lt;/a&gt; existed until last week, but I have been using it religiously since I first downloaded it. Threads is an app from Instagram just for DMs with the people on your Close Friends list—that’s literally it. It’s great. I have been trying to spend less time on Instagram because (wow!) it sometimes makes me feel bad and I don’t like that, but it’s hard to limit your time on an app that plays a big part in how you communicate with the people you’re close to. Using Threads to separate my daily DMs from the rest of Instagram has been huge for me, and I definitely recommend it to anyone else who is tired of opening Instagram 80 times a day but still wants to send selfies with silly filters on them to their friends..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-theme-park-trash&quot;&gt;🎙️ Theme Park Trash&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of my childhood in Southern California, about 30 minutes from Disneyland, Universal Studios, Knotts’ Berry Farm, etc. etc. I knew theme park people, I wanted to be theme park people, I could have been theme park people if I’d had a driver’s license, and listen: Miya and Rosie are the best kind! They juggle that loving nostalgia and present romanticizing of places like Disneyland with the absolute full knowledge that yes, theme parks are sort of a capitalistic nightmare! Buuuuuut they’re really fun, and we can give ourselves that! Each episode, they discuss topics or imagine scenarios related to theme parks—like designing a new ride for Harry Potter World, or planning a perfect Disneyland date. Miya and Rosie are really fucking funny and also incredibly brilliant—listen to them &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/3j5OKiJ2r5PUideL79YfNL&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I’d recommend starting with one of their recent episodes, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/3ydZAXqUtRvjnPotY9BRA6&quot;&gt;Writing a Mickey Mouse Movie&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-laura-olins-newsletter&quot;&gt;✉️ Laura Olin’s newsletter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura Olin sends out a newsletter every Thursday with 10 links to nice, lovely things found on the internet, and it makes me feel good every week. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/lauraolin.com/101-1183253?e=01aecfd511&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is this week’s. I’ll let it speak for itself! If you like it, you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://tumblr.us12.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=8014320de9941eaab79e8a1ce&amp;amp;id=a6274aff24&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="🎙️ Podcast" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><summary type="html">On patience</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 33</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/33" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 33" /><published>2020-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/33</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/33">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-slowing-down&quot;&gt;On slowing down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been trying to wake up just a little bit earlier, early enough that I am allowed to spend some extra time in bed with a cup of tea before I need to get up and get ready for work, early enough to have a little bit of breathing room. Maybe I spend that time reading, or watching the pigeons on my balcony, or playing a video game. (Did you know you could play video games in the morning before work? I certainly didn’t. But you can.) Maybe I spend that time just laying in bed, doing nothing. I am often in a rush, but not in the mornings—that is when I am allowed to slow down, take my time, and breathe. Just for an hour, but it’s my hour. And then I get out of bed, and I get ready for work. And the rest of the day comes fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a fast reader. No one considered it a problem, and it didn’t become one until I was in my mid-teens, with my brain feeling bad more often than not. One thing depression took from me was comprehension and memory: I was absorbing less and less as I read, struggling more to remember what it had been that I spent an hour doing. It wasn’t until I was 19 or 20 that I really realized why, when I was in class assigned Jane Austen’s &lt;em&gt;Emma.&lt;/em&gt; My professor emphasized that Austen deserved to be read slowly; I had read two Austen novels before and did not enjoy either of them, couldn’t really tell you what had happened and blamed the text. But I was a marginally obedient student and cared too much about my grades, so of course I read. And I read slowly, pushing against my instinct. And I enjoyed it. I still couldn’t tell you small details and did poorly on comprehension quizzes, but my experience was not marked by frustration and confusion which many of my reading experiences had become. I still struggle with instinct, the motivation to do the most, the feeling that I’m not a good reader if I’m not cycling through new books every few days. I want to keep slowing down, and keep giving words the time they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-helen-rosner-interviews-samin-nosrat&quot;&gt;🔗 Helen Rosner Interviews Samin Nosrat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-interview/i-fail-almost-every-day-an-interview-with-samin-nosrat&quot;&gt;this New Yorker piece&lt;/a&gt; for a variety of reasons: Helen and Samin are two of my favorite people in the food world, the photo of Samin’s sink as she strains pickled beets, the conversation about depression, etc. The moment that struck me the most was Samin reflecting on writing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/14/dining/persian-food-recipes-samin-nosrat.html&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; about Persian food for the NYT, then interjecting, “but then, well, it turns out that people can like our food and still want to bomb us.” You might have noticed, but talking about Palestinian food is one of my main hobbies: watching others (my mom, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EGaf6yMtBF0&quot;&gt;that one BA video&lt;/a&gt;) make it, eating it, sharing it with my friends—that’s joy, that’s love. I know the people I share my food with already love me, and are already learning about the ways my people are harmed; this is not the case for every patron looking for shawarma. It’s beautiful to hope someone will taste zaatar and decide they’re ready to help free Palestine, but that’s an impossible pressure to place on cuisine. Not only will people eat our food and still bomb us, they’ll take it for their own and pretend we never existed in the first place. There are small ways to curb that, like not buying &lt;a href=&quot;http://bdslist.org/consumer/sabra-dipping-co-llc/&quot;&gt;certain hummus brands&lt;/a&gt;, vetting “Mediterranean” restaurants before you go, and so on. Food can be a tool of justice, but never on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-turning-off-notifications&quot;&gt;📱 Turning off notifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing more annoying to me than trying to concentrate on reading an article or playing a game or watching a video on my phone and seeing a bunch of banner notifications pop up to distract me—so &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jilliangmeehan/status/1231070822074327042&quot;&gt;I turned them off&lt;/a&gt;. I also turned off push notifications and badges for most of the apps on my phone, so I only get notified for things that &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need my attention, like text messages and DMs. Spend some time curating your notification settings this week—you deserve a little more quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-portrait-of-a-lady-on-fire&quot;&gt;🎥 Portrait of a Lady on Fire&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portrait of a Lady on Fire, directed by Céline Sciamma, is perhaps the best romantic film I have ever seen. The subtle eye movements, the tense collarbones, the &lt;em&gt;yearning.&lt;/em&gt; The absolute yearning, oh my god. This movie is a beautiful meditation on gaze, with the premise being a woman commissioned to paint a wedding portrait but not let the subject know she is painting her. And then (spoiler?) they fall in love. And it’s beautiful and tender and there were two scenes that made me cry and I still get goosebumps everywhere when I think about them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fandango.com/portrait-of-a-lady-on-fire-219068/movie-times&quot;&gt;Find it in a theater near you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-little-weirds-by-jenny-slate&quot;&gt;📖 Little Weirds by Jenny Slate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9780316485340&quot;&gt;Jenny Slate’s book&lt;/a&gt; a little over a week ago, but I have not stopped thinking about it. I miss reading it! It was full of nice, small passages that made me feel happy and gentle and tender. The way to read this book, in my opinion, is to wake up a little bit earlier than you need to and spend 5 minutes reading it until you feel good and soft and ready to get out of bed, and then carry that feeling with you for the rest of the day, like taking a daily multivitamin. I underlined so much of this book, but my one very favorite bit was this: &lt;strong&gt;“My vulnerability is natural and permissible and beautiful to me, and it should remind you of your responsibility to behave like a friend to me and the world.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="📖 Read" /><summary type="html">On slowing down</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 32</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/32" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 32" /><published>2020-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/32</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/32">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-goals&quot;&gt;On goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime last year, Summer and another friend and I started a monthly email thread to plan and talk about our goals for the coming month, followed by the occasional video chat for progress updates. We talked about things we wanted to accomplish in our careers, in our personal lives, and in our relationships, but we also talked about our feelings, our anxieties, the things we’re grateful for, and the things we need help with. What started as a way to voice our goals and desires and to hold each other accountable became a pleasant excuse to catch up with each other and just &lt;em&gt;talk&lt;/em&gt;. And I really can’t overstate how nice that is. We have recommended several methods for setting and tracking goals in this newsletter—including &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/6&quot;&gt;a habit-tracking app&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/4&quot;&gt;goal-tracking spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/27&quot;&gt;workbook for setting yearly goals&lt;/a&gt;, and the app mentioned below—but this is the only one that encourages community with people you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year, Oscars season approaches, and I tell myself &lt;em&gt;I will watch every film nominated for Best Picture.&lt;/em&gt; Sometimes I’ve already seen a handful in theaters, some years I haven’t seen any at all. This year was less than more, from a combination of disinterest, snubs, and general anxiety at being in Public and Seen. The best I did, before this year, was 2015 when torrenting was my friend (but of course I don’t do that anymore; I’m very cool and lawful). I’m not sure why I love awards shows, but I have since even before I loved to be mad online and wasn’t familiar with any material being awarded. I watched 15 hours of movies from Wednesday–Sunday, while still keeping my room relatively clean and putting together a viewing party with my roommate. I still didn’t see all of the Best Picture nominations, but I was satisfied with my breadth. I set a lot of goals for personal and professional development—many that I do not meet—but it’s fun to make something very &lt;em&gt;arbitrary,&lt;/em&gt; like a quota of movies, and to achieve it. Goal-setting can be fun. There can be enough time if I make enough time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-pain--glory&quot;&gt;🎥 Pain &amp;amp; Glory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was part of my Oscars binge, one of the films nominated for Best International Picture—and Antonio Banderas for Best Actor. Folks! Do you ever watch 14 hours of film directed by straight men and get exhausted, think all movies are just too long, wonder when directors stopped listening to their editors, triggering an existential spiral? And then you watch &lt;em&gt;Pain &amp;amp; Glory,&lt;/em&gt; and you are healed? I highly recommend watching this even without the saturation of indulgence beforehand. Antonio Banderas is so good, especially when I realized his most notable role for me is, in fact, &lt;em&gt;Spy Kids.&lt;/em&gt; The story follows an aging queer director, reflecting on his past and contending with his present. It is extremely tender, generous with time, and just &lt;em&gt;beautiful.&lt;/em&gt; Again, healed. Check it out, hopefully in a theater near you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tangerine&quot;&gt;📱Tangerine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tangerine.app&quot;&gt;this app&lt;/a&gt; for a few months as a beta tester, and I’m so happy that it is finally out there in the world for everyone else to use! Tangerine combines two of my favorite things—habit tracking, and mood tracking—in a beautiful and easy-to-use way. It’s made a difference in the way I approach my daily habits and routines, and has quickly become one of my most-used apps. You can download it on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/tangerine/id1468882685&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-birds-of-prey-the-fantabulous-emancipation-of-one-harley-quinn&quot;&gt;🎥 Birds of Prey: The Fantabulous Emancipation of One Harley Quinn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry, I’m recommending two movies!!!! I’ve really done nothing else since the last letter. So, I truly do not give a fuck about the DCEU, and the sparing few movies I’ve seen from that set have been pretty bad-to-mediocre. And yet! I hate that I’m basically recommending this movie because #representation, but it was really so fucking fun. A wonderfully talented cast with women of color, queer characters who get to exist besides that, a perfect soundtrack, bright colors and exciting fight scenes…there’s no reason not to see it! I love to have fun! I would die for Margot Robbie. Ewan McGregor is the best villain. Directed by Cathy Yan. Also in theaters now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-desk-lunch&quot;&gt;💌 Desk Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I (obviously) love newsletters, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.desklunchnewsletter.com&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; is one of my very favorites. Every issue of Desk Lunch is written by a different creative person about their process, their life, their journey, their thoughts. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/desklunchnewsletter/issue-97-perpetually-seeking-carolyn-yoo?e=b36865b50b&quot;&gt;latest issue&lt;/a&gt;, which I read this morning, was so good and relevant to me in particular—Carolyn Yoo writes about struggling to answer &lt;em&gt;“The Question”&lt;/em&gt; of her career path: “Perhaps I would keep searching for what I was meant to do for many more years of my life, but I could learn to embrace the spiral instead of resenting that I hadn’t reached an answer yet.” Whew. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.us16.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=9a0a385211ebb7b21b0ef828a&amp;amp;id=908a07a835&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to Desk Lunch for more great stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="💌 Newsletter" /><summary type="html">On goals</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 31</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/31" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 31" /><published>2020-01-30T16:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-30T16:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/31</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/31">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-social-media&quot;&gt;On social media&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time for my scheduled annual spiral about social media—that lovely time of year when I wonder what I’m doing on Instagram and Twitter, what I’m trying to get out of it, what I should be posting, who I actually care about following, and what it all means. The cycle goes like this: I decide I want to spend less time feeling bad on social media, so I unfollow a bunch of accounts that aren’t contributing to my life in a meaningful way to clear up my feed and make it easier to less time scrolling and more time seeing only the content I care about; a week later, I get bored and decide I’m not getting enough out of social media, so I find and follow a bunch of new accounts that are exciting or inspiring to me in some way; then, the cycle continues. Maybe the trick is to make peace with this ebb and flow of being very online, instead of feeling weird and bad about it. Maybe the trick is just &lt;em&gt;not overthinking it&lt;/em&gt;. For now, I still don’t really know what I’m doing and I still feel very conflicted about the way I use social media—but if I figure it out, I’ll let you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve lived most of my life online. I found my first internet friends when I was 10, feeling alone, caring too much about too many things; I’m 22 now, and sort of the same. My friends are far away, my boyfriend is far away, my family is far away. I’ve loved so many people from such a distance. As social media becomes part of everyone’s social habits, inextricable from the “real world,” those friendships are stronger, but they’re intertwined with everything that sucks. I read about a shooting and wish my friend a happy birthday in the same thought; I read about my people fighting for their freedom and see others celebrating a game before I finish the headline. I never want to be an old man shouting at a cloud. We can all care about so, so many things, and that is how I got here in the first place. I never want to dismiss the lifesaving connections social media has brought me. I don’t know how to navigate my escapism collapsing into what I escape from, even though it’s been happening for years—even more, I don’t know how to deal with the fact that I don’t want to escape anymore. I want to &lt;em&gt;know.&lt;/em&gt; I don’t want distance. From anyone, from anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-reconstructions-by-bradley-trumpfheller&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;strong&gt;Reconstructions&lt;/strong&gt; by Bradley Trumpfheller&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend has a chapbook and it’s one of the most stunning things you will read in 2020. (I don’t care that it’s only January!) Bradley is ridiculously talented. Each of their poems just feels in love with the medium, in love with the page, trying to run off of it—there’s an elegance to the weight of just how  &lt;em&gt;impressive&lt;/em&gt; their work is. I read it on a plane &amp;amp; studied it for hours after. It deserves so, so much attention. You can buy &lt;em&gt;Reconstructions&lt;/em&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://siblingrivalrypress.bigcartel.com/product/reconstructions-by-bradley-trumpfheller&quot;&gt;Sibling Rivalry Press website!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-how-to-do-nothing&quot;&gt;📖 How To Do Nothing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think everyone should be required to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781612197494&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt;, full stop. I highlighted lines on nearly every page, but here is a favorite, from the introduction, that will give you a sense of what this book is all about: “The point of doing nothing, as I define it, isn’t to return to work refreshed and ready to be more productive, but rather to question what we currently perceive as productive.” This is not just a book about birdwatching and quitting Facebook—it is a book about collective action and shared public spaces and attention and art and community. If you’ve read it, DM me so we can talk. If you haven’t, you need to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-high-school-musical-the-musical-the-series&quot;&gt;📺 High School Musical: The Musical: The Series&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RlaV8sJGhfc&quot;&gt;trailer dropped&lt;/a&gt; for this show, all I could think was &lt;em&gt;this is for me.&lt;/em&gt; I’m a survivor of the Glee fandom (as is Jillian), and yes! It did warp my brain! I am hungry for disaster surrounded by a song (this explains why I can’t stop thinking about &lt;em&gt;CATS (2019),&lt;/em&gt; too)!  I wanted this show to be like &lt;em&gt;Riverdale,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Nancy Drew,&lt;/em&gt; just absurd and a good time and makes you think &lt;em&gt;wait, am I so irony-poisoned that I’ve turned this into my favorite show?&lt;/em&gt; BUT! TWIST! This show is actually fucking great! No irony! Full seriousness! It holds all of the camp and cradles it, it acknowledges its predecessors (&lt;em&gt;HSM&lt;/em&gt; as much as &lt;em&gt;Glee&lt;/em&gt; as much as all other teen comedies), and does so, so good by its teens. Basically everyone gets complexity, everyone gets a full life, they are kind, they are mean, and they are jealous, but never cartoonishly or destructively. They sing well but it doesn’t feel like, &lt;em&gt;oh ok cool we love 30-year-old Broadway veterans&lt;/em&gt;. There are characters of color, there are queer characters (QPOC, even!) There’s a Palestinian flag! Just! In the background of a scene? Yes, reader, I cried! Watch it on Disney+, my reluctant ally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-shrill&quot;&gt;📺 Shrill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked through our archives to see if we had already mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hulu.com/series/shrill-54eab813-3a9b-496d-9d7e-908597ad8d1a&quot;&gt;this show&lt;/a&gt;, because I was &lt;em&gt;sure&lt;/em&gt; we had—but somehow, no! Which is a problem, because this show is brilliant and funny and makes me feel so good. The second season just came out on Hulu, and we are all so lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="📺 TV" /><summary type="html">On social media</summary></entry></feed>