<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-05T22:27:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Letters To Summer</title><subtitle>Two friends sharing the things they're reading, watching, listening to, and enjoying. In your inbox every other Thursday.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Letter 61</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/61/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 61" /><published>2021-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/61</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/61/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-digital-communication&quot;&gt;On digital communication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve met most of my best friends on Tumblr and Twitter, so I’ve always been really comfortable communicating and building relationships online. I have a lot of feelings about the way I navigate social media based on the 10+ years I’ve been doing it, I guess, and with that comes a lot of feelings about how I communicate with friends both privately and publicly—in DMs, in tweets, in group chats, in Discord servers, in text messages, and IRL. I think there’s a time and place for each of these, and it’s not even something that I can articulate very well, just something that feels instinctual to me. (A side effect of having so many communication channels: sometimes I find myself having three different conversations with a friend at the same time via three different apps.) Lately, I’ve been leaning into private, one-on-one conversations a little bit more—Summer took a small break from Twitter, so suddenly I had an excuse to spend all day texting her little updates about my life; and I met a friend to drink boba in the park over the weekend so we could catch up in person. Both felt really nice and really natural. There are so many ways to stay connected with people you care about online, and the thing is it doesn’t really matter how you do it as long as you…do it. I think that’s the point I wanted to make, who knows. Text your friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’m afraid I’m more charismatic online than I am in person. I have a lot of social anxiety, manifesting in both ends of the spectrum: I am kind of weird, quiet, hiding behind people I know, or I am overly energetic and obnoxious and feel like death when I am alone again. I’m embarrassed by what comes out of my mouth even if there is no reason to be. It is not that I am more cautious or filtered when I communicate through text, but something about my tone feels more confident. I barely know the voices of some of the people I trust the most in the world, because our communication has been always online. I’ve seen a slow reconsideration of friendships forged on the internet in the last few years and I think the pandemic has only reinforced how strong digital communication has the potential to be, if only you put work and effort into the relationships (like literally any relationship lol) formed through it. I love when my friends text me out of the blue and I love when people check up on me, I love stupid e-mails and IG DMs and anything people do to keep up and keep in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-how-drivers-license-by-olivia-rodrigo-captures-suburban-sadness-from-flash-thrive&quot;&gt;🔗 how DRIVERS LICENSE by OLIVIA RODRIGO captures suburban sadness from Flash Thrive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok so I hadn’t actually heard &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZmDBbnmKpqQ&quot;&gt;this song&lt;/a&gt; before I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4MiF-xxt-Q0&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; essay and I only connected the dots that the Olivia Rodrigo people keep talking about is the girl in &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/31&quot;&gt;High School Musical: The Musical: The Series&lt;/a&gt; like a week ago, and YET! This analysis made me cry? It probably has something to do with the fact that I’m back in the suburbs in my childhood home and cannot even drive, but anyway. Rosie’s video essays are the absolute best—if you care about Coming of Age 2010s aesthetics and where that all comes from, I highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-uncanny-counter&quot;&gt;📺 The Uncanny Counter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I am the kind of person who feels way too many feelings and loses her mind at every TV show. So, full disclosure, I basically recommend every TV show I’ve ever watched. And if I don’t, it’s because Summer already recommended it and that’s why I decided to watch it. All this to say: I recently finished the first season of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjq1qiQ9ZLwAhV4MlkFHe2qC4UQFjAKegQIAhAD&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.netflix.com%2Ftitle%2F81323551&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3aaBmQdFFqYVtEhPvjpbZE&quot;&gt;The Uncanny Counter&lt;/a&gt; and it made me cry on several occasions and I love all of the characters and their amazing fits with my whole heart. My elevator pitch is that it’s like if the Grim Reaper was a very adorable high school boy with a found family and lots of good turtleneck/jacket combos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-muppets-2011&quot;&gt;🎥 The Muppets (2011)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I asked my TL what is a movie that feels like &lt;em&gt;Mamma Mia!,&lt;/em&gt; because I was sad and wanted that level of comfort but felt like watching something new. My friend Nico suggested &lt;em&gt;The Muppets&lt;/em&gt; and it honestly was a top 5 decision of 2021. It’s silly and sweet and the music is great, a truly All Ages type of movie that does not condescend or resort to cheap humor. I cried? which is fine and normal, I don’t think there’s ever been a movie I didn’t cry at, but wow! It’s on Netflix, please go have fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-star-projectors&quot;&gt;🔗 Star projectors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got this a projector recently as part of my quest to make my bedroom as cozy as possible and it’s my new favorite thing. Every night, I turn it + a pink lamp on and light a candle in my bedroom, and it has become a 10000x more fun and relaxing space. I didn’t do a ton of research, so there may be other star projectors out there that are better for you, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/slredirect/picassoRedirect.html/ref=pa_sp_atf_aps_sr_pg1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;adId=A009563818FGV3586F8DY&amp;amp;url=%2FBlissLights-Sky-Lite-Projector-Ambiance%2Fdp%2FB07L8R5PK6%2Fref%3Dsr_1_2_sspa%3Fdchild%3D1%26keywords%3Dstar%2Bprojector%26qid%3D1619131053%26sr%3D8-2-spons%26psc%3D1&amp;amp;qualifier=1619131053&amp;amp;id=1180205478372372&amp;amp;widgetName=sp_atf&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is the one I got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎥 Movie" /><summary type="html">On digital communication</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 60</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/60/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 60" /><published>2021-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/60</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/60/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-astrology&quot;&gt;On astrology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school, I remember borrowing a friend’s astrology book and staying up late to flip through it, trying to piece together my birth chart and what it all meant. Now I am intimately familiar with my birth chart—and my friends’ birth charts, thanks to Co-star—and follow astrology meme accounts on Instagram. If you ask me if I “believe” in astrology, I think you’re kind of missing the point. I don’t care if the position of the planets actually has any “real” affect on my life. I like astrology as a tool for thinking about my actions and who I am, for recognizing patterns in my life and the world around me, for learning how to make sense of things, for relating to people who also have Virgo in their charts, etc. It’s fun, and sometimes comforting, to read my horoscope or keep track of which planets are in retrograde or compare birth charts with friends. Reading that astrology book in high school felt like a big awakening for me—not just because I finally knew what it meant to have a Scorpio sun, but because I found a new way to look at things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started thinking more deeply about astrology when I was in high school, early college; I had friends (like Jillian) who Knew Their Shit and started talking about things I had never known about—moon signs, rising signs, how different placements affect the body. For someone who had always felt like there was something kind of &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; with their body, with their brain, it was comforting to point cosmologically to how I was feeling. It felt less like explanation and more like seeking precedence, more like an analytical tool to find the truth—not so much &lt;em&gt;blame it on the planets,&lt;/em&gt; rather, &lt;em&gt;use the planets to figure out where exactly the core of this is coming from.&lt;/em&gt; I never ended up digging as deep as other people I love did, nor did I ever familiarize myself with the full meaning of it all, but it’s something patiently, presently there at the back of my head. I like the reminders to check in with myself if there is a pisces moon, or letting mercury in retrograde remind me bad/frustrating things are not always within my control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-salat-by-dujie-tahat&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;Salat&lt;/em&gt; by Dujie Tahat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love chapbooks that use their space &amp;amp; form so well, chaps that feel like they &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; exist in this form: Dujie Tahat’s &lt;em&gt;Salat&lt;/em&gt; is just that. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dujietahat.com/bio/&quot;&gt;Dujie’s&lt;/a&gt; writing is absolutely stunning—the book takes on the form of prayer, and each poem echoes that meditation so well. I read it cover to cover twice through as soon as I got it and have been thinking about it every week since. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tupelopress.org/product/salat/&quot;&gt;You can buy it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cherry-blossom-trees&quot;&gt;💡 Cherry blossom trees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to the Brooklyn Botanical Garden yesterday to see the cherry blossom and magnolia trees beginning to bloom and it put me in the best mood!!! Please, if you live somewhere that has pretty blooming trees right now, take some time to just go outside and admire them for a while. Take a bunch of pictures. Post them so other people can feel the good vibes. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-rilo-kiley-1999&quot;&gt;🎶 Rilo Kiley 1999&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommended the Rilo Kiley album &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/23&quot;&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; a while back. Their music has been in my regular rotation since that newsletter, basically, but this past week I let them be my main on-shuffle artist and found myself particularly drawn to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7bYq6huhr7JsnkoPExW1Xz?si=rst-Mc0rT-m0pxxOtxsAlw&quot;&gt;self-titled, first album&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not great at writing about music but there is something about Jenny Lewis’s voice that just makes me feel in-tune with myself, even if who I am at the current moment is pretty insufferable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-sandalwood-incense&quot;&gt;🖇️ Sandalwood incense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://grandteaimports.com&quot;&gt;Grand Tea Imports&lt;/a&gt; has really good tea, and maybe I’ll recommend some of that another time, but I also really like their &lt;a href=&quot;https://grandteaimports.com/products/extra-thin-no-smoke-sandalwood-incense&quot;&gt;sandalwood incense&lt;/a&gt;. Whenever I want some really cozy vibes, I light a stick of this in my living room and it completely resets my brain—it’s a signal that it’s time to relax for a second. Smells great, doesn’t fill the room with smoke, supports a small local business, 10/10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="💡 Idea" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><summary type="html">On astrology</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 59</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/59/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 59" /><published>2021-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/59</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/59/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-breakfast&quot;&gt;On breakfast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not good at eating breakfast, most days. Like, I love eggs and bagels and bacon and toast and all that—I do! But I also love to sleep in late and then rush to start my day, and there is usually not enough time for breakfast in that routine. When I was still working on an office every day, I got into the habit of eating a Clif bar from the office snack stash every day while I made my tea in the morning. Once I started working from home because of the pandemic, I was on my own. Eventually I started buying Clif bars for myself, because even though I am bad at breakfast, I still need to eat something in the morning if I want to make it through the day. Yes, I could wake up earlier and learn how to slow down and enjoy some scrambled eggs first thing in the morning if I really tried. That sounds like it would be nice. For now, though, the best I can do most days is a protein bar with chocolate chips in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not hungry when I wake up. I work better if I’m fed. These are two truths that often conflicted back in the days of going to a physical place that is not my bedroom to complete my job. I used to wake up, drink coffee, make more coffee, run to work, and crash very soon after, running only on caffeine and the anxiety of going from one place to the next before my hunger kicked in. Although breakfast is, allegedly, “the most important meal of the day” (this feels like some sort of American capitalist propaganda, idk man), it really always felt like something special rather than necessary. When I think of breakfast, I think of plans with friends—the effort and care put into waking up, giving ourselves time and space between this act and doing anything else, and then coming together to eat incredibly heavy, ridiculous amounts of food. I think of my family; Palestinian breakfasts are large, spanning many different plates—I do not like eggs but I will eat them on my mother’s breakfast table, alongside pickled turnips and labneh and fresh bread and olives and all of the other things people will make fun of me for writing poems about. Having breakfast means I am giving myself time and care and space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-reading-sucks&quot;&gt;✉️ Reading Sucks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ellomelissa.substack.com/&quot;&gt;Melissa Lozada-Oliva’s newsletter&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favorite things. I “love reading” and based on this newsletter it can seem like I am an “avid” or “consistent” reader. While I can meet my pseudo-goals, I still carry a lot of guilt with reading, especially against the other ways I spend my time. Sometimes, I think, what could I have accomplished if instead of banking 50 hours on Ace Attorney in two weeks, I did 50 hours of reading? But this line of thinking simply is not productive. I worry about reading many books at once, or the time it takes me to finish something—this keeps me from reading long books—but reading Melissa’s newsletter has been really comforting for feeling kinship with someone who also is always trying, but actively acknowledging sometimes we do other things, sometimes our brains get in the way, and sometimes the world simply does not give us the space and attention for reading. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ellomelissa.substack.com/subscribe?utm_source=menu&amp;amp;simple=true&amp;amp;next=https%3A%2F%2Fellomelissa.substack.com%2F&quot;&gt;You can subscribe here,&lt;/a&gt; and check out the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://ellomelissa.substack.com/p/what-i-read-this-week-0f1&quot;&gt;recent one with an interview with one of my faves, Hannah Rego&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-stickers&quot;&gt;🔗 Stickers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked about &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/56/&quot;&gt;using a planner&lt;/a&gt; in this newsletter before, but I just recently started putting stickers in my planner every day to pretend I am one of those cute studygram accounts with adorable bullet journal spreads and it has brought me a lot of joy. I got a bunch of stickers from &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/56/&quot;&gt;Kawaii Pen Shop&lt;/a&gt; recently, and I also get some from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/punimelt/posts&quot;&gt;Punimelt’s Patreon&lt;/a&gt; every month, which I love and endorse very much. Get some stickers! Actually use them! Put them all over your stuff! It will make you happy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-ergonomic-grip-for-switch&quot;&gt;🎮 Ergonomic Grip for Switch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I have pain literally everywhere, but I won’t let it stop me from gaming for six hours. There are games I like playing handheld more than docked, and so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.satisfye.com/products/zengrip-pro&quot;&gt;this ergonomic grip&lt;/a&gt; for my Switch has been really helpful; there are a lot of different options, though, so shop around for what suits you. Just know it exists and your hands will love you for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-magic-spoon-cereal&quot;&gt;🍽️ Magic Spoon cereal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually kind of hate myself for recommending trendy, DTC cereal, but since we’re on the topic of breakfast I gotta say that I have been eating and enjoying &lt;a href=&quot;https://magicspoon.com&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; lately. I really like the cookies and cream flavor, and I really like that it has a lot of protein in it because I need that if I want to get through the day without feeling like death. This is pretty good stuff to have around for breakfast—or days when you really truly do not have the energy to make an actual meal for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><summary type="html">On breakfast</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 58</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/58/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 58" /><published>2021-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/58</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/58/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-self-care&quot;&gt;On self care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be dramatic but sometimes existing in this world is hard. Like, the idea of getting out of bed and sitting at my desk for several hours a day, or cooking a meal for myself and then washing all the dishes, or even just taking a shower and washing my face—sometimes it’s just too much. Sometimes it feels like the best I can do is lay on the couch in yesterday’s t-shirt and eat a bowl of cereal and play video games. And that’s cool! I am trying to be a lot more forgiving with myself on those days. But I am also trying to take better care of myself, to at least do the bare minimum. Yes, sure, sheet masks and bubble baths are self care. But so is brushing your teeth and taking a big gulp of water on the hard days. So is cleaning off a tiny area of your desk so you feel a little less stressed while you’re working. (And so is knowing when to stop pushing yourself and just lay down on the couch for a little bit.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while I thought I “wasn’t into skincare,” because so much of what I saw online was about glamorous ritual and this indulgence into complicated process. It was also largely focused on the face. As conversations around the capitalism-poisoned term “self care” grew more prevalent in the spaces I frequented, I realized of course, I was “into skincare”—because I have to be! I have eczema! In fact, I am deeply into taking care and managing the health of my skin, otherwise I’m covered in cuts from dry skin cracking! It took literally re-arranging the phrase—instead of self care, it’s &lt;em&gt;taking care of yourself—&lt;/em&gt;for me to realize self care isn’t a trendy thing I’m behind on. Allowing this to be an act instead of a concept helped me think about the things I actually need to do in order to regulate my health, thinking about how to continually fold them into my routine: drinking water, sleeping early, flossing—normal things that are very hard when you’re depressed. The extra, the sometimes superfluous—an extra special meal, staying in bed longer than normal—these things can be folded into taking care of myself, too, but I can’t ignore the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-soft-scrambled-eggs&quot;&gt;🍽️ Soft scrambled eggs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never liked eggs growing up. My parents would try a myriad of ways of trying to get me to eat them since they’re “good for you,” but I refused unless very specific circumstances were met (I wanted to play video games with my brother while eating). When I started college, eggs were an easy source of protein and very easy to bulk up sad leftovers—you know when there’s like, half a serving left of basically any meal? Add an egg! It’s great. But my favorite way to eat them are creamy, soft-scrambled on really crusty bread, spinach, and some soft cheese spread—season with salt, pepper, and chili flakes. I had this for breakfast the other day and just remembered, yes! This is the best thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-homemade-iced-chai&quot;&gt;🍽️ Homemade iced chai&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love iced chais—the venti ones at Starbucks singlehandedly got me through college. Now, though, they’re a pretty rare treat for me since I don’t go to coffee shops all that often. But! Last week I picked up a container of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tazo.com/us/en/products/lattes-iced/classic-chai-latte.html&quot;&gt;Tazo’s chai concentrate&lt;/a&gt; at the grocery store and used it to make a pretty yummy iced chai with oat milk at home. I think it’s going to be my new Friday morning treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-samias-the-baby&quot;&gt;🎶 Samia’s The Baby&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first heard Samia in 2018 or 2019 when she had just a handful of songs on Spotify; she came up on some indie sad girl playlist and I loved the absolute crazy intensity of her voice, but she wasn’t on my regular rotation until 2020. Her semi-recently released &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7faAwJDTt9Y8kVAcSHy9Y6&quot;&gt;The Baby&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; along with the cover-album &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7MGuErisn7eWnGriy2iGbZ&quot;&gt;The Baby Reimagined&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are equally excellent and a very good, vibe-y time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-dram&quot;&gt;🍽️ Dram&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another beverage! I tried this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dramapothecary.com&quot;&gt;“herbal sparkling water”&lt;/a&gt; on a whim the other day and liked it a lot—I got the cardamom &amp;amp; black tea flavor, which is a pretty weird (but delicious) flavor for sparkling water. Turns out they have some other cool-sounding flavors, plus a CBD version, which I really want to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><summary type="html">On self care</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 57</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/57/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 57" /><published>2021-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/57</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/57/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-changing-seasons&quot;&gt;On changing seasons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I played Animal Crossing today, the snow had finally melted to reveal grayish-green grass, a sign that spring is coming to my little video game island. In real life, too, the snow has mostly melted away. This week has been warmer and sunnier—I can go outside without having to shove my hands inside my pockets. I’m hungry for warm weather, for shorts and sweatshirt weather, for walks-in-the-park weather. I think we’re almost on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been GOING OUTSIDE lately. Since I live in Southern California, it has less to do with the temperature being bearable and more to do with how long it’s bright out. I have been trying to take meetings outside. Yesterday, after work, I painted in the sun at 5PM. I was so happy to still have some daylight after work. I forgot how much winter affects me, especially with a specific work schedule—I am not someone who prioritizes doing things like “getting Vitamin D,” but the season change is so, so welcome because it means I have more opportunities to do the basic, healthy thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-tonys-chocolonely&quot;&gt;🍽️ Tony’s Chocolonely&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is my first memory of eating &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonyschocolonely.com/us/en&quot;&gt;this chocolate&lt;/a&gt;: early in the pandemic, my partner put a giant chocolate bar into our grocery cart and said he had tried it before, and it was good. I was like, ok, I love chocolate, let’s go. And it was the best chocolate I’d ever had! We realized they carried it at the market near my apartment, too, it became a snacky staple. This is honestly my favorite chocolate, I will eat a whole bar throughout the course of the day and only feel a little gross. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonyschocolonely.com/us/en/chocoshop/product/milk-caramel-sea-salt-32-1&quot;&gt;mix-ins are absolutely spectacular&lt;/a&gt;. The chocolate is also ethically sourced! Highly recommend for something sweet to look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-ikenfell&quot;&gt;🎮 Ikenfell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humblegames.com/games/ikenfell/&quot;&gt;this game&lt;/a&gt; last year and never finished playing it because I got distracted by other things—but I picked it back up a couple of weeks ago and I’ve really been loving it. It’s a cute, magical indie RPG with a great soundtrack and lots of queer characters, and there’s really nothing not to like about that as far as I’m concerned. It’s also really forgiving to players who want to make the battles a little easier (or just skip them altogether in favor of experiencing the story) which I always love to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-ace-attorney-trilogy&quot;&gt;🎮 Ace Attorney Trilogy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These games are old and thus have been on my radar for years. I have friends who love them dearly and because of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/phoenix-wright-ace-attorney-trilogy-switch/&quot;&gt;eShop sale&lt;/a&gt; at the beginning of this year, I have joined them! These games are so campy! The writing is so silly! I love to have fun. They fully engrossed me in the 40ish hours it takes to play through the games available for Switch—I finished everything maybe in the second week of January and I haven’t been able to stop thinking about them! I’m begging Capcom to put the rest of the games on Switch, but you can play literally any of them on your phone, your computer, your PlayStation, your 3ds. Anything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-lofi-video-game-music&quot;&gt;🎶 Lofi video game music&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days I’m pretty much incapable of getting any work done if I’m not listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wofB1wzyYYI&amp;amp;t=1193s&quot;&gt;Genshin Impact Lofi ✨ 1 Hour Lofi Hip Hop&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube, or something similar. Video game soundtracks are just good! I like to have them on in the background all the time! I also really like &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/0L8SKsIJlQ4TDEJ86clycU?si=spNBbqrFS7esq16qXWBVtw&quot;&gt;this Spotify playlist&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8flvMNTM7NE&quot;&gt;this YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><summary type="html">On changing seasons</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 56</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/56/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 56" /><published>2021-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/56</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/56/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-starting-over&quot;&gt;On starting over&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just moved into a new apartment a little over a week ago, which is always a weird and exciting and stressful experience. I’m in a new neighborhood, living on my own for the first time in my life, moving all the furniture around to see what feels right. Starting over is fun, but it’s also a little bit scary—so I find comfort in the things in my life that have &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; changed. Things like blankets and plants and cups of pens that I brought over from my last place. Things like video games that I feel like I could play forever (I just started playing Fire Emblem: Three Houses again). Things like TV shows and movies that I’ve already seen a billion times and love to rewatch. That’s a different kind of starting over, one that never changes and keeps me feeling steady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of unfinished notebooks. Some of them are for specific uses: a notebook to practice my Arabic in, a notebook to write recipes in, a notebook for my work-to-dos. I have a poetry notebook, an essays notebook that’s sometimes a poetry notebook but also sometimes a personal to-do list, a notebook to write about the books I read—on &amp;amp; on &amp;amp; on. I want to just &lt;em&gt;finish them&lt;/em&gt; so I can buy another &amp;amp; start fresh. I love the possibilities of a new notebook but treat them far too preciously. I struggle with clean-slates, with starting over; this manifests so minorly in my Animal Crossing House, my rooms haphazardly built throughout the months with furniture I had at the time &amp;amp; struggle to switch out, building instead of shaping. I want to! I want my brain to be clean, smooth, to build itself back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-limits-of-the-lunchbox-moment-by-jaya-saxena&quot;&gt;🔗 The Limits of the Lunchbox Moment by Jaya Saxena&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food writing is one of my favorite genres, but there’s often been a disconnect for me when I read the stories other children if immigrants write—specifically, the focus on the “lunchbox moment” in which a child of color is mocked for bringing their traditional food to school. There are an overwhelming number of factors that contribute to this being unrelatable to me, but I often felt frustrated by the lack of alternative stories in how food, especially at a young age, factors into racism and marginalization (as well as ignoring broader issues such as access and colonialism). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eater.com/22239499/lunchbox-moment-pop-culture-tropes&quot;&gt;This piece&lt;/a&gt; unpacks the “lunchbox moment” so, so well, featuring an array of conversations with people of color talking about their relationship to the “moment,” food, and what their experiences genuinely looked like. The writer does something remarkable, as well, and talks about a piece she’d written in the past, examining where her claims had come from; did she simply forget something she had written about, or were the events manufactured, based on broader pressures in the industry? It’s a great piece of food writing, but also so productive for the more institutional ramifications of shallow identity politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-hobonichi-planner&quot;&gt;🔗 Hobonichi planner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been good at using planners, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2021/pc/detail_cover/cb21_jan/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; was an impulse buy last year when I started working from home and I’ve loved it ever since. I don’t know if it makes me more productive or more organized than before, but I really enjoy taking the time to fill out my schedule every week, and I do think it’s helpful to keep open in front of me while I work so I can jot down notes to myself and things I need to do. JetPens has a helpful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/guide-to-the-hobonichi-techo-planner/pt/900&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; to the Hobonichi lineup that can help you choose one that suits your needs—I like the A5 Cousin because of the big daily pages, personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-lolita-podcast&quot;&gt;🎙️ Lolita Podcast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recommended Jamie Loftus’s work a few times on this newsletter—she is simply my favorite comedian—but &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/4dvc06zTAaAylzdTrsgKzp&quot;&gt;this podcast&lt;/a&gt; is a little different; in it, she explores the cultural legacy of Nabokov’s &lt;em&gt;Lolita&lt;/em&gt; through the (awful) film adaptations, the fashion culture, the way references appear (poorly) in the zeitgeist, in music; it’s an impeccable piece of scholarship and journalism. In my years as an English Major™, I don’t think I ever encountered a research question approached with such thorough care. I learned SO MUCH, leaving the series equal levels grateful &amp;amp; horrified. BIG MAJOR TRIGGER WARNINGS for discussions of child sexual assault, pedophilia, and rape. I had to listen to each episode in pieces, so make sure you take your time. Find it wherever you listen to podcasts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-shower-eucalyptus&quot;&gt;💡 Shower eucalyptus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I did when I moved into my new apartment (before I even finished fully unpacking) was get a bundle of eucalyptus from a bodega down the street and tie it to my showerhead. Eucalyptus is great! It looks nice and smells nice and putting it in your shower is a really simple thing you can do to make the whole bathroom feel a little nicer. Look for it at your local bodega, grocery store, or flower shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🎙️ Podcast" /><category term="💡 Idea" /><summary type="html">On starting over</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 55</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/55/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 55" /><published>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/55</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/55/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-sleep&quot;&gt;On sleep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember being a teenager and staying up until 4 a.m. on Tumblr for no good reason, or pulling all-nighters to finish writing essays—I could never do that now. Now, I can’t function on less than eight hours of sleep. Now, I like having a bedtime and sticking to it. My body has found a rhythm it likes: I get sleepy around midnight, I wake up at 8:00 a.m., and I hit snooze a few too many times until I finally drag myself out of bed to make tea. Consistency and routine is important to me in most things, and sleep is no exception. That said, I’m getting better at letting myself break out of that routine, sometimes staying up a couple extra hours to laugh at stuff online with my friends, just because I can and it makes me feel good. Yes, I’ll be extra tired in the morning. But that’s a problem for future me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I would wake up at the odd hours of the night, turn on all of the lights in my room, and just resume playing with my toys. Sometimes I would make enough noise for my parents to come check on me, bleary-eyed and confused at my utter lack of nighttime decorum. They’d gently tell me to go back to sleep, turn off the lights, and leave. I can’t remember how long it would take to fall asleep again. I feel like I go from the extreme ends of sleep—either I am napping during the day, getting ready for bed by 10 and struggling to rise at 9, or I’m awake until 2 and eyes-open at 4:30. Between all of those extremes is the constant in which it is difficult to simply &lt;em&gt;fall asleep.&lt;/em&gt; I’ve tried many things: putting my phone in a different room, melatonin, chamomile, reading before bed, hot baths, exercising, meditation: my body is REALLY &lt;em&gt;awake&lt;/em&gt; or it’s ABSOLUTELY &lt;em&gt;asleep&lt;/em&gt; and unfortunately I am not the boss of that. One day I’ll have a healthier relationship to sleep. I know what 4AM sounds like for no good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-shahr-e-jaanaan-the-city-of-the-beloved-by-adeeba-shahid-talukder&quot;&gt;📖 Shahr-E-Jaanaan: The City of the Beloved by Adeeba Shahid Talukder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book feels bigger than I fully understand. This collection seeks to re-create Urdu classical poetry tradition. Every spread is STUNNING, there are so many magical moments at the sentence level, at the formal level—I read it in two sittings, but I’ll definitely be re-reading it over and over again at a slower pace. I want essays! I want annotations! I want to know everything about these poems! Get your copy from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/shahr-e-jaanaan-the-city-of-the-beloved/9781946482297&quot;&gt;Bookshop&lt;/a&gt; or a local indie!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-opal&quot;&gt;📱 Opal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opal.so&quot;&gt;this app&lt;/a&gt; for a while, so when it finally launched this week I downloaded it immediately. Basically, it’s a more-fun version of iOS Screen Time—you can block certain apps for small chunks of time while you work, set up schedules to block apps at the same time every day, or just keep it running all the time and take 10 minute breaks to check Twitter as needed. I’m enjoying it a lot already, and I’m really looking forward to seeing what they add in future updates. (Also: you do have to pay for premium features, but students and academics can apply for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opal.so/students&quot;&gt;discount&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-lorde&quot;&gt;🎶 Lorde&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You all know and love her! She’s coming out with a ridiculous photobook soon that I absolutely pre-ordered the second I saw it was available! Whenever I start having “oh my GOD I’m a college graduate who is working full time and also we’re in a global pandemic and also I don’t know if I spent my time so far wisely and I know I’m not old and there’s so much life after your twenties but what if I’m afraid of living fully forever” I just turn on Pure Heroine and jump to Melodrama after and then let it all shuffle and blend together. They don’t quite hit for the crisis I’m in, but what I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; know is the next album &lt;em&gt;will,&lt;/em&gt; and that’s all I need to calm down, just a little bit. Lorde will always get me! Stream her literally everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-virtual-cottage&quot;&gt;📱 Virtual Cottage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://dui.itch.io/virtual-cottage&quot;&gt;this desktop app&lt;/a&gt; months ago and thought it looked so cozy and nice, but I couldn’t use it on my Mac—then last week I clicked on it again and saw they added a Mac version! And I was right, it is very cozy and nice. I like to keep it open all day and listen to the rain and lofi music while I work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><summary type="html">On sleep</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 54</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/54/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 54" /><published>2021-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/54</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/54/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-moving&quot;&gt;On moving&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a kid, I don’t think I ever lived in one place longer than ten years; and as an adult I’ve never stayed in an apartment longer than three. Having one place to call home for dozens of years sounds like a nice fantasy, but I have a hard time picturing a future that doesn’t include moving from one tiny Brooklyn apartment to another every few years. At the end of this month, I’ll be moving out of a neighborhood I’ve lived in for three years, out of an apartment I’ve lived in for two, and into a studio where I’ll be living alone for the first time in my life. It’s weird and scary and exciting and stressful and cool and I just want it to be over as soon as possible. I’m trying not to think about the fact that the bedroom I’m in right now won’t be my bedroom anymore in a few weeks, and the bagel place on the corner won’t be my bagel place, and the view from the balcony won’t be my view. Instead, I’m trying to think about making a brand new home for myself—at least for the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first big move I remember was Michigan to California; as I consider this fact, I realize I only remember the arrival: Pasadena, a furnished apartment, a weird loft-area I became obsessed with, insisting any place we lived in California once we transitioned from company-loaned rental &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to have one. I cannot remember the act of packing up my first childhood bedroom; I remember a garage sale. I remember a box of Pokemon cards my brother and I commonly cite as a Big Mistake to sell (we didn’t actually have anything rare, but it’s fun to pretend a life with no debt because of Pokemon). Since then, I have moved into a dorm, I have moved into an apartment, I have moved into a psuedo-house, and into another apartment; every time, I’ve had a legion of loved ones assisting me. A friend who knows how to make the space in a suitcase count. My mother attempting to get my security deposit back with her thorough cleaning. My dad with a rented Volvo, the seats pushed down and my desk dismantled in the back, boxes of books stacked upon it. In a pandemic, I get none of this. My roommate and I absently watching episodes of Jeopardy, her wrapping the kitchenware we care about in bubblewrap as I lay on the ground using my inhaler. There is dust everywhere. In a few days, people we love will come wearing masks to relieve us of donations. We will attempt ritual, to say goodbye to a place we loved. It won’t feel right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-you-exist-too-much-by-zaina-arafat&quot;&gt;📖 You Exist Too Much by Zaina Arafat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been WAITING to recommend this. This was my last read of 2020—it was a book that had been on my radar the entire year, but hadn’t been in the mood for until 11:40PM on a night in late December, for some reason! I basically stayed up all night reading it; &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.catapult.co/products/you-exist-too-much-a-novel-by-zaina-arafat&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; is about a messy DJ-slash-MFA-student who checks herself into a rehab therapy center for love addiction. The story is framed in her past relationships, exploring the complicated ways family affects romance and romance affects family. It is so well-paced, it’s funny, it’s exciting, and emotionally devastating! Yes, I sobbed!!!!  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781948226509&quot;&gt;Get it from your favorite Indie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-stardew-valley&quot;&gt;🎮 Stardew Valley&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, okay. Technically we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/3&quot;&gt;already recommended&lt;/a&gt; Stardew Valley multiplayer, but we have not recommended &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stardewvalley.net&quot;&gt;Stardew Valley&lt;/a&gt; just by itself. So I’m allowed! I’ve been playing this game on and off for years and it always gives me so much comfort—spending day after day watering my crops, talking to the townsfolk, and looking for ores in the mines. Perfect for people who played a lot of Harvest Moon as a kid, people who bought a Switch last year to play Animal Crossing and want to branch out, and people who like cute fishing minigames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-tea-after-coffee&quot;&gt;🍽️ Tea after coffee&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a caffeine addict who had a full-blown breakdown this morning upon realizing that I wouldn’t be able to drink coffee without leaving my apartment (moving sucks!). My parents are also big coffee people—when I am home, we basically each have 2-3 cups before breakfast. It’s fun, it’s traditional, it makes my entire body shake until I crash at 2:30PM and wish I was a child with little responsibility. I’ve been declining the very generous second cup of coffee, these days, replacing it with some kind of black tea (&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.numitea.com/Chocolate-Puerh/p/NUMIS-10360&amp;amp;c=NumiTeaStore@ByType@Indulgent&quot;&gt;chocolate pu erh&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite right now). I know black tea also has a lot of caffeine, but it eases me into the afternoon better than all of that coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-media-backlog&quot;&gt;💡 Media backlog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never been good at keeping lists of movies to watch or books to read or games to play. There is so much stuff out there that I want to consume and it’s very overwhelming to have and maintain a huge list of all of that stuff. That said, a lot of my friends consistently recommend great stuff to me, and I never want to lose track of or forget about those recommendations—so I did what I do best and made myself a Notion page. Now I have a space to keep track of all the stuff I want to try, the things I’m in the middle of, and my ratings for things I’ve already finished. I’m starting slow and trying to keep it small and manageable by only add things that I actually want to, not just things I think I’m supposed to enjoy. I’m excited to see what it looks like in a few months once I’ve used it more, but for now, you can see it (and make a copy for your own Notion workspace) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so/ff069a9e791345dcb0d4a364bd9a632f&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="💡 Idea" /><summary type="html">On moving</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 53</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/53/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 53" /><published>2020-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/53</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/53/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-2020-favorites&quot;&gt;Our 2020 favorites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a year, lol. This is our last newsletter of 2020, so we took a look back at some of our favorite recommendations from the past twelve months—here are the ten things that helped us make it through this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-high-school-musical-the-musical-the-series&quot;&gt;📺 High School Musical: The Musical: The Series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-31&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/31&quot;&gt;Letter 31&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was from the second letter of the year, and although I haven’t re-watched the show since my initial viewing, it does feel representative of a lot of the joy I attempted to capture through media during the pandemic. I rewatched &lt;em&gt;Glee,&lt;/em&gt; I rewatched the HSM trilogy, I listened to musicals in the shower and while I cleaned. I think, in a normal year, I would have done these things, too, but the utter joy I felt watching HSM:TM:TS colored all of this. I am crossing my fingers for the second season to happen once TV production is safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-tangerine&quot;&gt;📱 Tangerine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/32&quot;&gt;Letter 32&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tangerine.app/&quot;&gt;this app&lt;/a&gt; all year to track my daily habits and my mood, and I still love it. Since I first mentioned it, they’ve added more journaling features, so you can write with prompts to release stress and anger, reflect on what you’re grateful for, calm your anxiety, etc. I also really like having the Tangerine widget on my home screen so I can see my progress toward completing all of my daily habits at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️theme-park-trash&quot;&gt;🎙️Theme Park Trash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/34&quot;&gt;Letter 34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I don’t really like podcasts, anymore! I’m over the audio medium! Ok, that’s not super true, but my voracious listening has definitely lessened these past few months. The podcast I am always excited for, though, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/parktrashpod?lang=en&quot;&gt;Theme Park Trash&lt;/a&gt;! Even though amusement parks should be completely dead during a global pandemic, Miya and Rosie have continued to make excellent content these past few months. They’re funny! They’re smart! They don’t act like Disney has any business firing all of those cast members and then just opening for dining! I really love this podcast, I love their minds, and I am more than happy to spend an hour or so every few weeks with two people who also probably might put HSM:TM:TS on their end of the year list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-untamed&quot;&gt;📺 The Untamed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-44&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/44/&quot;&gt;Letter 44&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/81200228&quot;&gt;this show&lt;/a&gt; back in August, I said it had fully consumed me for a month. And guess what! It’s December and it is still fully consuming me! I have watched it all the way through a second time, and now I’m starting to watch the “special edition” (whatever that means) and the various spin-off movies. It’s a whole thing. I love this story and its many adaptations with my whole heart and it is, in a way, the thing that has had the biggest impact on my year. So as much as this is a recommendation for The Untamed, it is also mostly a recommendation for finding a piece of media you can immerse yourself in and love with your entire being and share with your closest friends, because it’s such a great feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-deluge-by-leila-chatti&quot;&gt;📖 Deluge by Leila Chatti&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-44-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/44/&quot;&gt;Letter 44&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve thought about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781556595899&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; every day since I read it. I’ve had it off the shelf, as an option for a reread, too; I’ve flipped through pages, but I think I do need a little distance before I can give it the time it deserves. I love this book, it’s my favorite of 2020, and I just want everyone to read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-teleparty&quot;&gt;📱 Teleparty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-43&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/43/&quot;&gt;Letter 43&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Netflix Party has rebranded to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflixparty.com&quot;&gt;Teleparty&lt;/a&gt;, and now lets you watch TV shows and movies on Hulu, HBO, and Disney+ on top of Netflix. My friends and I have used it &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; this year, since watching TV online with your friends is the closest you can come to having a party in the middle of a pandemic. It is buggy and imperfect, but we love it very much for bringing us together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-hades&quot;&gt;🎮 Hades&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-49&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/49/&quot;&gt;Letter 49&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am only more certain than I was when I recommended this initially that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.supergiantgames.com/games/hades/&quot;&gt;this game&lt;/a&gt;, is, in fact, perfect. I will allow myself hyperbole, something I am trying to do less often, for fear of learning the people who made it were actually terrible, employees were mistreated, or something that could tarnish my pleasure. Well, nothing like that has happened yet! Instead, hearing about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-secret-to-the-success-of-bastion-pyre-and-hades-1838082618&quot;&gt;workplace practices of Supergiant&lt;/a&gt; only made it feel &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; too-good-to-be-true. I love this game, I love this game. For the monotonous day-to-day in pandemic times or not, for the depression cycle, for the anxiety of doing things; this game is a balm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-duolingo&quot;&gt;📱 Duolingo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-48&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/48/&quot;&gt;Letter 48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to report that I’ve maintained an 83-day &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; streak since I started using it earlier this year—turns out I really enjoy learning new languages, and Duo makes it really easy to get started and maintain consistent studying. (If you’re wondering: I’m still practicing French and Mandarin every day, and I’ve also started learning a tiny bit of Japanese.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-making-salted-caramel&quot;&gt;🍽️ Making salted caramel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-51&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/51/&quot;&gt;Letter 51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been craving sweets pretty much every single day…of my life? I’m exaggerating, but being sad always exasperates my desire for something indulgent. A few of my favorite places closed this year, including my favorite place to get cake. Making &lt;a href=&quot;https://sallysbakingaddiction.com/homemade-salted-caramel-recipe/&quot;&gt;this salted caramel&lt;/a&gt; was a nice way to give myself something extra; I make a lot of cookies, I use the Ghiradelli brownie mix, when I see my mom I eat knafeh—but nothing is really as tooth-chillingly, disgustingly sweet as I want it to be. Adding a glob of caramel to ice cream, to brownies, whatever? It helped! I felt happier! And it’s so easy, it’s so satisfying to make, I feel like there’s no point in trying anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-among-us&quot;&gt;🎮 Among Us&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-47&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/47/&quot;&gt;Letter 47&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/among-us/id1351168404&quot;&gt;Among Us&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favorite games I played this year, especially because it’s been a good way to connect with friends I can’t see IRL. There’s nothing better to me than a quick, silly multiplayer game where my main objective is completing tasks on a to-do list. And now you can play it on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/among-us-switch/&quot;&gt;Switch&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="🎙️ Podcast" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><summary type="html">Our 2020 favorites</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 52</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/52/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 52" /><published>2020-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/52</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/52/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-the-cold&quot;&gt;On the cold&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent this year dreading winter. Dreading the cold and the early sunsets, dreading the isolation of staying home all the time without sunny weekends to spend sitting in the park. Now that it’s here, it’s not so bad, I guess. It gets dark at 4:30, so I turn on the lamps and light a candle. My bedroom is cold, so I wear sweaters and have an extra blanket on my bed. I don’t go outside unless I need to, so I take vitamin D gummies every morning. I eat lots of soup, I put a virtual fireplace on the TV while I read, I drink hot tea in the morning (and then again in the afternoon), I play video games in bed under the covers—these are the things I do to feel cozy, which is not the same as feeling &lt;em&gt;not cold&lt;/em&gt;. I think being cold is, a little bit, part of being cozy. And I think, at this point, I’m dreading the winter a little bit less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was born in Michigan. Our house was on a big hill, perfect for sledding; I remember falling into snow and feeling so cold I was warm. I remember the weather changing, warming, getting frustrated at layers and sweaters and snowpants, just wanting to be able to feel the real temperature of everything around me. I live in California now, alternating between the bay area and Los Angeles county, meaning my spectrum of temperature is…maybe 50F—100F. I like when temperatures drop, when I can snuggle with a blanket, wearing an oversized sweater that looks best with leggings. I don’t really know what &lt;em&gt;cold cold&lt;/em&gt; feels like anymore, the last time I felt a real winter felt like a novelty (New York, Jan 2019) and snow is only something that dusts the mountaintops visible from the foothills. I am happy in my California winters. I am tired of fire season. I want to live in sweatpants and feel wind and let my hot coffee feel appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-gilmore-girls&quot;&gt;📺 Gilmore Girls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I feel a little weird recommending something that is already massively popular—especially after its 20teens resurgence thanks to Netflix, but I have been doing very little else the past few weeks besides rewatching this show as my partner watches it for the first time. &lt;em&gt;Gilmore Girls&lt;/em&gt; is, unfortunately, one of my defining traits; my relationship with it has waxed and waned across the years, going from obsessive, lonely 10 year old cycling through the seasons on DVD on an endless loop—my first “binge watch”—to cynical high schooler frustrated with whiteness, to gleeful young adult happily engaging with the nonsense of rich people and the incredible dramatic precision. I can see parts of myself mapped in this show, seeing the places I attempted to be Rory, knowing the places I am more like Lane, joyfully pretending my messiness in the kitchen is as charming as Sookie. &lt;em&gt;Gilmore Girls&lt;/em&gt; used to be between me &amp;amp; the TV, my family sitting behind me on the couch; today, it’s me &amp;amp; the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gilmoreguysshow.com/&quot;&gt;Gilmore Guys&lt;/a&gt;, me &amp;amp; my Twitter timeline, me &amp;amp; my best friends, me &amp;amp; my boyfriend. I am corny, but that’s life baby! It’s on Netflix. Go feel fall and crave coffee at 8pm!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-forest&quot;&gt;📱 Forest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to spend less time on my phone, trying to stop absentmindedly picking it up to check Twitter while I’m in the middle of doing other things. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forestapp.cc&quot;&gt;Forest&lt;/a&gt; is a very cute app that’s helping me with that, lately. You pick a length of time you want to spend off of your phone, and then the app plants a tree that starts growing as your timer counts down. If you close the app to do other things, your tree dies. A little dramatic, maybe, but it helps me make more mindful decisions about when I want to be on my phone and when I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-pen-and-the-sword-conversations-with-edward-said&quot;&gt;📖 The Pen and the Sword: Conversations with Edward Said&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Samia sent me &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haymarketbooks.org/books/888-the-pen-and-the-sword&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago and it’s probably one of the more accessible texts I’ve read that discusses Zionism, Palestinian resistance, and anti-colonial looks at the study of literature—all of that, in one tiny little book! As every good little diaspora baby does, I consistently look to Said to help articulate things I observe, things I feel. Highly recommend for anyone who has wanted to read more Said but needs something more digestible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-be&quot;&gt;🎶 BE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTS was the top artist in my Spotify Wrapped this year, even though I only started listening to them a few months ago. Nobody who knows me is surprised. Anyway, their &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/2qehskW9lYGWfYb0xPZkrS?si=699Ud167R6WgkYCsGs-IvA&quot;&gt;latest album&lt;/a&gt; has fun, chill quarantine vibes and it makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><summary type="html">On the cold</summary></entry></feed>