<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-25T20:53:59+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Letters To Summer</title><subtitle>Two friends sharing the things they're reading, watching, listening to, and enjoying. In your inbox every other Thursday.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Letter 65</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/65/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 65" /><published>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/65</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/65/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-lorde&quot;&gt;On Lorde&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I listened to &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt;, I was in the living room of my college apartment sitting on the couch with a friend who was sharing my bedroom for the summer—we squeezed so many people into that three-bedroom apartment, partners and exes and friends and crushes coming and going during the two years we lived there—and I remember having an immediate attachment to it the way I never really had with &lt;em&gt;Pure Heroine&lt;/em&gt;. Listening to The Louvre and Writer In The Dark and Supercut and Perfect Places for the first time, sitting in a room bathed in pink light, surrounded by friends in the first place that really felt like home to me since I left &lt;em&gt;home—&lt;/em&gt;I’ll probably never forget that. I’ll also probably never forget listening to those songs alone in the car at night, windows down, driving around my hometown just to do it, just because I needed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not going through a breakup when &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; came out. I remember listening to it clearly; I was in my bedroom, the lights were off, and I still used Snapchat. Everything in that album felt visceral—I was, quite literally, a &lt;em&gt;writer in the dark;&lt;/em&gt; even if my experiences were not aligned with Lorde at that moment, I felt like our emotional vibes were on the same track. As I revisit &lt;em&gt;Pure Heroine&lt;/em&gt;, it feels more like a &lt;em&gt;forever&lt;/em&gt; album than I had originally expected—there is always some part of me that will be longing for that sense of surrealness in coming-of-age, coupled with a hazy awareness that things will change, and no moment can ever be perfectly replicated; all we have are our memories, and that album. As I move into “adulthood” during a global pandemic, I’ve been listening to a lot of Lorde—partly in anticipation, partly because I want to imagine that surreal aliveness again, instead of the dulled movements 15 months in my house have produced. I’m not sure if I’m ready for what I’m predicting her next era will be, based off of “Solar Power”. I think, though, I want to be someone that not only longs for the sun, but goes to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-we-are-lady-parts&quot;&gt;📺 We Are Lady Parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This show, available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiZiJHvxJ_xAhXiVTABHSFfBT8QFjAAegQIBRAD&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.peacocktv.com%2Fstream-tv%2Fwe-are-lady-parts&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw0B0SOweTCqlzu3QRtcrEuv&quot;&gt;Peacock&lt;/a&gt;, is about a Muslim girl punk band and guess what!!!! It is as cool and fun as that description sounds!!! I watched all six episodes in a depression-haze and it helped me into a peaceful sleep. It made me cry! It made me scream (quietly, because it was 2AM)! As well as providing great camp and bright colors, the short arc of the season gives a generally balanced amount of time to each character while having a clear protagonist who carries us through. I love women!!! I need a second season, desperately, so you all have to watch it even if that means making a Peacock account!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-lilac&quot;&gt;🎶 LILAC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/01dPJcwyht77brL4JQiR8R&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is the album that will get me through this summer!!! I sent it to Summer a few weeks ago and said “i think u would like this album” and she told me she was vibing to it so hard while writing to-do lists, which is such high praise, and exactly the same energy that it gives me. Vibing while I write to-do lists, vibing while I carry a 20lb bag of cat litter home, vibing while I walk to the train to go to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-watermelon-with-feta-cheese&quot;&gt;🍽️ Watermelon with feta cheese&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hot outside!!!! It’s watermelon season!!!! Go get a watermelon and cut it up and put it in the fridge until it’s very very cold and top it with your favorite salty cheese, it doesn’t have to be feta. This is my favorite meal when I am combatting my constant dehydration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-2021-wholesome-games-direct&quot;&gt;🎮 2021 Wholesome Games Direct&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much fun as watching the Nintendo Direct and the rest of E3 is every year, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ozqhc7YXd3M&quot;&gt;Wholesome Games direct&lt;/a&gt; is really what I look forward to the most—it’s a roundup of a bunch of cute indie games (and when I say “a bunch,” I mean it. I think this year they had about 75 games.) that are available across many platforms. Some of the games I’m most looking forward to from this year’s direct are &lt;a href=&quot;https://venbagame.com/&quot;&gt;Venba&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://snacko.land/&quot;&gt;Snacko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chikon.club/&quot;&gt;Soup Pot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gardenstorygame.com/&quot;&gt;Garden Story&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ShibaPixels&quot;&gt;Yokai Inn&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KittenCupStudio&quot;&gt;Pekoe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><summary type="html">On Lorde</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 64</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/64/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 64" /><published>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/64</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/64/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-summer&quot;&gt;On summer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s June and I still don’t have an air conditioner yet, which has not been very fun. The weather has been oscillating between 80 to 90 degree humidity—days where I have to keep the windows open and a box fan so loud I can’t hear anything else pointed directly at my body at all times—and 50 to 60 degree rainy gloominess—days where I have to sit under a blanket on the couch and I can’t go outside without an umbrella. This is the in-between of spring and summer, I guess. I don’t mind the rain, because it’s cozy and it gives me a reprieve from the heat. And I don’t mind the heat, because it’s nice to spend time outside and feel the sun on my skin. I guess it would be too much to ask for something in the middle. My air conditioner gets here next week, and the temperatures will go up, and I will go the park with my friends and sweat in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK name pun out of the way, my name is actually Arabic not the season, means something even cooler, etc etc. I was looking outside around 7pm the other day and thought about how it was still light outside, maybe just getting dark. I can remember one summer evening in Michigan where I was running around my neighborhood until very late (for a small child), maybe 9:30? and it was still light out! And it was just so amazing that it was night time but the sun was still around. That agonizingly long of a day doesn’t happen in California, or maybe it does and I just do not go outside enough! I do not like hot weather, truthfully. What summer does mark for me, though, is an incredible amount of fruit I love: apricots, watermelon, figs—I wait all year for fig season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-pizza-for-dinner&quot;&gt;🍽 Pizza for dinner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen, I am SO tired every day &amp;amp; there’s a constant barrage of poison gurgling around in my brain because of my Twitter addiction or the World Events making me feel inhuman &amp;amp; sometimes! nothing sounds appetizing except pizza. There have been a few times the past two weeks or so where I just ordered a pizza instead of looking in the fridge and it increased my mood significantly; listen, pizza isn’t even my main comfort food. But I guess we’re all different after over a year of being inside! Everyone should order a pizza in my honor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-madoka-magica&quot;&gt;📺 Madoka Magica&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched Madoka Magica for the first time while I was recovering from my second dose of Moderna and uh. Wow! It’s probably one of the coolest shows I’ve ever seen—the story is absolutely devastating and twists the magical girl genre in a dark, satisfying way. And the art style is just really really neat. It’s only 12 episodes, so watch it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hulu.com/series/puella-magi-madoka-magica-085f5007-1b32-4dd7-9aea-41397554fb9b&quot;&gt;Hulu&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend if you want to cry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-nazar&quot;&gt;✉️ NAZAR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nazar.substack.com/&quot;&gt;This newsletter&lt;/a&gt; by Vanessa Taylor covers surveillance, often specifically how it affects Black Muslim communities. It was on break for a little bit but is officially back! I’ve learned a lot—tech writing through the lens of the harm of surveillance is the main angle I am interested in, and this newsletter encompasses a broad scope under that lens. Start with &lt;a href=&quot;https://nazar.substack.com/p/muslim-abolitionists-on-islam-carceral&quot;&gt;this letter&lt;/a&gt; with testimonies from Muslim Abolitionists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-mario-kart&quot;&gt;🎮 Mario Kart&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been playing a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.googleadservices.com/pagead/aclk?sa=L&amp;amp;ai=CW-B9Ylq5YK7DKcH5mgST04KoCN2F4-lhrMqJi88N1IHWnuYICAAQAiC5VCgCYMnGqYvApNgPoAG9ucXqAsgBAcgD2CCqBEBP0LyEqDI-H2rl6d4hlE8bhp-q6mojMjnDCTAZhYmYn-cBPA_zwM0_mvIkfR1VBTlQZhAdqRnifrkvWTifQIniwATF2ci3jAOABZBOoAZmgAe0wui4AYgHAZAHAagHpr4bqAe5mrECqAfw2RuoB_LZG6gH89EbqAfu0huoB_-csQKoB8rcG7AIAdIIBRACIIQBmglBaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmludGVuZG8uY29tL2dhbWVzL2RldGFpbC9tYXJpby1rYXJ0LTgtZGVsdXhlLXN3aXRjaC-xCe4IjsiQg_lUuQmbACiq2dLWUPgJAZgLAaoMAggBuAwByBT39e-f8dHN4GjQFQGYFgH4FgGAFwGSFwYSBAgBEAM&amp;amp;ae=2&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiF2qSbxPzwAhU4RTABHRgRB4kQ0Qx6BAgDEAE&amp;amp;dct=1&amp;amp;dblrd=1&amp;amp;sival=AF15MECJOrM50ynXUMgIgOu3gGi81GOtww9XSnoJiqarhT80LyrklxI7xZu8v4GaOZV3F9By_ISMDkOBd9imoWJE5ygSx_BV1N8-gKBbgbUhXjUyOmzR0o0xt6tdf6_j_58DtbRkMYrAFOsnQ_fM7l8TfwYMkvvV38CxrmgnhhZPVZS3Pf6GdLU&amp;amp;sig=AOD64_0q4sFLeqvUqP3YQKHRV0u5mPQnPA&amp;amp;adurl=https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/mario-kart-8-deluxe-switch/%3Fcid%3DA1002-01:ch%3Dpdpd&quot;&gt;Mario Kart&lt;/a&gt; online with my friends lately and it is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; fun!!! I’ve always loved Mario Kart, but I’m particularly enjoying its resurgence in my life right now. So if you’re looking for fun, kinda low effort ways to hang out with friends for an evening, set up an online multiplayer game and go wild. Our favorite, most chaotic match is 200cc on the Baby Park course with shells only. It makes me feel like I’m driving four cars at once and they’re all on fire, and it’s great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><summary type="html">On summer</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 63</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/63/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 63" /><published>2021-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/63</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/63/">&lt;p&gt;Hi, friends. We’re forgoing our regular recommendation format. What follows, instead, is a list of actions for supporting the continued resistance of Palestinians against the colonial body of Israel. This list is not original nor comprehensive, but it is what I have learned from Palestinians currently living under occupation, from organizers in the US, from family. Palestinians have been experiencing genocide for 73 years. In the past two weeks, the global conversation has shifted towards that recognition. Do not stand for Zionist rhetoric that seeks to dehumanize Palestinians or delegitimize our resistance. Do not stand for distractions that de-center the fight for a liberated Palestine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Continue to share footage and the stories from Palestinians on the ground. N.A. Mansour has compiled an incredibly useful &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nadooshfattoosh/status/1393150775090720769&quot;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter. I have been following &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/m7mdkurd&quot;&gt;Mohammed el-Kurd&lt;/a&gt; the closest.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bdsmovement.net/&quot;&gt;Boycott, Divestment, Sanctions&lt;/a&gt; is a Palestinian-led movement for freedom, justice and equality. BDS upholds the simple principle that Palestinians are entitled to the same rights as the rest of humanity. Are you a student? Join or start a divestment campaign for your university. Organize your workplace to adopt BDS. Artists, do not perform in Israel. Do not buy Sabra hummus or from the other companies listed; there are others that invest in Israel (L’Oreal or Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s, for example), but the campaign has a focus. There are ALWAYS alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many governments globally are invested in arms aid to Israel; e-mail &amp;amp; call your representatives to stop investing your taxes in this violence; if you’re American, &lt;a href=&quot;https://uscpr.org/militaryfunding&quot;&gt;you can use this tool&lt;/a&gt; to see how much aid your district sends each year. The answer may surprise you. Tell your reps to support &lt;a href=&quot;https://jewishcurrents.org/aoc-to-introduce-resolution-blocking-bomb-sale-to-israel/&quot;&gt;AOC’s resolution to block the current gigantic arms bill proposed&lt;/a&gt;; use &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.everyaction.com/1bUDFJrq_kWz5sjKEeyoPQ2&quot;&gt;this template&lt;/a&gt; to tell your reps to support bill H.R. 2590, stating that the US will not fund the Israeli government’s imprisonment and torture of Palestinian children. (all Palestinians, though, regardless of gender &amp;amp; age, deserve to live.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Donations will not free Palestine but we can provide relief to the living. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ayaghanameh/status/1394351170576175104&quot;&gt;Aya Ghanameh is raising money&lt;/a&gt; for a couple in Gaza hoping to build a home. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/ebe8da-help-support-a-family-in-gaza?utm_campaign=p_cp_display&amp;amp;utm_medium=copy_link&amp;amp;utm_source=customer&quot;&gt;Help support another family in Gaza here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pcrf1.z2systems.com/np/clients/pcrf1/donation.jsp?campaign=1680&quot;&gt;The Palestine Children’s Relief Fund&lt;/a&gt; is an American organization whose office in Gaza was recently destroyed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://palestinianyouthmovement.com/&quot;&gt;Palestinian Youth Movement&lt;/a&gt; is an international, grassroots movement made up of Palestinians across the diaspora fighting for a free Palestine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://decolonizepalestine.com/&quot;&gt;Decolonize Palestine&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent resource created by Palestinians to help people learn more about our history. It debunks myths and provides extensive, accessible explanations on what the colonial power would beg you to think is “complicated”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Palestinian. I am American born. I am lucky to be here. When I told my father what was happening in Sheikh Jarrah, he said, “that could have been us.” We wonder when our ancestral home will be razed in the name of “archeology,” of “history.” Noura Erakat tweeted this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It’s not just being part of a Palestinian nation that drives me, but the guilt of sheer fortune that I was born in the US and not in Gaza or Sheikh Jarrah where Israel could massacre and displace my family while the world looks on and insists we condemn ourselves 4 being targets.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Noura Erakat (@4noura) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/4noura/status/1393229229211459588?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so here I am: overcome by grief and guilt. But still, I cannot help but feel hope. I know the ones I love are resisting the colonial body that seeks to destroy them. International solidarity is imperative to that resistance. I hope you will join me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;❤️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="💡 Idea" /><summary type="html">Hi, friends. We’re forgoing our regular recommendation format. What follows, instead, is a list of actions for supporting the continued resistance of Palestinians against the colonial body of Israel. This list is not original nor comprehensive, but it is what I have learned from Palestinians currently living under occupation, from organizers in the US, from family. Palestinians have been experiencing genocide for 73 years. In the past two weeks, the global conversation has shifted towards that recognition. Do not stand for Zionist rhetoric that seeks to dehumanize Palestinians or delegitimize our resistance. Do not stand for distractions that de-center the fight for a liberated Palestine.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 62</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/62/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 62" /><published>2021-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/62</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/62/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-soup&quot;&gt;On soup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer and I talk about soup a lot, like maybe an unnatural amount? We both just love soup very much. It’s a superior meal! I have been ordering the same wonton noodle soup from this place in my neighborhood on a near-weekly basis lately—including the day after I got my second dose of the vaccine, while I was laying on my couch feeling miserable all day. It always makes me feel better. There’s something beyond comforting to me about a whole meal that is just a big bowl of warm broth with some noodles or whatever in it. It’s my favorite genre of food and I will always find solace in it, full stop. Thank you for listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I eat soup at least once a week. I really like making broth, handling whole spices and the way it smells is basically my substitute for a candle. I love the fullness that comes from eating a really big bowl of soup; I’ve struggled with various degrees of eating disorders a lot of my life and so the cheat of broth was something that helped me during really tough periods. I think there are a lot of foods I feel sort of repelled by because of the way I held them in difficult periods—soup, luckily, will always be good! Sometimes it’s just a bowl of very good garlicy broth with bread ripped into it. Sometimes it’s something blended and herby and also there’s bread, too. Sometimes it’s shishbarak and it’s my birthday and yogurt-mint-garlic is the best thing I’ve ever tasted. All soup is good soup and I will never accept slander!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-umang-kalras-everybodys-girlfriend&quot;&gt;📖 Umang Kalra’s &lt;em&gt;everybody’s girlfriend&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love zines! I bought all of the ones &lt;a href=&quot;https://gumroad.com/umangkalra&quot;&gt;Umang Kalra has up on gumroad a month&lt;/a&gt; or so ago and finally was able to spend time with them; the poems in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gumroad.com/umangkalra#hSTx&quot;&gt;everybody’s girlfriend&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; in particular, are spectacular—Kalra writes with a graceful bluntness. Along with the gorgeous collage-backdrops, these poems are super easy to get sucked into—if you’re having trouble reading lately (I am!!!!), the short-but-impactful vibes are a really good solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cozy-grove&quot;&gt;🎮 Cozy Grove&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been trying to get back into the habit of waking up a bit earlier and playing video games before work, or sitting on the couch to play games while I eat lunch instead of sitting at my desk all desk, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cozygrovegame.com&quot;&gt;Cozy Grove&lt;/a&gt; is a really good game for that. It’s a very sweet game with nice calming music, and I’ve really enjoyed playing it so far. If you like video games that are basically just fun little to-do lists, or if you’re looking for something you can play for approximately 30 minutes a day (and no more! because the game will literally only give you so many things to do in a day, which I think is pretty cool!), I recommend checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-tommye-blounts-what-are-we-not-for&quot;&gt;📖 Tommye Blount’s &lt;em&gt;What Are We Not For?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: I’m having trouble reading! Also me: recommends two books in the same letter! Okay, so I’ve had this really sad stack growing and growing on my nightstand for the past few months and was able to make the smallest dent in it a few days ago with &lt;a href=&quot;https://bullcitypress.com/product/what-are-we-not-for/&quot;&gt;this chapbook&lt;/a&gt;. It’s fucking gorgeous. I was literally open-mouthed the entire time; it felt like these poems were simply too striking to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; break my brain fog. It’s short, like chapbooks are, so that, too, can always help when you’re in a reading slump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-scorecard&quot;&gt;📱 Scorecard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a bit of shameless self-promo, but my company launched a new app this week! And I’m very proud of it! We’ve been working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getscorecard.app&quot;&gt;Scorecard&lt;/a&gt; for a while, and it’s really nice to see it out in the world finally—I hope people like it. Basically: it’s an app for keeping score while you play games with your friends. It’s colorful and it’s fun and it’s easy to use. If you give it a try, please let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><summary type="html">On soup</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 61</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/61/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 61" /><published>2021-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/61</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/61/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-digital-communication&quot;&gt;On digital communication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve met most of my best friends on Tumblr and Twitter, so I’ve always been really comfortable communicating and building relationships online. I have a lot of feelings about the way I navigate social media based on the 10+ years I’ve been doing it, I guess, and with that comes a lot of feelings about how I communicate with friends both privately and publicly—in DMs, in tweets, in group chats, in Discord servers, in text messages, and IRL. I think there’s a time and place for each of these, and it’s not even something that I can articulate very well, just something that feels instinctual to me. (A side effect of having so many communication channels: sometimes I find myself having three different conversations with a friend at the same time via three different apps.) Lately, I’ve been leaning into private, one-on-one conversations a little bit more—Summer took a small break from Twitter, so suddenly I had an excuse to spend all day texting her little updates about my life; and I met a friend to drink boba in the park over the weekend so we could catch up in person. Both felt really nice and really natural. There are so many ways to stay connected with people you care about online, and the thing is it doesn’t really matter how you do it as long as you…do it. I think that’s the point I wanted to make, who knows. Text your friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’m afraid I’m more charismatic online than I am in person. I have a lot of social anxiety, manifesting in both ends of the spectrum: I am kind of weird, quiet, hiding behind people I know, or I am overly energetic and obnoxious and feel like death when I am alone again. I’m embarrassed by what comes out of my mouth even if there is no reason to be. It is not that I am more cautious or filtered when I communicate through text, but something about my tone feels more confident. I barely know the voices of some of the people I trust the most in the world, because our communication has been always online. I’ve seen a slow reconsideration of friendships forged on the internet in the last few years and I think the pandemic has only reinforced how strong digital communication has the potential to be, if only you put work and effort into the relationships (like literally any relationship lol) formed through it. I love when my friends text me out of the blue and I love when people check up on me, I love stupid e-mails and IG DMs and anything people do to keep up and keep in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-how-drivers-license-by-olivia-rodrigo-captures-suburban-sadness-from-flash-thrive&quot;&gt;🔗 how DRIVERS LICENSE by OLIVIA RODRIGO captures suburban sadness from Flash Thrive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok so I hadn’t actually heard &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZmDBbnmKpqQ&quot;&gt;this song&lt;/a&gt; before I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4MiF-xxt-Q0&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; essay and I only connected the dots that the Olivia Rodrigo people keep talking about is the girl in &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/31&quot;&gt;High School Musical: The Musical: The Series&lt;/a&gt; like a week ago, and YET! This analysis made me cry? It probably has something to do with the fact that I’m back in the suburbs in my childhood home and cannot even drive, but anyway. Rosie’s video essays are the absolute best—if you care about Coming of Age 2010s aesthetics and where that all comes from, I highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-uncanny-counter&quot;&gt;📺 The Uncanny Counter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I am the kind of person who feels way too many feelings and loses her mind at every TV show. So, full disclosure, I basically recommend every TV show I’ve ever watched. And if I don’t, it’s because Summer already recommended it and that’s why I decided to watch it. All this to say: I recently finished the first season of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjq1qiQ9ZLwAhV4MlkFHe2qC4UQFjAKegQIAhAD&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.netflix.com%2Ftitle%2F81323551&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3aaBmQdFFqYVtEhPvjpbZE&quot;&gt;The Uncanny Counter&lt;/a&gt; and it made me cry on several occasions and I love all of the characters and their amazing fits with my whole heart. My elevator pitch is that it’s like if the Grim Reaper was a very adorable high school boy with a found family and lots of good turtleneck/jacket combos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-muppets-2011&quot;&gt;🎥 The Muppets (2011)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I asked my TL what is a movie that feels like &lt;em&gt;Mamma Mia!,&lt;/em&gt; because I was sad and wanted that level of comfort but felt like watching something new. My friend Nico suggested &lt;em&gt;The Muppets&lt;/em&gt; and it honestly was a top 5 decision of 2021. It’s silly and sweet and the music is great, a truly All Ages type of movie that does not condescend or resort to cheap humor. I cried? which is fine and normal, I don’t think there’s ever been a movie I didn’t cry at, but wow! It’s on Netflix, please go have fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-star-projectors&quot;&gt;🔗 Star projectors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got this a projector recently as part of my quest to make my bedroom as cozy as possible and it’s my new favorite thing. Every night, I turn it + a pink lamp on and light a candle in my bedroom, and it has become a 10000x more fun and relaxing space. I didn’t do a ton of research, so there may be other star projectors out there that are better for you, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/slredirect/picassoRedirect.html/ref=pa_sp_atf_aps_sr_pg1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;adId=A009563818FGV3586F8DY&amp;amp;url=%2FBlissLights-Sky-Lite-Projector-Ambiance%2Fdp%2FB07L8R5PK6%2Fref%3Dsr_1_2_sspa%3Fdchild%3D1%26keywords%3Dstar%2Bprojector%26qid%3D1619131053%26sr%3D8-2-spons%26psc%3D1&amp;amp;qualifier=1619131053&amp;amp;id=1180205478372372&amp;amp;widgetName=sp_atf&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is the one I got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎥 Movie" /><summary type="html">On digital communication</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 60</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/60/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 60" /><published>2021-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/60</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/60/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-astrology&quot;&gt;On astrology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school, I remember borrowing a friend’s astrology book and staying up late to flip through it, trying to piece together my birth chart and what it all meant. Now I am intimately familiar with my birth chart—and my friends’ birth charts, thanks to Co-star—and follow astrology meme accounts on Instagram. If you ask me if I “believe” in astrology, I think you’re kind of missing the point. I don’t care if the position of the planets actually has any “real” affect on my life. I like astrology as a tool for thinking about my actions and who I am, for recognizing patterns in my life and the world around me, for learning how to make sense of things, for relating to people who also have Virgo in their charts, etc. It’s fun, and sometimes comforting, to read my horoscope or keep track of which planets are in retrograde or compare birth charts with friends. Reading that astrology book in high school felt like a big awakening for me—not just because I finally knew what it meant to have a Scorpio sun, but because I found a new way to look at things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started thinking more deeply about astrology when I was in high school, early college; I had friends (like Jillian) who Knew Their Shit and started talking about things I had never known about—moon signs, rising signs, how different placements affect the body. For someone who had always felt like there was something kind of &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; with their body, with their brain, it was comforting to point cosmologically to how I was feeling. It felt less like explanation and more like seeking precedence, more like an analytical tool to find the truth—not so much &lt;em&gt;blame it on the planets,&lt;/em&gt; rather, &lt;em&gt;use the planets to figure out where exactly the core of this is coming from.&lt;/em&gt; I never ended up digging as deep as other people I love did, nor did I ever familiarize myself with the full meaning of it all, but it’s something patiently, presently there at the back of my head. I like the reminders to check in with myself if there is a pisces moon, or letting mercury in retrograde remind me bad/frustrating things are not always within my control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-salat-by-dujie-tahat&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;Salat&lt;/em&gt; by Dujie Tahat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love chapbooks that use their space &amp;amp; form so well, chaps that feel like they &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; exist in this form: Dujie Tahat’s &lt;em&gt;Salat&lt;/em&gt; is just that. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dujietahat.com/bio/&quot;&gt;Dujie’s&lt;/a&gt; writing is absolutely stunning—the book takes on the form of prayer, and each poem echoes that meditation so well. I read it cover to cover twice through as soon as I got it and have been thinking about it every week since. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tupelopress.org/product/salat/&quot;&gt;You can buy it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cherry-blossom-trees&quot;&gt;💡 Cherry blossom trees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to the Brooklyn Botanical Garden yesterday to see the cherry blossom and magnolia trees beginning to bloom and it put me in the best mood!!! Please, if you live somewhere that has pretty blooming trees right now, take some time to just go outside and admire them for a while. Take a bunch of pictures. Post them so other people can feel the good vibes. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-rilo-kiley-1999&quot;&gt;🎶 Rilo Kiley 1999&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommended the Rilo Kiley album &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/23&quot;&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; a while back. Their music has been in my regular rotation since that newsletter, basically, but this past week I let them be my main on-shuffle artist and found myself particularly drawn to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7bYq6huhr7JsnkoPExW1Xz?si=rst-Mc0rT-m0pxxOtxsAlw&quot;&gt;self-titled, first album&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not great at writing about music but there is something about Jenny Lewis’s voice that just makes me feel in-tune with myself, even if who I am at the current moment is pretty insufferable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-sandalwood-incense&quot;&gt;🖇️ Sandalwood incense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://grandteaimports.com&quot;&gt;Grand Tea Imports&lt;/a&gt; has really good tea, and maybe I’ll recommend some of that another time, but I also really like their &lt;a href=&quot;https://grandteaimports.com/products/extra-thin-no-smoke-sandalwood-incense&quot;&gt;sandalwood incense&lt;/a&gt;. Whenever I want some really cozy vibes, I light a stick of this in my living room and it completely resets my brain—it’s a signal that it’s time to relax for a second. Smells great, doesn’t fill the room with smoke, supports a small local business, 10/10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="💡 Idea" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><summary type="html">On astrology</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 59</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/59/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 59" /><published>2021-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/59</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/59/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-breakfast&quot;&gt;On breakfast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not good at eating breakfast, most days. Like, I love eggs and bagels and bacon and toast and all that—I do! But I also love to sleep in late and then rush to start my day, and there is usually not enough time for breakfast in that routine. When I was still working on an office every day, I got into the habit of eating a Clif bar from the office snack stash every day while I made my tea in the morning. Once I started working from home because of the pandemic, I was on my own. Eventually I started buying Clif bars for myself, because even though I am bad at breakfast, I still need to eat something in the morning if I want to make it through the day. Yes, I could wake up earlier and learn how to slow down and enjoy some scrambled eggs first thing in the morning if I really tried. That sounds like it would be nice. For now, though, the best I can do most days is a protein bar with chocolate chips in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not hungry when I wake up. I work better if I’m fed. These are two truths that often conflicted back in the days of going to a physical place that is not my bedroom to complete my job. I used to wake up, drink coffee, make more coffee, run to work, and crash very soon after, running only on caffeine and the anxiety of going from one place to the next before my hunger kicked in. Although breakfast is, allegedly, “the most important meal of the day” (this feels like some sort of American capitalist propaganda, idk man), it really always felt like something special rather than necessary. When I think of breakfast, I think of plans with friends—the effort and care put into waking up, giving ourselves time and space between this act and doing anything else, and then coming together to eat incredibly heavy, ridiculous amounts of food. I think of my family; Palestinian breakfasts are large, spanning many different plates—I do not like eggs but I will eat them on my mother’s breakfast table, alongside pickled turnips and labneh and fresh bread and olives and all of the other things people will make fun of me for writing poems about. Having breakfast means I am giving myself time and care and space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-reading-sucks&quot;&gt;✉️ Reading Sucks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ellomelissa.substack.com/&quot;&gt;Melissa Lozada-Oliva’s newsletter&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favorite things. I “love reading” and based on this newsletter it can seem like I am an “avid” or “consistent” reader. While I can meet my pseudo-goals, I still carry a lot of guilt with reading, especially against the other ways I spend my time. Sometimes, I think, what could I have accomplished if instead of banking 50 hours on Ace Attorney in two weeks, I did 50 hours of reading? But this line of thinking simply is not productive. I worry about reading many books at once, or the time it takes me to finish something—this keeps me from reading long books—but reading Melissa’s newsletter has been really comforting for feeling kinship with someone who also is always trying, but actively acknowledging sometimes we do other things, sometimes our brains get in the way, and sometimes the world simply does not give us the space and attention for reading. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ellomelissa.substack.com/subscribe?utm_source=menu&amp;amp;simple=true&amp;amp;next=https%3A%2F%2Fellomelissa.substack.com%2F&quot;&gt;You can subscribe here,&lt;/a&gt; and check out the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://ellomelissa.substack.com/p/what-i-read-this-week-0f1&quot;&gt;recent one with an interview with one of my faves, Hannah Rego&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-stickers&quot;&gt;🔗 Stickers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked about &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/56/&quot;&gt;using a planner&lt;/a&gt; in this newsletter before, but I just recently started putting stickers in my planner every day to pretend I am one of those cute studygram accounts with adorable bullet journal spreads and it has brought me a lot of joy. I got a bunch of stickers from &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/56/&quot;&gt;Kawaii Pen Shop&lt;/a&gt; recently, and I also get some from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/punimelt/posts&quot;&gt;Punimelt’s Patreon&lt;/a&gt; every month, which I love and endorse very much. Get some stickers! Actually use them! Put them all over your stuff! It will make you happy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-ergonomic-grip-for-switch&quot;&gt;🎮 Ergonomic Grip for Switch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I have pain literally everywhere, but I won’t let it stop me from gaming for six hours. There are games I like playing handheld more than docked, and so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.satisfye.com/products/zengrip-pro&quot;&gt;this ergonomic grip&lt;/a&gt; for my Switch has been really helpful; there are a lot of different options, though, so shop around for what suits you. Just know it exists and your hands will love you for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-magic-spoon-cereal&quot;&gt;🍽️ Magic Spoon cereal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually kind of hate myself for recommending trendy, DTC cereal, but since we’re on the topic of breakfast I gotta say that I have been eating and enjoying &lt;a href=&quot;https://magicspoon.com&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; lately. I really like the cookies and cream flavor, and I really like that it has a lot of protein in it because I need that if I want to get through the day without feeling like death. This is pretty good stuff to have around for breakfast—or days when you really truly do not have the energy to make an actual meal for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><summary type="html">On breakfast</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 58</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/58/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 58" /><published>2021-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/58</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/58/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-self-care&quot;&gt;On self care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be dramatic but sometimes existing in this world is hard. Like, the idea of getting out of bed and sitting at my desk for several hours a day, or cooking a meal for myself and then washing all the dishes, or even just taking a shower and washing my face—sometimes it’s just too much. Sometimes it feels like the best I can do is lay on the couch in yesterday’s t-shirt and eat a bowl of cereal and play video games. And that’s cool! I am trying to be a lot more forgiving with myself on those days. But I am also trying to take better care of myself, to at least do the bare minimum. Yes, sure, sheet masks and bubble baths are self care. But so is brushing your teeth and taking a big gulp of water on the hard days. So is cleaning off a tiny area of your desk so you feel a little less stressed while you’re working. (And so is knowing when to stop pushing yourself and just lay down on the couch for a little bit.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while I thought I “wasn’t into skincare,” because so much of what I saw online was about glamorous ritual and this indulgence into complicated process. It was also largely focused on the face. As conversations around the capitalism-poisoned term “self care” grew more prevalent in the spaces I frequented, I realized of course, I was “into skincare”—because I have to be! I have eczema! In fact, I am deeply into taking care and managing the health of my skin, otherwise I’m covered in cuts from dry skin cracking! It took literally re-arranging the phrase—instead of self care, it’s &lt;em&gt;taking care of yourself—&lt;/em&gt;for me to realize self care isn’t a trendy thing I’m behind on. Allowing this to be an act instead of a concept helped me think about the things I actually need to do in order to regulate my health, thinking about how to continually fold them into my routine: drinking water, sleeping early, flossing—normal things that are very hard when you’re depressed. The extra, the sometimes superfluous—an extra special meal, staying in bed longer than normal—these things can be folded into taking care of myself, too, but I can’t ignore the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-soft-scrambled-eggs&quot;&gt;🍽️ Soft scrambled eggs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never liked eggs growing up. My parents would try a myriad of ways of trying to get me to eat them since they’re “good for you,” but I refused unless very specific circumstances were met (I wanted to play video games with my brother while eating). When I started college, eggs were an easy source of protein and very easy to bulk up sad leftovers—you know when there’s like, half a serving left of basically any meal? Add an egg! It’s great. But my favorite way to eat them are creamy, soft-scrambled on really crusty bread, spinach, and some soft cheese spread—season with salt, pepper, and chili flakes. I had this for breakfast the other day and just remembered, yes! This is the best thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-homemade-iced-chai&quot;&gt;🍽️ Homemade iced chai&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love iced chais—the venti ones at Starbucks singlehandedly got me through college. Now, though, they’re a pretty rare treat for me since I don’t go to coffee shops all that often. But! Last week I picked up a container of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tazo.com/us/en/products/lattes-iced/classic-chai-latte.html&quot;&gt;Tazo’s chai concentrate&lt;/a&gt; at the grocery store and used it to make a pretty yummy iced chai with oat milk at home. I think it’s going to be my new Friday morning treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-samias-the-baby&quot;&gt;🎶 Samia’s The Baby&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first heard Samia in 2018 or 2019 when she had just a handful of songs on Spotify; she came up on some indie sad girl playlist and I loved the absolute crazy intensity of her voice, but she wasn’t on my regular rotation until 2020. Her semi-recently released &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7faAwJDTt9Y8kVAcSHy9Y6&quot;&gt;The Baby&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; along with the cover-album &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7MGuErisn7eWnGriy2iGbZ&quot;&gt;The Baby Reimagined&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are equally excellent and a very good, vibe-y time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-dram&quot;&gt;🍽️ Dram&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another beverage! I tried this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dramapothecary.com&quot;&gt;“herbal sparkling water”&lt;/a&gt; on a whim the other day and liked it a lot—I got the cardamom &amp;amp; black tea flavor, which is a pretty weird (but delicious) flavor for sparkling water. Turns out they have some other cool-sounding flavors, plus a CBD version, which I really want to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><summary type="html">On self care</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 57</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/57/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 57" /><published>2021-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/57</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/57/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-changing-seasons&quot;&gt;On changing seasons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I played Animal Crossing today, the snow had finally melted to reveal grayish-green grass, a sign that spring is coming to my little video game island. In real life, too, the snow has mostly melted away. This week has been warmer and sunnier—I can go outside without having to shove my hands inside my pockets. I’m hungry for warm weather, for shorts and sweatshirt weather, for walks-in-the-park weather. I think we’re almost on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been GOING OUTSIDE lately. Since I live in Southern California, it has less to do with the temperature being bearable and more to do with how long it’s bright out. I have been trying to take meetings outside. Yesterday, after work, I painted in the sun at 5PM. I was so happy to still have some daylight after work. I forgot how much winter affects me, especially with a specific work schedule—I am not someone who prioritizes doing things like “getting Vitamin D,” but the season change is so, so welcome because it means I have more opportunities to do the basic, healthy thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-tonys-chocolonely&quot;&gt;🍽️ Tony’s Chocolonely&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is my first memory of eating &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonyschocolonely.com/us/en&quot;&gt;this chocolate&lt;/a&gt;: early in the pandemic, my partner put a giant chocolate bar into our grocery cart and said he had tried it before, and it was good. I was like, ok, I love chocolate, let’s go. And it was the best chocolate I’d ever had! We realized they carried it at the market near my apartment, too, it became a snacky staple. This is honestly my favorite chocolate, I will eat a whole bar throughout the course of the day and only feel a little gross. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonyschocolonely.com/us/en/chocoshop/product/milk-caramel-sea-salt-32-1&quot;&gt;mix-ins are absolutely spectacular&lt;/a&gt;. The chocolate is also ethically sourced! Highly recommend for something sweet to look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-ikenfell&quot;&gt;🎮 Ikenfell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humblegames.com/games/ikenfell/&quot;&gt;this game&lt;/a&gt; last year and never finished playing it because I got distracted by other things—but I picked it back up a couple of weeks ago and I’ve really been loving it. It’s a cute, magical indie RPG with a great soundtrack and lots of queer characters, and there’s really nothing not to like about that as far as I’m concerned. It’s also really forgiving to players who want to make the battles a little easier (or just skip them altogether in favor of experiencing the story) which I always love to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-ace-attorney-trilogy&quot;&gt;🎮 Ace Attorney Trilogy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These games are old and thus have been on my radar for years. I have friends who love them dearly and because of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/phoenix-wright-ace-attorney-trilogy-switch/&quot;&gt;eShop sale&lt;/a&gt; at the beginning of this year, I have joined them! These games are so campy! The writing is so silly! I love to have fun. They fully engrossed me in the 40ish hours it takes to play through the games available for Switch—I finished everything maybe in the second week of January and I haven’t been able to stop thinking about them! I’m begging Capcom to put the rest of the games on Switch, but you can play literally any of them on your phone, your computer, your PlayStation, your 3ds. Anything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-lofi-video-game-music&quot;&gt;🎶 Lofi video game music&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days I’m pretty much incapable of getting any work done if I’m not listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wofB1wzyYYI&amp;amp;t=1193s&quot;&gt;Genshin Impact Lofi ✨ 1 Hour Lofi Hip Hop&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube, or something similar. Video game soundtracks are just good! I like to have them on in the background all the time! I also really like &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/0L8SKsIJlQ4TDEJ86clycU?si=spNBbqrFS7esq16qXWBVtw&quot;&gt;this Spotify playlist&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8flvMNTM7NE&quot;&gt;this YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><summary type="html">On changing seasons</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 56</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/56/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 56" /><published>2021-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/56</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/56/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-starting-over&quot;&gt;On starting over&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just moved into a new apartment a little over a week ago, which is always a weird and exciting and stressful experience. I’m in a new neighborhood, living on my own for the first time in my life, moving all the furniture around to see what feels right. Starting over is fun, but it’s also a little bit scary—so I find comfort in the things in my life that have &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; changed. Things like blankets and plants and cups of pens that I brought over from my last place. Things like video games that I feel like I could play forever (I just started playing Fire Emblem: Three Houses again). Things like TV shows and movies that I’ve already seen a billion times and love to rewatch. That’s a different kind of starting over, one that never changes and keeps me feeling steady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of unfinished notebooks. Some of them are for specific uses: a notebook to practice my Arabic in, a notebook to write recipes in, a notebook for my work-to-dos. I have a poetry notebook, an essays notebook that’s sometimes a poetry notebook but also sometimes a personal to-do list, a notebook to write about the books I read—on &amp;amp; on &amp;amp; on. I want to just &lt;em&gt;finish them&lt;/em&gt; so I can buy another &amp;amp; start fresh. I love the possibilities of a new notebook but treat them far too preciously. I struggle with clean-slates, with starting over; this manifests so minorly in my Animal Crossing House, my rooms haphazardly built throughout the months with furniture I had at the time &amp;amp; struggle to switch out, building instead of shaping. I want to! I want my brain to be clean, smooth, to build itself back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-limits-of-the-lunchbox-moment-by-jaya-saxena&quot;&gt;🔗 The Limits of the Lunchbox Moment by Jaya Saxena&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food writing is one of my favorite genres, but there’s often been a disconnect for me when I read the stories other children if immigrants write—specifically, the focus on the “lunchbox moment” in which a child of color is mocked for bringing their traditional food to school. There are an overwhelming number of factors that contribute to this being unrelatable to me, but I often felt frustrated by the lack of alternative stories in how food, especially at a young age, factors into racism and marginalization (as well as ignoring broader issues such as access and colonialism). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eater.com/22239499/lunchbox-moment-pop-culture-tropes&quot;&gt;This piece&lt;/a&gt; unpacks the “lunchbox moment” so, so well, featuring an array of conversations with people of color talking about their relationship to the “moment,” food, and what their experiences genuinely looked like. The writer does something remarkable, as well, and talks about a piece she’d written in the past, examining where her claims had come from; did she simply forget something she had written about, or were the events manufactured, based on broader pressures in the industry? It’s a great piece of food writing, but also so productive for the more institutional ramifications of shallow identity politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-hobonichi-planner&quot;&gt;🔗 Hobonichi planner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been good at using planners, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2021/pc/detail_cover/cb21_jan/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; was an impulse buy last year when I started working from home and I’ve loved it ever since. I don’t know if it makes me more productive or more organized than before, but I really enjoy taking the time to fill out my schedule every week, and I do think it’s helpful to keep open in front of me while I work so I can jot down notes to myself and things I need to do. JetPens has a helpful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/guide-to-the-hobonichi-techo-planner/pt/900&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; to the Hobonichi lineup that can help you choose one that suits your needs—I like the A5 Cousin because of the big daily pages, personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-lolita-podcast&quot;&gt;🎙️ Lolita Podcast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recommended Jamie Loftus’s work a few times on this newsletter—she is simply my favorite comedian—but &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/4dvc06zTAaAylzdTrsgKzp&quot;&gt;this podcast&lt;/a&gt; is a little different; in it, she explores the cultural legacy of Nabokov’s &lt;em&gt;Lolita&lt;/em&gt; through the (awful) film adaptations, the fashion culture, the way references appear (poorly) in the zeitgeist, in music; it’s an impeccable piece of scholarship and journalism. In my years as an English Major™, I don’t think I ever encountered a research question approached with such thorough care. I learned SO MUCH, leaving the series equal levels grateful &amp;amp; horrified. BIG MAJOR TRIGGER WARNINGS for discussions of child sexual assault, pedophilia, and rape. I had to listen to each episode in pieces, so make sure you take your time. Find it wherever you listen to podcasts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-shower-eucalyptus&quot;&gt;💡 Shower eucalyptus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I did when I moved into my new apartment (before I even finished fully unpacking) was get a bundle of eucalyptus from a bodega down the street and tie it to my showerhead. Eucalyptus is great! It looks nice and smells nice and putting it in your shower is a really simple thing you can do to make the whole bathroom feel a little nicer. Look for it at your local bodega, grocery store, or flower shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🎙️ Podcast" /><category term="💡 Idea" /><summary type="html">On starting over</summary></entry></feed>