<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-27T21:18:45+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Letters To Summer</title><subtitle>Two friends sharing the things they're reading, watching, listening to, and enjoying. In your inbox every other Thursday.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Letter 45</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/45/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 45" /><published>2020-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/45</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/45/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-distraction&quot;&gt;On distraction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I don’t know how to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; multitask anymore. I don’t know how to just do one thing at a time, start to finish, before moving on to the next thing. I am always trying to do more than one thing, whenever possible—I read tweets while I watch TV, and then I have to rewind to see what I missed; I pick up my phone in between every chapter of a book; I start new video games before I’ve finished the old ones. Even while I’m writing this, I’m getting notifications that I desperately want to click on. I want to get up from my desk and lay on my bed and check Instagram, even though I just checked it. There’s always something new to be looking at. There’s always something new to occupy my mind. And if there isn’t, I’ll find something anyway. I’m working on setting boundaries, on putting my phone on the other side of the room when I don’t need it, on learning how to (maybe, slowly, barely) strengthen my attention span when every day is the same and mindless scrolling is an easy coping mechanism. Today, I meditated for 10 minutes at the beginning of the workday. Maybe tomorrow, I’ll stand in front of the tea kettle and wait for it to boil without wandering into another room to check my email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had trouble focusing, on sitting still, on staying on one task. I’ve tried methods of blocking out time to devote myself to a single thing, but never kept the habit. I should be working on something else while writing this. Maybe you should be while reading it, too. I have a lot of difficulty deciphering between distraction and break — if I jump on Twitter after completing a task, isn’t it worth it to give my brain a moment of rest? But what if I was on Twitter all throughout the task? If I stamped the document I was meant to be working on each time I moved away from it, I’d never have a legible piece of work again. That might be the solution—creating a system of accountability with myself. What does distraction look like? There are two modes, to me: purposeful and compulsive. Sometimes the world is so bad and I simply want to not exist in it anymore, instead am desperately searching for something to keep my mind otherwise occupied. This is fine. Sometimes I am increasingly bored with what I must do—waiting for the kettle to boil, waiting for a website to load, waiting for an e-mail—and find myself completely away from intention an hour later. Yes, the water has cooled before I made tea, yes I had sixty new tabs open before the page was visible, yes I realized I had been sitting on my bed for nearly a half hour while people were waiting for me in the other room. These are not breaks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pkmnshitpost/status/1258402286402969600?lang=en&quot;&gt;Oh, to have someone deep-clean my brain with a vacuum as if I am an old Pikachu plush&lt;/a&gt;. Oh, to pick one task and complete it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-search-party&quot;&gt;📺 Search Party&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This show had been on my radar since it premiered in 2016, but I hadn’t gotten around to it until last week. Yes, I watched three seasons in a week! Alia Shawkat, my Arab American icon, I love her so much, is so so fucking good and I need her to be a leading lady in everything. The first season is the shiniest for me—the cringe humor is perfectly executed, the mystery is intriguing, and I really, really haven’t laughed that loud that consistently in such a long time. Season 2 and 3 are a little more stressful, a little messier, but still a good reward. I am really excited to see what the fourth season brings. Watch it on HBOMax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-awesome-acnh-resources&quot;&gt;🎮 Awesome ACNH resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’m still playing Animal Crossing! Not every day, and not nearly as much as I did back in March, but I’m still very much loving it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/skullface/awesome-acnh&quot;&gt;This doc of resources&lt;/a&gt; is one of the best I’ve seen, and is helpful whether you’ve been playing for months or are just getting started—it’s got links to help you with everything from tracking turnip prices and planning hybrid flower gardens to finding cute custom designs and keeping track of which bugs you still need to catch. It’s a really good one-stop shop for any ACNH help you might need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-new-testament-by-jericho-brown&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;The New Testament&lt;/em&gt; by Jericho Brown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m 26 poetry books-deep for the Sealey Challenge, and &lt;em&gt;The New Testament&lt;/em&gt; is definitely in my top 5 for the month! Jericho Brown is probably one of the most influential poets right now and I hadn’t spent too much time with his work, so this was just an incredible evening of reading. Every page was stunning. I wanted to underline it all. I want to close-read every poem and watch the perfect moments forever. You know the drill—&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/&quot;&gt;bookshop&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781556594571&quot;&gt;IndieBound&lt;/a&gt; for your copy! Many libraries are re-opening too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-three-gems-tea&quot;&gt;🍽️ Three Gems Tea&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve been really into finding small tea businesses and trying out their different loose leaf teas, and my newest favorite is Three Gems Tea. I ordered their &lt;a href=&quot;https://threegemstea.com/collections/tea/products/6-oolong-tea-sampler&quot;&gt;6 oolong tea sampler&lt;/a&gt; and the ones I’ve tried so far are very yummy—I’m excited to pick a couple of favorites and order bigger bags of them. They also have a really cute &lt;a href=&quot;https://threegemstea.com/products/3-is-a-magic-number-three-gems-tea-zine-1&quot;&gt;zine&lt;/a&gt; for sale (you know we love zines here) and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://threegemstea.com/pages/brew-guide&quot;&gt;helpful brew guide&lt;/a&gt; on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><summary type="html">On distraction</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 44</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/44/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 44" /><published>2020-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/44</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/44/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-burnout&quot;&gt;On burnout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many things that I want to do every day that I don’t have enough time for it all. At the same time, I’m too tired to do much of anything except sit at my desk all day and then watch TV or play video games for a few hours until it’s time for bed. But I want to do things! I want to walk to the park on my lunch break! I want to send postcards to my friends! I want to participate in a weekly book club! I want to knit socks! I want to make stuff! I want to learn! But, yes, I also want (and frankly &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt;) to lay in bed with a cup of tea and do nothing. Sometimes I want to do that for the whole day. I don’t love it, but it is what it is. I’m working on it, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so tired all of the time. I start so many letters like this. Jill and I pace this letter very well, and have taken the breaks we needed when we needed them; the practice of writing for the letter has never exhausted me, but sometimes I struggle with content because having things to recommend means &lt;em&gt;doing things&lt;/em&gt; besides eating and playing Animal Crossing. I don’t want to say I feel burnt out from being a person? But sometimes? That’s what it feels like! I’ve experienced burnout from school and from writing and from my job; the only thing I’ve ever really taken a big break from, purposefully, was writing poetry. I’m not sure when I’ll fall back into it. Will I ever be a student again? Am I scarred? Maybe! All I know is I have a headache every morning and I’m still watching &lt;em&gt;Sex and the City,&lt;/em&gt; slower than I’ve ever watched any show in my life probably&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; May we all feel energized again, soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-deluge-by-leila-chatti&quot;&gt;📖 DELUGE by Leila Chatti&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August is the time for the Sealey Challenge, where you read a book of poetry every day (named for the poet who started it, Nicole Sealey, who I recommended in &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/2&quot;&gt;one of our first letters&lt;/a&gt;). I’m 13 days strong, but haven’t really been able to stop thinking about my first day: DELUGE. Leila captures panic/confusion/betrayal of your body so wonderfully and heart-breakingly, composing a true arc. There is a climax point. There is an urgency to continue reading, one more akin to a thrilling novel. The book, as a physical object, is also stunning, which I generally expect from Copper Canyon. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coppercanyonpress.org/books/deluge-by-leila-chatti/&quot;&gt;Go get a copy&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-pride-and-prejudice&quot;&gt;📽️ Pride and Prejudice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how many times I’ve watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/70032594&quot;&gt;this movie&lt;/a&gt;, but I know it’s a lot. Most recently, with a group of friends on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflixparty.com&quot;&gt;Netflix Party&lt;/a&gt; so we could all scream into the chat together. (The hand flex! &lt;em&gt;The hand flex!!!&lt;/em&gt;) It has never once failed to make me feel good, and no matter how many times I’ve seen it, it only gets more perfect each time. It’s on Netflix now! If you haven’t seen it, watch it now. And if you have, watch it again. And again, and again, and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-nory-candy-shop&quot;&gt;🍽️ Nory Candy Shop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LianaAgh&quot;&gt;Liana Aghajanian&lt;/a&gt; tweeted about this LA-based Armenian candy shop’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/save-56yr-old-small-family-run-candy-business&quot;&gt;GoFundMe for COVID relief&lt;/a&gt; and mentioned that they also mail boxes of lokum/Turkish delight nationally…so I bought two boxes! It’s the best version I’ve ever had, better than the confectioner-sugar soaked boxes or the fresher, gooey-er Syrian versions selected at the Arab market by my parents’ home. I got a box of pomegranate and mango and it feels like such a special treat, and a wonderful break from the copious amounts of cookies and brownies I’ve been baking during quarantine. You can look at their offerings and order &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norylocum.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-untamed&quot;&gt;📺 The Untamed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the thing that has fully consumed me for the past month, I guess! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/81200228&quot;&gt;The Untamed&lt;/a&gt; is a live-action adaptation of a novel called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mo_Dao_Zu_Shi&quot;&gt;Mo Dao Zu Shi&lt;/a&gt;—I will let you go down that rabbit hole by yourself. It is sort of about demons, but mostly about yearning, and it’s extremely cheesy but will also rip your heart out a little bit. My friends convinced me to watch it, and as we all know, everything is better when you share it with the people you care about. (Full disclosure: my preamble in &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/43/&quot;&gt;the last letter&lt;/a&gt; was 100% about this show.) Listen: I can’t say it’s the best show I’ve ever seen in my life, but I have spent hours and hours and hours thinking about it, and I don’t think I’ll stop anytime soon. Do with that what you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📺 TV" /><summary type="html">On burnout</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 43</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/43/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 43" /><published>2020-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/43</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/43/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-community&quot;&gt;On community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I think the purest kind of joy is telling your friends to watch a show or read a book or play a game or listen to an album that you really, really love just so you can watch them fall in love with it too. So you can send incoherent messages back and forth to each other about how it makes you feel. So you can experience a thing that makes you feel like you’re on fire &lt;em&gt;together&lt;/em&gt;. I guess that’s sort of why we started this newsletter—because sharing the things you like with the people you like is so, so good. It’s just a really funny, pleasant feeling to watch a TV series sweep through your friend group, picking off each person one by one until we’re all saturated with love for the same dumb thing. I want to bottle that feeling and experience it every single day, forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online spaces have always been my biggest source of community; I have been so lucky to connect with people across my interests and never really feel alone, despite all of the times I have been lonely. In the early pandemic, there were lots of shifts with how people related to each other, realizing they could not see each other or touch—the majority of my longest, strongest friendships have taken place this way. My community is always with me and always away from me, our sync oscillating (different places in life, different interests, different time zones) but I always know we can fall back into a rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-great&quot;&gt;📺 The Great&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very much in the vein of &lt;em&gt;The Favorite&lt;/em&gt; (showrunned by the guy who wrote it) &lt;em&gt;*but maybe a little more earnest when it comes to girl power, *The Great&lt;/em&gt; is a very fun pseudo-history about the Russian empress Catherine the Great, starring Elle Fanning. She’s so fucking good! Everyone in the cast is! My roommate and I picked this show for our mealtime routine, which was actually a bad idea because it’s really disgusting and has an incredible amount of vomiting, but! It was so fucking funny! I am so happy for Elle Fanning! My main descriptor: fun!!!! Love to have it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hulu.com/series/the-great-238db0d4-c476-47ed-9bee-d326fd302f7d&quot;&gt;Watch it on Hulu&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-netflix-party&quot;&gt;📱 Netflix Party&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People have been talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflixparty.com&quot;&gt;Netflix Party&lt;/a&gt; since the beginning of quarantine (and probably before that, too!) as one of the ways to scratch the itch of hanging out with your friends when you can’t actually see them irl. I never actually tried it until this week, but now it’s my new favorite thing, thanks for asking. All you have to do is download the Chrome extension, open the movie or episode you want to watch on Netflix, and share the Netflix Party link with your friends so you watch and chat together. I’ve been using it to watch The Untamed with a couple of friends who have seen it before so we can all yell and cry about it together—pure joy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-falastin-a-cookbook&quot;&gt;🍽️ Falastin: A Cookbook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sami Tamimi is the co-author of &lt;em&gt;Jerusalem,&lt;/em&gt; a cookbook that has sat in my house since its release about ten years ago, heavily referenced and respected by my mom (the best cook in the world!). Now, he has taken the spotlight in his own cookbook (still co-authored) on Palestinian cooking. &lt;em&gt;Falastin&lt;/em&gt; is beautiful and the recipes are really fucking good. I’ve only made a few things so far, but I’m so excited to try more!! The recipe index is also really awesome, especially for people unfamiliar with ingredients common in Arab cooking; what’s even better is it’s not just defining spices, it’s also defining terms, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://bdsmovement.net/what-is-bds&quot;&gt;BDS&lt;/a&gt; or OPT (occupied Palestinian territories)—these terms that describe the limitations of our movement, or the movements behind our liberation are as vital as olive oil or sumac or anything else. I recommend making the sweet tahini rolls, the dough is very good. Buy your copy on &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/falastin-a-cookbook/9780399581731&quot;&gt;bookshop&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9780399581731&quot;&gt;IndieBound&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-apply-for-your-absentee-ballot&quot;&gt;🔗 Apply for your absentee ballot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have heard, but there are less than 100 days until the election and we are still in the middle of a pandemic and USPS is having all kinds of issues, which is all just to say that you should probably apply for an absentee ballot sooner rather than later. (Yes, even if you think you might vote in person. Just do it anyway.) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vote.org/absentee-ballot/&quot;&gt;This form&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vote.org&quot;&gt;vote.org&lt;/a&gt; makes it very easy to do. I did it earlier this week! At the very least, I recommend looking up the deadline to request a ballot in your state and putting it on your calendar so you don’t forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><summary type="html">On community</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 42</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/42" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 42" /><published>2020-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/42</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/42">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-change&quot;&gt;On change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nice thing about projects like this one—fun personal projects with low stakes that you have total creative control over—is that you can do whatever you want with them. If you have a bunch of new ideas, you can try them out. If something isn’t working, you can go in a different direction instead. I often find change in my personal life scary and anxiety-inducing, but trying new things with a side project is exciting. This is all to say: we have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/letterstosummer&quot;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; now! You can sign up at different tiers to get some (hopefully) cool bonus content from us! And we will be donating 100% of the proceeds to a different organization every month, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theokraproject.com&quot;&gt;The Okra Project&lt;/a&gt;! I’m happy we have a chance to do something like this, and I’m even happier to look back and see how far this little newsletter has come since the beginning. I hope you like it, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am less afraid of change than I am of being an inconsistent person. I’m not ritualistic, I’m horrible at keeping habits—most of my day-to-day is a series of small changes with how I approach my work, my life, my friends. There are ways to frame this more generously: spontaneous! eclectic! very cool and fun!, but difficult to assign when changing an Animal Crossing villager stresses me out. I want to remember the facets of change that are good, the ones that allow you to define yourself further: change that builds upon itself, change that leaves you refreshed, change that leaves you excited. The world is exhausting and I am bad at doing things, but this newsletter is a constant. I’m happy to be doing things with Jill to make us both feel refreshed and re-excited about doing anything again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-black-maria-by-aracelis-girmay&quot;&gt;📖 The Black Maria by Aracelis Girmay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was seeking comfort and realized more than anything, I wanted to re-read &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Animalia&lt;/em&gt; by Aracelis Girmay, &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/22&quot;&gt;which I have recommended on this newsletter before&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t have my copy with me, which was tragic, but I realized I could just buy a different Aracelis Girmay book! And so I did! &lt;em&gt;The Black Maria&lt;/em&gt; continues to affirm my belief that Aracelis Girmay can do practically anything with a poem and you still know she wrote it, because no one can do it like she can!!! There’s a signature vibe, an energy, something I could talk about more in depth if I was smarter or less tired. This collection, formally, is so fucking cool; poems blend into each other, it feels epic but distinct. I am always in awe! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boaeditions.org/products/the-black-maria&quot;&gt;Go buy a copy!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-one-anti-racist-action-a-day&quot;&gt;✉️ One Anti-Racist Action a Day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://oneaction.today&quot;&gt;This newsletter&lt;/a&gt; is exactly what it sounds like: a daily reminder of something you can do to be anti-racist, support the Black Lives Matter movement, and care for the people in your community. Sometimes it has a link to a petition to sign, sometimes it has a template for an email to send, and sometimes it has something for you to read. To be clear: subscribing to this newsletter should not be the extent of your anti-racism work, but it is a really great place to start if you’ve been feeling overwhelmed by resources or want a daily reminder to hold yourself accountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-mujis-pens--stationery&quot;&gt;🔗 Muji’s pens &amp;amp; stationery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgive me if you’ve heard of this worldwide corporation before, but they recently declared bankruptcy in the US and I am feeling some type of way. Muji pens are my favorite to write with and their notebooks changed everything for me! Small, simply cute, and just enough pages for a semester! You can peruse their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.muji.us/store/stationery.html&quot;&gt;online store&lt;/a&gt;. My favorite is the purple capped gel-ink pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cute-face-masks&quot;&gt;🧠 Cute face masks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what! We are in the middle of a pandemic! And you should absolutely be wearing a face mask every time you leave your house! I got a &lt;a href=&quot;https://losangelesapparel.net/products/3-pack-cotton-mask?variant=31978394189886&quot;&gt;pack of three&lt;/a&gt; reusable cloth ones (pink, of course) back in March, but recently ordered another from &lt;a href=&quot;https://piehole.bigcartel.com&quot;&gt;Piehole&lt;/a&gt;. They’re making a bunch of cute, reusable masks and donating 50% of the proceeds to an organization of your choice. Bottom line: we’re going to be wearing masks for a while, so you might as well stock up on some cute ones that look good with your outfits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🧠 Wellness" /><summary type="html">On change</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 41</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/41" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 41" /><published>2020-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/41</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/41">&lt;p&gt;Before we get into this week’s letter, we’d like to direct you to letter &lt;a href=&quot;/39&quot;&gt;#39&lt;/a&gt; for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pymusa.com/donations&quot;&gt;The Palestinian Youth Movement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glitsinc.org&quot;&gt;GLITS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-uncertainty&quot;&gt;On uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when going to bars and parties was a regular occurrence, I got anxious and easily irritated whenever my boyfriend invited me to go somewhere with him but didn’t give me a specific time or place well in advance. I hated the uncertainty of not knowing where the night was going, not having a clear plan. I hated feeling unprepared. Some people have no problem making casual plans and seeing where the night takes them; I am not one of those people. Calendar invites are my love language. That’s how uncertainty makes me feel on a small scale, so you can imagine what the uncertainty of, say, a global pandemic does to me—or even the uncertainty of what my life will look like in five years. I know this is an anxiety that will probably stick with me forever, on some level, but I’ve gotten a little bit better at dealing with it: recognizing what is actually within my control in the present moment, exercising control over those things in a healthy and helpful way, and learning to let go of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m anxious and impatient but not very good at making plans, and so generally, I don’t. Logistics stress me out. I’m not very fun, because of this, nor do I do very much, but most of my near-future is understood. So, naturally, the uncertainty of the pandemic is fucking me up. Choosing to create certainty for myself means deciding to be pessimistic (realistic?) about how to continue and how the virus will continue, too. My future is working from home, sanitizing all of my groceries (I know technically we don’t have to but read the first two words of this), and wearing a mask every time I go out. It also means being reluctant to look forward to anything; my partner and I used to see each other every month, but now airlines are deciding to book full flights? So no? We’re both in terrible outbreak states? Will TV happen anymore? I don’t want it to if it means people aren’t safe? I’m just a year past graduating and having that spiral of uncertainty, contending with it, figuring things out. All of that figure-outing has kind of dissolved, though. I guess I’m okay with not knowing but mostly because I don’t have a choice but to be resigned to it. At least everyone is sort of in the same boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-pose&quot;&gt;📺 Pose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of uncertainty, I’m going to recommend a show I haven’t finished yet. &lt;em&gt;POSE&lt;/em&gt; on FX! I’ve consumed too much Ryan Murphy content this quarantine, but this show is definitely the best and has the least amount of frustrating trademarks of Ryan Murphy shows. It’s shot beautifully, the cast is stunning and talented, and there are hardly any white people in sight. :) When an episode is feel-good, I cry, when an episode is heart-wrenching, I cry, and if there’s anything I need during quarantine it’s honestly different emotional triggers besides “general despair and hopelessness.” Season 1 and 2 are both streaming on Netflix!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-punisher-by-phoebe-bridgers&quot;&gt;🎶 Punisher by Phoebe Bridgers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phoebe Bridgers is and will always be my sad girl queen, and she has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/2xECuqnvvmVktV7UO8Dd3s&quot;&gt;new album&lt;/a&gt; to help you lean into your sad girl-ness, too. I don’t know how to write about music and I always get nervous when I try, so I will just say that this album makes me &lt;em&gt;Feel Things™&lt;/em&gt; in the best way. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/4BNew3AqFCvABdFsYMRiyB?si=SmZThXRySQ-4DXq0ku-UUQ&quot;&gt;Savior Complex&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite song of the moment and I’m looking forward to seeing it at the top of my most-played list in my Spotify Rewind this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-apricot-season&quot;&gt;🍽️ Apricot Season&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truthfully, I’m not doing many new things these days, just playing the same video games, watching reruns of Food Network shows, and fucking around online until it’s time to sleep. Time is super warped in quarantine but you know what’s a beautiful marker? Seasonal fruits! Go buy apricots! They’re one of my main sources of joy these past few weeks! They are so little and far less messy than other stone fruit. A perfect snack. If you’re allergic I’m sorry! I’m gonna eat the last one in my fridge right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-quaranzine-by-conveyor-studio&quot;&gt;📖 Quaranzine by Conveyor Studio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://conveyor.studio/shop/qz-subscription&quot;&gt;Conveyor&lt;/a&gt; is a very nice indie book studio, and they’re currently publishing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://conveyor.studio/shop/qz-subscription&quot;&gt;six-part zine series&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with some cool creative folks. You can subscribe to get all six zines, or you can buy each one individually as they come out—and the profits are being donated to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nynice.org&quot;&gt;NICE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nychealthandhospitals.org&quot;&gt;NYC Health + Hospitals&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve gotten two of the zines so far, and I love them both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📖 Read" /><summary type="html">Before we get into this week’s letter, we’d like to direct you to letter #39 for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend The Palestinian Youth Movement and GLITS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 40</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/40" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 40" /><published>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/40</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/40">&lt;p&gt;There’s no personal note from either of us this time. Instead, we’d like to direct you to letter &lt;a href=&quot;/39&quot;&gt;#39&lt;/a&gt; for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theokraproject.com&quot;&gt;The Okra Project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glitsinc.org&quot;&gt;GLITS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-last-black-man-in-san-francisco&quot;&gt;📽️ Last Black Man in San Francisco&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This movie had been on my list for an achingly long time, and I finally watched it on my birthday. It was so fucking good, and so different than what I expected. The &lt;em&gt;energy&lt;/em&gt; of this movie. Time can pass and you don’t really notice it, or time can drag on and you notice it, but this film pulls you in such a way that you feel like viewing itself is momentum. What a tragedy it got so little awards recognition. I don’t know a person that watched this movie that didn’t think it was spectacular. The cinematography is ridiculously cool—there are so many weird, surreal shots that make the weirdness so stunning? The performances are endearing and just spectacular. Highly recommend, especially for folks in the bay, especially if you’re a transplant. You can watch it on Amazon or Kanopy if your library participates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cardcaptor-sakura&quot;&gt;📺 Cardcaptor Sakura&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched all of Cardcaptor Sakura for the first time a few months ago, right when the city was starting to shut down and I suddenly had a lot more time to myself. I was contemplating a rewatch of Sailor Moon, which I have always found comforting to have on in the background while puttering around in my apartment, but started watching Cardcaptor Sakura at the suggestion of a friend instead and quickly fell in love with it. It’s cute and fun and joyful and I promise it will make you feel good. And it’s on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/70309056?trackId=200257858&quot;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; now, so you really have no choice but to fall in love with it, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-permadeath-by-marlin-m-jenkins&quot;&gt;🔗 Permadeath by Marlin M. Jenkins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://therumpus.net/2020/06/permadeath/&quot;&gt;This essay&lt;/a&gt; is exactly the type of writing I aspire to, and the type of writing I want to see in the world—Marlin is always so good at identifying the &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; in a game, that &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; that makes you attached and emotional, and making you reflect on what those attachments look like, what they mean—whether or not you’ve actually played the game being discussed. The prose is also just so fucking beautiful. More good video game writing! More treating video games like the art they are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-eat-a-snack&quot;&gt;🍽️ Eat a snack!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I struggled a lot trying to think of a second recommendation this week. We always tend toward recommending media that we’re enjoying, which I love, because sharing a book or a movie or a video game with your friends is one of the greatest joys there is. But right now I want to recommend that you eat a snack, because that feels like the most honest and true recommendation I can give—eat a snack, or drink a glass of water, or take a shower, or go for a short walk outside, or do whatever other tiny thing you can do right now to take care of yourself. (My favorite snacks today have been cheez-its and blackberries. In case you wanted to know.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><summary type="html">There’s no personal note from either of us this time. Instead, we’d like to direct you to letter #39 for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend The Okra Project and GLITS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 39</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/39" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 39" /><published>2020-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/39</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/39">&lt;p&gt;We’re forgoing our regular format this week, since what we’re doing recreationally isn’t important right now. Instead, we’d like to encourage you all to donate to folks on the ground protesting the murders of George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and the countless other Black folks who have been killed by police violence. Educate yourselves and your loved ones on police abolition, and take care of your communities however you can. We’d also like to emphasize that police violence in the US is ongoing and not just something happening in this moment—the violence that Black folks face is not trendy! Hold onto this energy and continue to donate to anti-racist organizations and bail funds even after the protests slow down. Become aware of community organizations dedicated to fighting oppressive structures. Find your niche in how you can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send emails to your government officials.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.email2act.com&quot;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; has several easy-to-use email templates that you can use to email officials in different cities about the actions of their police. All you have to do is plug in your name and hit send. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://defund12.org/nyc&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; has email templates for urging your representatives to defund the police department and redirect those funds to education and social services.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate to bail funds.&lt;/strong&gt; Protestors are doing extremely important work right now, and local bail funds ensure that they can continue doing that work. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bailfunds.github.io&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a list of bail funds across the country that could use your help, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.actblue.com/donate/bail_funds_george_floyd&quot;&gt;here’s&lt;/a&gt; a link to split a donation between over 70 of them at once. Several cities that have gotten a massive amount of support over the past week are asking folks to send their donations elsewhere, so please make sure to do your research first!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate to mutual aid funds.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t forget: we’re in a pandemic. People need supplies, and people on the ground need to be safe, too. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thegirlwithfood/status/1267572248149442562&quot;&gt;This thread&lt;/a&gt; has links nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refrain from spreading cop propaganda.&lt;/strong&gt; Officers at various marches have joined protestors, but without actual actions/consequences, this is meaningless because the harmful structures that led us here stay in place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join or support abolition organizations.&lt;/strong&gt; Here are a few to start: &lt;a href=&quot;https://survivedandpunished.org/about/&quot;&gt;Survived &amp;amp; Punished&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area &amp;amp; NYC), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antipoliceterrorproject.org/&quot;&gt;Anti-Police Terror Project&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area), &lt;a href=&quot;https://humanimpact.org/&quot;&gt;Human Impact&lt;/a&gt; (does work through a public health lens), &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peoplesbreakoak?lang=en&quot;&gt;People’s Breakfast&lt;/a&gt; (Oakland, also does free meals program), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.api-rise.org/&quot;&gt;API Rise&lt;/a&gt; (Los Angeles), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asianprisonersupport.com/&quot;&gt;Asian Prisoner Support Committee&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom-inc.org/&quot;&gt;Freedom Inc.&lt;/a&gt; (Madison). These are geographically centered on just a few places, and some culturally specific—please send us organizations in your location and we can include them in future letters!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue to educate yourself on abolition.&lt;/strong&gt; Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1HUpCPvOwUJElxtUP4mCysAY9GyZrSmUk&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; with flyers that present alternatives to policing. MPD15, an organization working toward a police-free Minneapolis, has a helpful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mpd150.com/faq/&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; on their website. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usprisonculture.com/blog/essential-pic-reading-list/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; are some other essential readings to get you started! &lt;a href=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/59ead8f9692ebee25b72f17f/t/5b65cd58758d46d34254f22c/1533398363539/CR_NoCops_reform_vs_abolition_CRside.pdf&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a helpful graphic from &lt;a href=&quot;http://criticalresistance.org/abolish-policing/&quot;&gt;Critical Resistance&lt;/a&gt; that breaks down the difference between reform and abolition.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep going!&lt;/strong&gt; This work doesn’t end today. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blacklivesmatters.carrd.co&quot;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; has tons more resources and ways you can take action. Call and email your representatives regularly. Set up recurring donations. Attend protests and vigils in your city if you can. Share helpful, informative posts with your friends, family, and followers. Continue to listen, and continue to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="💡 Idea" /><summary type="html">We’re forgoing our regular format this week, since what we’re doing recreationally isn’t important right now. Instead, we’d like to encourage you all to donate to folks on the ground protesting the murders of George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and the countless other Black folks who have been killed by police violence. Educate yourselves and your loved ones on police abolition, and take care of your communities however you can. We’d also like to emphasize that police violence in the US is ongoing and not just something happening in this moment—the violence that Black folks face is not trendy! Hold onto this energy and continue to donate to anti-racist organizations and bail funds even after the protests slow down. Become aware of community organizations dedicated to fighting oppressive structures. Find your niche in how you can help.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 38</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/38" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 38" /><published>2020-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/38</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/38">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-video-games&quot;&gt;On video games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most mornings, in between making my first cup of tea of the day and sitting at my desk to work, I play Animal Crossing in bed to ease myself awake. I go through my daily chores in the game (watering my flowers, digging up fossils, talking to my neighbors, checking the shops) before I’m ready to tackle my daily chores in real life. Once I finish working for the day, I’m eager to return to my students in Fire Emblem Three Houses (which &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/21&quot;&gt;Summer recommended in this newsletter&lt;/a&gt; before I was ready to hear it). And all the moments in between, I spend plenty of time watching Twitch streams, liking tweets about Breath of the Wild, and sending Summer way too many Discord messages about the games we’re playing. I’d like to say something here about how video games are a place to “find solace” in these “unprecedented” and “trying” times, whatever that means. Instead, I will point you to two essays that I keep returning to that say it better than I can: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2020/02/video-games-are-a-to-do-list-you-play.html&quot;&gt;“Video Games Are a To-Do List That You Play”&lt;/a&gt; is required reading to understand me, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/5/12/21241735/nintendo-switch-animal-crossing-video-games-coronavirus-quarantine&quot;&gt;Alanna Okun’s recent piece&lt;/a&gt; about playing video games in quarantine hit me especially hard. Here’s a quote from the latter: “I want a place that’s not here, a set of problems that aren’t these, something I can talk about with my friends and co-workers and strangers that isn’t going to claw me apart with anxiety.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been just a year since I graduated college, which means it’s been just a year since a month-long period began in which I did very little each day besides play Breath of the Wild. I was so exhaused. I was getting sicker each day, from some mysterious dust in my apartment (I’m ok now, I use my inhaler and everything). I was anxiously waiting to hear back from a few jobs but had no energy to apply to others. Really, there was nothing else for me besides playing. The only major story point I had left was to defeat Ganon. And for a month, I didn’t; instead, I wandered. I felt too scared to fight the last battle without a friend with me. I’m not trying to make this into some sort of grand metaphor about how I wasn’t ready to move onto the next phase of my life in the interim of graduating and an office job, but the wandering in Breath of the Wild helped soothe my anxiety about urgency; the big things could wait, and handling the…side quests of life?…was valid, for now. There isn’t a time in my life in which video games did not assist that urgency to do More, and there isn’t a time in which video games didn’t improve other aspects of my life. Games made my brother and I have a good relationship, helped me make friends, and continue to help me come down from stressful events. Jill and I talk about video games basically every day, and like her, Animal Crossing is part of my morning routine—it was part of my morning routine when I was eight, too, and when I was fourteen, when there was no pandemic and I just carried general anxiety and stress about the world. It’s a constant that’s not actually a constant. And I need it! I love video games. Always have and always will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-sex-and-the-city&quot;&gt;📺 Sex and the City&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sex and the City is under the “comfort viewing” section on HBO. I thought I was tuning into an adult Gossip Girl&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; dealing with the absolutely bonkers stakes rich people create for themselves but instead it’s actually? Comfortable? Oh to go to brunch with your friends, oh to walk the New York streets at night in your $400 shoes, oh to be part of a campy group of friends that are archetypal yet fleshed out. The disconnect from my actual life—Carrie mentions meeting Mr. Big at 9 o’clock to which I said &lt;em&gt;god that’s so late,&lt;/em&gt; to my boyfriend’s amusement—is just strong enough to not remind me that I can’t drink wine and laugh with my friends without a computer screen. Normally I don’t recommend something I haven’t finished, but I’m flying through season 2, and having a very good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cleaning-your-desk&quot;&gt;💡 Cleaning your desk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not have the greatest week, to be honest. A bad combination of PMS and anxiety left me feeling absolutely horrible for a few days, and while I’m still not feeling great, I did manage to take advantage of a slight burst of energy to clean off some of the clutter on my desk and rearrange things in a way that’s making my brain feel a little bit better. I replaced the haphazard piles of sticky notes with a daily planner! I moved anything I don’t use on a daily basis out of sight! The thing is: cleaning up your workspace is not a perfect, permanent solution to any of the bad stuff, but it’s probably one of the only things in your control right now, so it definitely doesn’t hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-carly-rae-jepsens-dedication-side-b&quot;&gt;🎶 Carly Rae Jepsen’s &lt;em&gt;Dedication Side B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up pretty sad this morning and guess what! Carly helped! We love a complex album that tracks a relationship and mixes the upbeat with the sad! I’m still in my initial listens, but as someone who got into CRJ relatively late—this is my suggestion to you: go have fun! &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7oHKKCXCFIv3J1Yh5F08pu&quot;&gt;Go to Spotify!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-rebecca-solnit-on-hope&quot;&gt;📖 Rebecca Solnit on hope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most comforting things I’ve read so far during all this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/07/what-coronavirus-can-teach-us-about-hope-rebecca-solnit&quot;&gt;Rebecca Solnit’s essay&lt;/a&gt; in The Guardian about &lt;em&gt;what the coronavirus can teach us about hope.&lt;/em&gt; I suggest you read it, too. And when you’ve finished that and want some more, you can read her book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781608465767&quot;&gt;Hope in the Dark&lt;/a&gt;, which explores how hope and human compassion can be catalysts for change in moments like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="💡 Idea" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="📖 Read" /><summary type="html">On video games</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 37</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/37" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 37" /><published>2020-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/37</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/37">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-nostalgia&quot;&gt;On nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if it’s because I’m bored, or because I’m desperately searching for new coping mechanisms in the middle of all of this, but I’ve been spending a lot of time thinking about a reaching for experiences I had growing up. Last night, after a couple glasses of wine, I went down a rabbit hole searching for all the old MMORPGs I used to play. (Pixie Hollow, anyone? Virtual Magic Kingdom? Toontown? Bring them back!) I’ve been heavily considering joining Summer as she rewatches Glee from the beginning. And now I guess Stephanie Meyer is publishing Midnight Sun, which, alright! Nostalgia is not always a good thing, but I’m finding it comforting these days, when little else is. It makes sense that we’d want to turn our minds to a past in which we could go outside without masks on, and enjoy the things that occupied our time when we were younger and had less to worry about—I think it’s okay to let yourself lean into the nostalgia a little bit! Make a playlist of songs you loved in high school. Revisit your favorite movies and TV shows and books and games, even if they aren’t as good now, just to scratch the itch. And then return to the present, because there is nothing more important than paying attention to what is happening around us right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re 7-ish weeks into quarantine, which means I’ve been rewatching a lot of TV. Nostalgia used to feel like an ugly word, a feeling I would wrinkle my nose at when I heard people talk about past eras. I now know this is because I was truly too young, and most of the nostalgia my peers had was constructed by media that told them to feel nostalgic for a time they never experienced. It felt artificial and white-washy, like &lt;em&gt;why would you want to experience a time in which the world was noticeably so much worse.&lt;/em&gt; Revisiting things from 2009 or 2012, though, I find myself nostalgic not for the Obama era (lmao) but the way that media carried me. Mostly, I’m thinking about shows like Glee, where I can trace so much of my fandom lineage, and that I can thank for so many of my friends (like Jillian 😀), the way I think about media, and the way I process discourse and conflict—my patience was never tested more than hiatus weeks, but the absolute &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt; those breaks generated. Unparalleled. I wasn’t in a great place mentally back then, but I can still pull fondness when I think about my shows. Something to be excited about. Something to make you feel something. I’m trying to hold onto things to be excited about—and right now, that manifests in reliving my urgency for a new episode of Glee each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-zaina-alsouss-a-theory-of-birds&quot;&gt;📖 Zaina Alsous’s &lt;em&gt;A Theory of Birds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend a lot of poetry in this newsletter, to the point where it seems like I’ve probably never read a novel, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://zainaalsous.com/&quot;&gt;Zaina’s&lt;/a&gt; collection gave me the feeling of reading a very immersive piece of fiction—not saying her work reads as prose in anyway, nor is it escapism, but there’s this incredible balance between intricacy and simplicity. Those words are not necessarily at odds, but the weight of Zaina’s work never feels overwhelming, rather gravitational. I was excited to turn each page, excited to see what else she had in store for her reader. This is a work I will revisit over and over and over again—I read each poem twice, wanting to give them all of my time, poking at Hazem to read along with me several times so that they got the attention they deserved. It’s brilliant. It’s brilliant. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781682261040&quot;&gt;Indiebound&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/a-theory-of-birds-poems/9781682261040&quot;&gt;Bookshop.org&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uapress.com/product/a-theory-of-birds/&quot;&gt;publisher’s website&lt;/a&gt; to get your copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-the-creative-independent-newsletter&quot;&gt;✉️ The Creative Independent newsletter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content that The Creative Independent puts out is always fantastic—beautiful essays about writing and other types of creative work; interviews with artists, musicians, and creators of all sorts; and guides for just about everything (from &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/guides/how-to-write-a-poem/&quot;&gt;how to write a poem&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/guides/how-to-lose-someone/&quot;&gt;how to lose someone&lt;/a&gt;)—but their &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/&quot;&gt;daily newsletter&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite way to experience what they have to offer. My most recent favorite featured an &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/jenny-odell-on-taking-the-time-you-need-to-notice-think-and-grow/&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Jenny Odell, author of &lt;em&gt;How To Do Nothing&lt;/em&gt;, which we have also &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/31&quot;&gt;recommended&lt;/a&gt;. Go read it immediately, and then subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-never-have-i-ever&quot;&gt;📺 Never Have I Ever&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly, I was hesitant to begin this show after the last few seasons of The Mindy Project, but that all faded away after the first episode. I love seeing high school shows that do away with strict caste (especially in contrast to the Glee I’ve been watching) and instead focus on the realistic fluidity of relationships; familiarity is present among basically everyone, it’s easy to be friends and find common ground with pretty much anyone when you’re in the same classes. Devi is a fantastic character—ridiculously funny and every mistake feels earned (again, in contrast to Glee). The side characters are precious and have stories I’m excited about, too—they are not set-dressing, so much the opposite in fact that assuming so is an addressed conflict. The Sherman Oaks setting is used with such a wonderful specificity and I am a sucker for anything in LA suburbs. Also there are a lot of hot people! It’s on Netflix, go enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-acnh-travel-guide&quot;&gt;🎮 ACNH Travel Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably isn’t news to anyone, but I’ve been playing a lot of Animal Crossing New Horizons lately. I want to give a shout-out to &lt;a href=&quot;http://acnhtravelguide.com&quot;&gt;this super nice companion app&lt;/a&gt; that I’ve been using that makes it easy to see which bugs and fish are in season (and available at the time you’re playing), what you’ve already found and donated to the museum, what events are coming up, and tons more. It also has links to other great community resources, so you can test out new island tunes or track and predict your turnip prices without leaving the app. Download for iOS &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/app/id1502818559&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><summary type="html">On nostalgia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 36</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/36" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 36" /><published>2020-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/36</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/36">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-quarantine&quot;&gt;On quarantine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told Summer there were two directions we could go in this week: we could write about quarantine, or we could write about something else. We both agreed it felt wrong to choose the latter, at least right now. So we’re writing about it—it’s just that writing about it is hard. Maybe because it’s no longer new; it’s been 39 days, for me, of feeling anxious every time I go outside for groceries, wearing a mask and gloves and staying as far away from other people as I can. Part of me is worried I’ll forget what it feels like to go outside without thinking about it—or that I’ll never be able to again. I am making peace with it, but that doesn’t always mean I feel good. Some days are okay, and other days I carry the heavy weight of anxiety around in my chest no matter what I do. There’s no way to put it lightly: this sucks. I am trying to take it one day at a time, and to look for small moments of joy: the sound of rain outside through an open window while I sleep, dancing in my kitchen while I make dinner, the way the sun hits my bedroom wall just right in the afternoon, underlining a line in a book that makes me feel good. (Also: I am still revisiting our &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/35&quot;&gt;last newsletter&lt;/a&gt; for suggestions of ways to feel better right now—maybe that’s something you need, too.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quarantine is really the only angle I can think about things, which I’m sure many people can relate to. I’m still working, from home, trying to keep normal business hours. I wake up, drink coffee with my boyfriend, check my turnip prices, and check my e-mail. I’ve broken the “no working in bed” rule many times these past weeks—it’s the most comfortable place to be. Every workplace annoyance feels worse, every headache or stomach pain the end of the world. I dropped half a banana today and almost cried. I’ve always been dramatic, quick to jump to the worst conclusions, ruled by anxiety, but some of it doesn’t feel as irrational now. We are making do; I’m lucky I’m with people I love, and I have others to reach out to often. Every time I am outside I am grateful in a way I wasn’t before, too. Picking produce at the grocery store a few weeks ago felt like a deeply precious thing and I love the taste of everything fresh, so much. It’s weird, it’s fucking weird, it’s tragic, and don’t let anyone make you feel weird for thinking it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-clue-1985&quot;&gt;📽️ Clue (1985)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whodunnits are just the best! I’d be wanting to see this movie for quite a bit, but it’s finally streaming on Prime Video and Kanopy. This movie is based off of the boardgame, Clue, which may not be a big selling point, but listen. It’s perfect! It’s perfect. It’s so fucking hilarious, everyone in the cast is a gem, it uses its source material very creatively, campy as hell, and has the best last line of any film in history. Nothing is better! Please go have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-collaborative-playlists&quot;&gt;🎶 Collaborative playlists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/cassiebirb&quot;&gt;Cassie&lt;/a&gt; asked a few of us to pick ten songs each to put on a collaborative playlist that we could all listen to. Picking just ten songs was surprisingly difficult, but it was fun to come up with a mix of songs that I’ve liked for a while and newer songs that I’ve been listening to a lot lately—and I loved seeing what my friends added. I won’t share our playlist, because I like that it’s just for us, but I do recommend making collaborative playlists as a really cute way to connect with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-birthright-by-george-abraham&quot;&gt;📖 Birthright by George Abraham&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/3&quot;&gt;George’s work&lt;/a&gt; has been among the &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/27&quot;&gt;batches&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/12&quot;&gt;poems&lt;/a&gt; I’ve recommended before, but their full length debut is finally here—&lt;em&gt;Birthright!&lt;/em&gt; It is a stunning, heart-wrenching, brilliant collection that I am so, so happy to finally hold in my hands. George is an absolute mastermind with form. They know how to communicate intensely and intricately, and there’s nothing more I want to do than spend hours and hours and hours with their work. You can buy it from &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttonpoetry.com/product/birthright/&quot;&gt;Button Poetry&lt;/a&gt; (make sure to check out the blurb I co-wrote with other friends, hehe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-the-morning-report&quot;&gt;✉️ The Morning Report&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hedhouseman.substack.com/p/potential-hauntings?token=eyJ1c2VyX2lkIjo5Mjc0LCJwb3N0X2lkIjozNjQyMzYsIl8iOiI4ejdKOCIsImlhdCI6MTU4NzY3ODQ2MCwiZXhwIjoxNTg3NjgyMDYwLCJpc3MiOiJwdWItNTUwMiIsInN1YiI6InBvc3QtcmVhY3Rpb24ifQ.yxQArScDu1nUUbm-sAxSwyKKYrQ50x8KWc2_2vok3NM&quot;&gt;The Morning Report&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favorite newsletters right now. It started as a series of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?src=typd&amp;amp;q=hedhouseman%3A%20%22morning%20report%22&quot;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/hedhouseman&quot;&gt;Haley Houseman&lt;/a&gt; about things she saw on early-morning walks with her dog, and is now a beautiful, occasional newsletter that is mostly about nature but is sometimes about other things, too. The most recent one, titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://hedhouseman.substack.com/p/potential-hauntings?token=eyJ1c2VyX2lkIjo5Mjc0LCJwb3N0X2lkIjozNjQyMzYsIl8iOiI4ejdKOCIsImlhdCI6MTU4NzY3ODQ2MCwiZXhwIjoxNTg3NjgyMDYwLCJpc3MiOiJwdWItNTUwMiIsInN1YiI6InBvc3QtcmVhY3Rpb24ifQ.yxQArScDu1nUUbm-sAxSwyKKYrQ50x8KWc2_2vok3NM&quot;&gt;“Potential hauntings,”&lt;/a&gt; made me feel all kinds of things, but I suggest you read &lt;a href=&quot;https://hedhouseman.substack.com/p/what-is-the-morning-report&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; to start with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><summary type="html">On quarantine</summary></entry></feed>