<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-08T21:48:37+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Letters To Summer</title><subtitle>Two friends sharing the things they're reading, watching, listening to, and enjoying. In your inbox every other Thursday.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Letter 48</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/48/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 48" /><published>2020-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/48</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/48/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-process&quot;&gt;On process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve talked about &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/24&quot;&gt;routines&lt;/a&gt; before in this newsletter, about the comfort of having them and noticing them. I think about my own routines a lot—the big ones, like the things I do every morning to get ready for the day or every evening to get ready for bed; and the small ones, like the way I approach certain tasks at work or the way I write this newsletter every week. Starting to quarantine and work from home this year shook a lot of those processes up, and I struggled for months to feel even somewhat stable again. I had a hard time figuring out how to change my daily habits to fit a different environment. I think now, after two seasons have come and gone, I’m starting to feel like I’m on solid ground again. And I think a lot of that is because of those repetitive tasks that I find so much comfort in, like making a cup of tea every morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to write again. This newsletter has been my main creative outlet for over a year; basically, since I finished college, I’ve been struggling with working on anything at all. There have been small projects here and there, but these past few weeks I’ve finally remembered what creative energy feels like, despite struggling with some other Life things. I’m trying to re-learn a writing process; how much time do I spend with my references, how much time do I spend editing, how much time do I spend thinking? I want to get comfortable with my approaches and have a true &lt;em&gt;method&lt;/em&gt; for getting work done and doing what I want to do. I’m not good at routines or habits or any personal organizational things at all, but I think &lt;em&gt;process&lt;/em&gt; is within my grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-xiao-mei-brown-sugar-boba-ice-cream-bars&quot;&gt;🍴 Xiao Mei Brown Sugar Boba Ice Cream Bars&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My roommate was &lt;a href=&quot;https://fresh.hmart.com/media/catalog/product/cache/4a29384b44aa82bd9906cfa705b6f349/3/3/3323002181.png&quot;&gt;buying boxes of these&lt;/a&gt; for a good few weeks and god, they’re just the most amazing ice cream I’ve ever had. The texture was ridiculous—the creamiest ice cream but with little boba bits in it for the loveliest chew. The caramelization on the sugar is perfect. They made me feel like shit and I didn’t even care! You’ll probably have to go to Chinatown or an Asian grocery store to get them, but if it’s out of your way, I promise it’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-duolingo&quot;&gt;📱 Duolingo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working on replacing some of my social media usage with other, less doomscroll-y apps, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duolingo.com&quot;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; is my recent favorite. I’ve been on and off Duolingo for years to practice my extremely mediocre French, but this time I decided to try learning a new language entirely from scratch, just for fun. (Turns out it is, in fact, a lot of fun.) So I’m learning Mandarin now! I think Duolingo is a good way to get started with learning a language whether you want to be fluent or you just want to pick up a few phrases, but it’s &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; a good way to do the latter. It’s also, in my case, a really productive way to stay off Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-high-fidelity-on-hulu&quot;&gt;📺 High Fidelity on Hulu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry to recommend a show that’s been cancelled, but I just sped through the first and only season of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hulu.com/series/high-fidelity-52cb09be-ccc9-4eb4-9db8-f00b0443b2f5&quot;&gt;High Fidelity&lt;/a&gt; and whew! It was so good! I had tried it a few weeks ago and couldn’t get through the first five minutes but after giving it another chance, oh my god. Zoe Kravitz is really fun to watch, but the side characters are even better—the record store setting works really well, and what may be another show’s entire premise only serves as a hint of a formula for one story (revisiting exes), giving space for a lot of fun with format within the fourth-wall-breaking moments. Maybe someone else will give us the S2 we deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-computecuter&quot;&gt;📱 Computecuter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/sailorhg&quot;&gt;@sailorhg&lt;/a&gt; put together &lt;a href=&quot;https://computecuter.com&quot;&gt;this really nice website&lt;/a&gt; full of recommendations for cute text editor themes, monospaced fonts, and mechanical keyboard parts. All the stuff you need to make your computer cute! I love this and the little community of people online dedicated to making tech spaces cuter—we need even more of it, imo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="📺 TV" /><summary type="html">On process</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 47</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/47/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 47" /><published>2020-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/47</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/47/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-fall&quot;&gt;On fall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one hand, I like fall a lot. I like the cooler temperatures and that feeling that hangs in the air that reminds me of being in school or going trick or treating as a kid. I like wearing big sweaters and thick socks. I like the corny Hallmark smell of autumn-themed candles. On the other hand, I hate that it’s already dark by 7 pm, and I hate that it’s going to keep getting dark earlier and earlier. I hate that it’s going to get harder to make outdoor plans as it gets colder when I’m already barely leaving my apartment. I hate that wearing a mask fogs up my glasses even worse when the temperature drops below 70 degrees. But there’s nothing I can do about any of that—fall is here! We are still in the middle of a pandemic and we are still learning how to cope! The best I can do is appreciate the coziness of having a warm drink inside, invest in a SAD lamp, and look forward to the fall Animal Crossing update, I guess. We’re in this together!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been craving a seasonal coffee since September hit. Although I was never a big Starbucks fan, the cafes near my college and old apartment would conform to the trend with peppermint mochas, pumpkin spice, eggnog lattes, etc—there was always something new and special to try once the wind started blowing a bit colder. Of course, I’m in California, so much of this month has been windows closed, air purifier on, N95 and surgical masks doubled up to take my laundry out to the washer. Although my area is lucky enough to have had less smokey days, the season still doesn’t feel real. I want to wear long sleeves and drink something artificially flavored! I want to need a scarf because I am asthmatic and my chest is getting cold! I’m unlearning the East Coast hegemonic conditioning of “4 seasons” since I’ve been living in California for so long, but the seasons feel so, so fake in quarantine. I love fall, but like, is it really here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-the-high-school-musical-trilogy&quot;&gt;📽️ The High School Musical Trilogy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner and I have been going through the &lt;em&gt;High School Musical&lt;/em&gt; trilogy these past few days, just for fun, and hey! They’re still great, better than &lt;em&gt;La La Land.&lt;/em&gt; After watching &lt;em&gt;Down to Earth with Zac Efron,&lt;/em&gt; I think I have a different fondness for him, because I’m seeing Troy in a different light than I had before. He’s a good boy! They’re all on Disney+, go have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-rookie-print-sale&quot;&gt;🔗 Rookie Print Sale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few days left to buy a very cool print or sticker set from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rookieprintsale.com&quot;&gt;Rookie Print Sale&lt;/a&gt;, a fundraiser donating 100% of the proceeds to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://movement.vote/&quot;&gt;Movement Voter Project&lt;/a&gt;. They’re selling a lot of really cool art, and you can help them support a bunch of local grassroots orgs that are working to get more people voting this fall. (Also, if you haven’t registered to vote or requested your mail-in ballot yet, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vote.org&quot;&gt;please do so!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-wendy-xus-interview-with-merlin-sheldrake&quot;&gt;🔗 Wendy Xu’s Interview with Merlin Sheldrake&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artofwendyxu.com/&quot;&gt;Wendy Xu&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favorite artists. She has a few graphic novels out, several shorter comics you can get on &lt;a href=&quot;https://gumroad.com/wendyxu&quot;&gt;gumroad&lt;/a&gt;, and occasionally does these really wonderful comic-essays. Probably my favorite one so far came out on Catapult a few weeks ago, a hybrid &lt;a href=&quot;https://catapult.co/stories/in-the-wilds-of-an-open-soil-with-merlin-sheldrake-entangled-biology-publishing-fungi-wendy-xu&quot;&gt;review-interview&lt;/a&gt; of the book &lt;em&gt;In the Wilds of an Open Soil&lt;/em&gt; by Merlin Sheldrake; she’s illustrated their conversation about his book about mushrooms and foraging, and it’s just so utterly charming and fantastical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-among-us&quot;&gt;🎮 Among Us&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you somehow haven’t already heard of Among Us, you’re welcome. It’s a very silly and fun multiplayer mafia-type game, where you work together as a team to complete a bunch of silly little tasks on a spaceship and find out which player is an imposter trying to kill everyone. It’s chaotic and perfect and I very much recommend playing it online with a bunch of friends. Available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/945360/Among_Us/&quot;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt; (Windows only) or &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/among-us/id1351168404&quot;&gt;mobile&lt;/a&gt;. I also recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/directory/game/Among%20Us&quot;&gt;watching people play it on Twitch&lt;/a&gt;—it’s so funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><summary type="html">On fall</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 46</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/46/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 46" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/46</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/46/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-priorities&quot;&gt;On priorities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what: I tried to do too many activities in my free time and now I’m exhausted because I spend way too many hours a day sitting at my desk and not enough hours a day doing things like “taking breaks” and “drinking water.” Classic me. The thing is, I want to do everything—I want to learn how to make 3d art, I want to play all the video games, I want to be a person who knits socks, I want to make cool stuff with my friends, etc. And the other thing is, I am terrified of starting a new project and then abandoning it. So in my very smart human brain, I only see two options: do all of the things every day forever, or do none of them. Turns out that’s really silly. Two people in my life (my therapist, and my friend Selena) keep telling me that it’s okay to want to do lots of things, and that it’s also okay to give up on those things for any reason. I’m learning this, slowly. I’m learning how to make time for things that matter to me while also making time to take care of myself as a person. I’m learning that maybe knitting is not for me, for example, but I can sign up for a 3d art course and spend a little bit of time each week learning how to do something new. Baby steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I interned at the Getty. My commute to the museum was about 1.5-2hrs both ways, every day. I had to wake up around 5am, and go to sleep around 9 in order to actually obey my alarm. I got home around 7PM each day. It was terrible! I was so tired, I felt unfulfilled by my job, and worst of all—I had to pick and choose the ways I wanted to wind down. There was no time to both play Breath of the Wild AND read. I couldn’t see my friends if I wanted to have dinner with my family. I just didn’t have time, no matter which way I swung it. When I went back to school, I found myself trying to do everything all of the time and never saying no—everything felt like it was my priority and so nothing felt like a priority. It’s taken me a while to start re-learning how to use my time and decide what I want, what’s important to me—these last few weeks, it’s been reading. I’m trying not to be mean to myself for writing not being a priority, or learning something new. It’s okay to return to my baseline. It’s okay for my day to only contain eating, working, reading, and sleep, even if I want thirty other things, too—soon, one day, I’ll have the energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-vegetarian-by-han-kang&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;The Vegetarian&lt;/em&gt; by Han Kang&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my August poetry challenge, I’ve still healthily kept my appetite for reading; it’s September 10th and I’ve finished three books! &lt;em&gt;The Vegetarian,&lt;/em&gt; handed to me confidently by my roommate when I said I needed to read a book for adults, was the answer. And holy shit!  It’s so fucking weird I loved it! It’s reportedly an excellent translation from the original Korean, maintaining the wonderfully cheeky-bordering satirical-careful tone that makes the various POVs &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; instead of making you want to roll your eyes into space. It’s about a woman who becomes a vegetarian after having a violent dream, and the absolute absurd reactions of men around her. The descriptions of food are great. The descriptions of body-stuff are vivid and made me upset (in a good way!). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781101906118&quot;&gt;IndieBound&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/the-vegetarian/9781101906118&quot;&gt;bookshop it&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-slowtember&quot;&gt;💡 Slowtember&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ve heard of Inktober: the month of daily drawing prompts every October that (to me, at least) sounds a bit intimidating and too overwhelming to even attempt. This year, there’s a new guy in town—&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/megaelod/status/1299348851405590528?s=21&quot;&gt;Slowtember&lt;/a&gt; is a series of art prompts for the month of September. The twist here is that you have a few days to complete the prompts, and you have two options to choose from for each piece. I know we’re already a little over a week into the month, but if you’re looking for a chiller alternative to Inktober, this is the one. I’ve been trying out &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jilliangmeehan/status/1300917215731089410?s=21&quot;&gt;pixel art&lt;/a&gt; for the first time and turning all my finished pieces into &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wafflecrossing/status/1301213430691528704?s=21&quot;&gt;sweaters in Animal Crossing&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m having a lot of fun with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-a-star-is-born-1954&quot;&gt;📽️ A Star Is Born (1954)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday was my partner and I’s one-year anniversary and we celebrated by doing a marathon of all of the &lt;em&gt;Star Is Born&lt;/em&gt; films (very cool and normal quarantine anniversary activities!). Although the 2018 one with Gaga will always hold a strange but special place in my heart, I was honestly so enchanted by the 1954 version. Judy Garland is obviously amazing, and the entire movie is so BEAUTIFUL and uses color SO WELL. I love musicals! I love them. Judy Garland will always be a treasure. We had to rent it, but it was worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-5-minday&quot;&gt;🔗 5 min/day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.katfukui.com/5-min-day&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Kat Fukui a couple of weeks ago, and it inspired me to start taking time at the end of each workday to write a list of what I did that day and what I want to focus on the next day. Sounds simple, but it can have a big impact if you’re feeling overwhelmed by everything on your plate or just need some extra reassurance that you are actually getting work done. My lists tend to be a mix of work stuff (finished a task I’ve been working on for a while) and personal stuff (didn’t eat lunch at my desk), and I like to add an emoji to the top to track my mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="💡 Idea" /><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><summary type="html">On priorities</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 45</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/45/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 45" /><published>2020-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/45</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/45/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-distraction&quot;&gt;On distraction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I don’t know how to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; multitask anymore. I don’t know how to just do one thing at a time, start to finish, before moving on to the next thing. I am always trying to do more than one thing, whenever possible—I read tweets while I watch TV, and then I have to rewind to see what I missed; I pick up my phone in between every chapter of a book; I start new video games before I’ve finished the old ones. Even while I’m writing this, I’m getting notifications that I desperately want to click on. I want to get up from my desk and lay on my bed and check Instagram, even though I just checked it. There’s always something new to be looking at. There’s always something new to occupy my mind. And if there isn’t, I’ll find something anyway. I’m working on setting boundaries, on putting my phone on the other side of the room when I don’t need it, on learning how to (maybe, slowly, barely) strengthen my attention span when every day is the same and mindless scrolling is an easy coping mechanism. Today, I meditated for 10 minutes at the beginning of the workday. Maybe tomorrow, I’ll stand in front of the tea kettle and wait for it to boil without wandering into another room to check my email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had trouble focusing, on sitting still, on staying on one task. I’ve tried methods of blocking out time to devote myself to a single thing, but never kept the habit. I should be working on something else while writing this. Maybe you should be while reading it, too. I have a lot of difficulty deciphering between distraction and break — if I jump on Twitter after completing a task, isn’t it worth it to give my brain a moment of rest? But what if I was on Twitter all throughout the task? If I stamped the document I was meant to be working on each time I moved away from it, I’d never have a legible piece of work again. That might be the solution—creating a system of accountability with myself. What does distraction look like? There are two modes, to me: purposeful and compulsive. Sometimes the world is so bad and I simply want to not exist in it anymore, instead am desperately searching for something to keep my mind otherwise occupied. This is fine. Sometimes I am increasingly bored with what I must do—waiting for the kettle to boil, waiting for a website to load, waiting for an e-mail—and find myself completely away from intention an hour later. Yes, the water has cooled before I made tea, yes I had sixty new tabs open before the page was visible, yes I realized I had been sitting on my bed for nearly a half hour while people were waiting for me in the other room. These are not breaks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pkmnshitpost/status/1258402286402969600?lang=en&quot;&gt;Oh, to have someone deep-clean my brain with a vacuum as if I am an old Pikachu plush&lt;/a&gt;. Oh, to pick one task and complete it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-search-party&quot;&gt;📺 Search Party&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This show had been on my radar since it premiered in 2016, but I hadn’t gotten around to it until last week. Yes, I watched three seasons in a week! Alia Shawkat, my Arab American icon, I love her so much, is so so fucking good and I need her to be a leading lady in everything. The first season is the shiniest for me—the cringe humor is perfectly executed, the mystery is intriguing, and I really, really haven’t laughed that loud that consistently in such a long time. Season 2 and 3 are a little more stressful, a little messier, but still a good reward. I am really excited to see what the fourth season brings. Watch it on HBOMax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-awesome-acnh-resources&quot;&gt;🎮 Awesome ACNH resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’m still playing Animal Crossing! Not every day, and not nearly as much as I did back in March, but I’m still very much loving it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/skullface/awesome-acnh&quot;&gt;This doc of resources&lt;/a&gt; is one of the best I’ve seen, and is helpful whether you’ve been playing for months or are just getting started—it’s got links to help you with everything from tracking turnip prices and planning hybrid flower gardens to finding cute custom designs and keeping track of which bugs you still need to catch. It’s a really good one-stop shop for any ACNH help you might need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-new-testament-by-jericho-brown&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;em&gt;The New Testament&lt;/em&gt; by Jericho Brown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m 26 poetry books-deep for the Sealey Challenge, and &lt;em&gt;The New Testament&lt;/em&gt; is definitely in my top 5 for the month! Jericho Brown is probably one of the most influential poets right now and I hadn’t spent too much time with his work, so this was just an incredible evening of reading. Every page was stunning. I wanted to underline it all. I want to close-read every poem and watch the perfect moments forever. You know the drill—&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/&quot;&gt;bookshop&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781556594571&quot;&gt;IndieBound&lt;/a&gt; for your copy! Many libraries are re-opening too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-three-gems-tea&quot;&gt;🍽️ Three Gems Tea&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve been really into finding small tea businesses and trying out their different loose leaf teas, and my newest favorite is Three Gems Tea. I ordered their &lt;a href=&quot;https://threegemstea.com/collections/tea/products/6-oolong-tea-sampler&quot;&gt;6 oolong tea sampler&lt;/a&gt; and the ones I’ve tried so far are very yummy—I’m excited to pick a couple of favorites and order bigger bags of them. They also have a really cute &lt;a href=&quot;https://threegemstea.com/products/3-is-a-magic-number-three-gems-tea-zine-1&quot;&gt;zine&lt;/a&gt; for sale (you know we love zines here) and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://threegemstea.com/pages/brew-guide&quot;&gt;helpful brew guide&lt;/a&gt; on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎮 Video game" /><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><summary type="html">On distraction</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 44</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/44/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 44" /><published>2020-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/44</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/44/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-burnout&quot;&gt;On burnout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many things that I want to do every day that I don’t have enough time for it all. At the same time, I’m too tired to do much of anything except sit at my desk all day and then watch TV or play video games for a few hours until it’s time for bed. But I want to do things! I want to walk to the park on my lunch break! I want to send postcards to my friends! I want to participate in a weekly book club! I want to knit socks! I want to make stuff! I want to learn! But, yes, I also want (and frankly &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt;) to lay in bed with a cup of tea and do nothing. Sometimes I want to do that for the whole day. I don’t love it, but it is what it is. I’m working on it, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so tired all of the time. I start so many letters like this. Jill and I pace this letter very well, and have taken the breaks we needed when we needed them; the practice of writing for the letter has never exhausted me, but sometimes I struggle with content because having things to recommend means &lt;em&gt;doing things&lt;/em&gt; besides eating and playing Animal Crossing. I don’t want to say I feel burnt out from being a person? But sometimes? That’s what it feels like! I’ve experienced burnout from school and from writing and from my job; the only thing I’ve ever really taken a big break from, purposefully, was writing poetry. I’m not sure when I’ll fall back into it. Will I ever be a student again? Am I scarred? Maybe! All I know is I have a headache every morning and I’m still watching &lt;em&gt;Sex and the City,&lt;/em&gt; slower than I’ve ever watched any show in my life probably&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; May we all feel energized again, soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-deluge-by-leila-chatti&quot;&gt;📖 DELUGE by Leila Chatti&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August is the time for the Sealey Challenge, where you read a book of poetry every day (named for the poet who started it, Nicole Sealey, who I recommended in &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/2&quot;&gt;one of our first letters&lt;/a&gt;). I’m 13 days strong, but haven’t really been able to stop thinking about my first day: DELUGE. Leila captures panic/confusion/betrayal of your body so wonderfully and heart-breakingly, composing a true arc. There is a climax point. There is an urgency to continue reading, one more akin to a thrilling novel. The book, as a physical object, is also stunning, which I generally expect from Copper Canyon. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coppercanyonpress.org/books/deluge-by-leila-chatti/&quot;&gt;Go get a copy&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-pride-and-prejudice&quot;&gt;📽️ Pride and Prejudice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how many times I’ve watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/70032594&quot;&gt;this movie&lt;/a&gt;, but I know it’s a lot. Most recently, with a group of friends on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflixparty.com&quot;&gt;Netflix Party&lt;/a&gt; so we could all scream into the chat together. (The hand flex! &lt;em&gt;The hand flex!!!&lt;/em&gt;) It has never once failed to make me feel good, and no matter how many times I’ve seen it, it only gets more perfect each time. It’s on Netflix now! If you haven’t seen it, watch it now. And if you have, watch it again. And again, and again, and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-nory-candy-shop&quot;&gt;🍽️ Nory Candy Shop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LianaAgh&quot;&gt;Liana Aghajanian&lt;/a&gt; tweeted about this LA-based Armenian candy shop’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/save-56yr-old-small-family-run-candy-business&quot;&gt;GoFundMe for COVID relief&lt;/a&gt; and mentioned that they also mail boxes of lokum/Turkish delight nationally…so I bought two boxes! It’s the best version I’ve ever had, better than the confectioner-sugar soaked boxes or the fresher, gooey-er Syrian versions selected at the Arab market by my parents’ home. I got a box of pomegranate and mango and it feels like such a special treat, and a wonderful break from the copious amounts of cookies and brownies I’ve been baking during quarantine. You can look at their offerings and order &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norylocum.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-untamed&quot;&gt;📺 The Untamed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the thing that has fully consumed me for the past month, I guess! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/81200228&quot;&gt;The Untamed&lt;/a&gt; is a live-action adaptation of a novel called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mo_Dao_Zu_Shi&quot;&gt;Mo Dao Zu Shi&lt;/a&gt;—I will let you go down that rabbit hole by yourself. It is sort of about demons, but mostly about yearning, and it’s extremely cheesy but will also rip your heart out a little bit. My friends convinced me to watch it, and as we all know, everything is better when you share it with the people you care about. (Full disclosure: my preamble in &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/43/&quot;&gt;the last letter&lt;/a&gt; was 100% about this show.) Listen: I can’t say it’s the best show I’ve ever seen in my life, but I have spent hours and hours and hours thinking about it, and I don’t think I’ll stop anytime soon. Do with that what you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📺 TV" /><summary type="html">On burnout</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 43</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/43/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 43" /><published>2020-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/43</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/43/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-community&quot;&gt;On community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I think the purest kind of joy is telling your friends to watch a show or read a book or play a game or listen to an album that you really, really love just so you can watch them fall in love with it too. So you can send incoherent messages back and forth to each other about how it makes you feel. So you can experience a thing that makes you feel like you’re on fire &lt;em&gt;together&lt;/em&gt;. I guess that’s sort of why we started this newsletter—because sharing the things you like with the people you like is so, so good. It’s just a really funny, pleasant feeling to watch a TV series sweep through your friend group, picking off each person one by one until we’re all saturated with love for the same dumb thing. I want to bottle that feeling and experience it every single day, forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online spaces have always been my biggest source of community; I have been so lucky to connect with people across my interests and never really feel alone, despite all of the times I have been lonely. In the early pandemic, there were lots of shifts with how people related to each other, realizing they could not see each other or touch—the majority of my longest, strongest friendships have taken place this way. My community is always with me and always away from me, our sync oscillating (different places in life, different interests, different time zones) but I always know we can fall back into a rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-great&quot;&gt;📺 The Great&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very much in the vein of &lt;em&gt;The Favorite&lt;/em&gt; (showrunned by the guy who wrote it) &lt;em&gt;*but maybe a little more earnest when it comes to girl power, *The Great&lt;/em&gt; is a very fun pseudo-history about the Russian empress Catherine the Great, starring Elle Fanning. She’s so fucking good! Everyone in the cast is! My roommate and I picked this show for our mealtime routine, which was actually a bad idea because it’s really disgusting and has an incredible amount of vomiting, but! It was so fucking funny! I am so happy for Elle Fanning! My main descriptor: fun!!!! Love to have it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hulu.com/series/the-great-238db0d4-c476-47ed-9bee-d326fd302f7d&quot;&gt;Watch it on Hulu&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-netflix-party&quot;&gt;📱 Netflix Party&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People have been talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflixparty.com&quot;&gt;Netflix Party&lt;/a&gt; since the beginning of quarantine (and probably before that, too!) as one of the ways to scratch the itch of hanging out with your friends when you can’t actually see them irl. I never actually tried it until this week, but now it’s my new favorite thing, thanks for asking. All you have to do is download the Chrome extension, open the movie or episode you want to watch on Netflix, and share the Netflix Party link with your friends so you watch and chat together. I’ve been using it to watch The Untamed with a couple of friends who have seen it before so we can all yell and cry about it together—pure joy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-falastin-a-cookbook&quot;&gt;🍽️ Falastin: A Cookbook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sami Tamimi is the co-author of &lt;em&gt;Jerusalem,&lt;/em&gt; a cookbook that has sat in my house since its release about ten years ago, heavily referenced and respected by my mom (the best cook in the world!). Now, he has taken the spotlight in his own cookbook (still co-authored) on Palestinian cooking. &lt;em&gt;Falastin&lt;/em&gt; is beautiful and the recipes are really fucking good. I’ve only made a few things so far, but I’m so excited to try more!! The recipe index is also really awesome, especially for people unfamiliar with ingredients common in Arab cooking; what’s even better is it’s not just defining spices, it’s also defining terms, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://bdsmovement.net/what-is-bds&quot;&gt;BDS&lt;/a&gt; or OPT (occupied Palestinian territories)—these terms that describe the limitations of our movement, or the movements behind our liberation are as vital as olive oil or sumac or anything else. I recommend making the sweet tahini rolls, the dough is very good. Buy your copy on &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/falastin-a-cookbook/9780399581731&quot;&gt;bookshop&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9780399581731&quot;&gt;IndieBound&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-apply-for-your-absentee-ballot&quot;&gt;🔗 Apply for your absentee ballot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have heard, but there are less than 100 days until the election and we are still in the middle of a pandemic and USPS is having all kinds of issues, which is all just to say that you should probably apply for an absentee ballot sooner rather than later. (Yes, even if you think you might vote in person. Just do it anyway.) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vote.org/absentee-ballot/&quot;&gt;This form&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vote.org&quot;&gt;vote.org&lt;/a&gt; makes it very easy to do. I did it earlier this week! At the very least, I recommend looking up the deadline to request a ballot in your state and putting it on your calendar so you don’t forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="📱 Tech" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><summary type="html">On community</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 42</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/42" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 42" /><published>2020-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/42</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/42">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-change&quot;&gt;On change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nice thing about projects like this one—fun personal projects with low stakes that you have total creative control over—is that you can do whatever you want with them. If you have a bunch of new ideas, you can try them out. If something isn’t working, you can go in a different direction instead. I often find change in my personal life scary and anxiety-inducing, but trying new things with a side project is exciting. This is all to say: we have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/letterstosummer&quot;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; now! You can sign up at different tiers to get some (hopefully) cool bonus content from us! And we will be donating 100% of the proceeds to a different organization every month, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theokraproject.com&quot;&gt;The Okra Project&lt;/a&gt;! I’m happy we have a chance to do something like this, and I’m even happier to look back and see how far this little newsletter has come since the beginning. I hope you like it, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am less afraid of change than I am of being an inconsistent person. I’m not ritualistic, I’m horrible at keeping habits—most of my day-to-day is a series of small changes with how I approach my work, my life, my friends. There are ways to frame this more generously: spontaneous! eclectic! very cool and fun!, but difficult to assign when changing an Animal Crossing villager stresses me out. I want to remember the facets of change that are good, the ones that allow you to define yourself further: change that builds upon itself, change that leaves you refreshed, change that leaves you excited. The world is exhausting and I am bad at doing things, but this newsletter is a constant. I’m happy to be doing things with Jill to make us both feel refreshed and re-excited about doing anything again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-the-black-maria-by-aracelis-girmay&quot;&gt;📖 The Black Maria by Aracelis Girmay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was seeking comfort and realized more than anything, I wanted to re-read &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Animalia&lt;/em&gt; by Aracelis Girmay, &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterstosummer.com/22&quot;&gt;which I have recommended on this newsletter before&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t have my copy with me, which was tragic, but I realized I could just buy a different Aracelis Girmay book! And so I did! &lt;em&gt;The Black Maria&lt;/em&gt; continues to affirm my belief that Aracelis Girmay can do practically anything with a poem and you still know she wrote it, because no one can do it like she can!!! There’s a signature vibe, an energy, something I could talk about more in depth if I was smarter or less tired. This collection, formally, is so fucking cool; poems blend into each other, it feels epic but distinct. I am always in awe! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boaeditions.org/products/the-black-maria&quot;&gt;Go buy a copy!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-one-anti-racist-action-a-day&quot;&gt;✉️ One Anti-Racist Action a Day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://oneaction.today&quot;&gt;This newsletter&lt;/a&gt; is exactly what it sounds like: a daily reminder of something you can do to be anti-racist, support the Black Lives Matter movement, and care for the people in your community. Sometimes it has a link to a petition to sign, sometimes it has a template for an email to send, and sometimes it has something for you to read. To be clear: subscribing to this newsletter should not be the extent of your anti-racism work, but it is a really great place to start if you’ve been feeling overwhelmed by resources or want a daily reminder to hold yourself accountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-mujis-pens--stationery&quot;&gt;🔗 Muji’s pens &amp;amp; stationery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgive me if you’ve heard of this worldwide corporation before, but they recently declared bankruptcy in the US and I am feeling some type of way. Muji pens are my favorite to write with and their notebooks changed everything for me! Small, simply cute, and just enough pages for a semester! You can peruse their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.muji.us/store/stationery.html&quot;&gt;online store&lt;/a&gt;. My favorite is the purple capped gel-ink pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cute-face-masks&quot;&gt;🧠 Cute face masks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what! We are in the middle of a pandemic! And you should absolutely be wearing a face mask every time you leave your house! I got a &lt;a href=&quot;https://losangelesapparel.net/products/3-pack-cotton-mask?variant=31978394189886&quot;&gt;pack of three&lt;/a&gt; reusable cloth ones (pink, of course) back in March, but recently ordered another from &lt;a href=&quot;https://piehole.bigcartel.com&quot;&gt;Piehole&lt;/a&gt;. They’re making a bunch of cute, reusable masks and donating 50% of the proceeds to an organization of your choice. Bottom line: we’re going to be wearing masks for a while, so you might as well stock up on some cute ones that look good with your outfits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📖 Read" /><category term="✉️ Newsletter" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🧠 Wellness" /><summary type="html">On change</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 41</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/41" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 41" /><published>2020-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/41</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/41">&lt;p&gt;Before we get into this week’s letter, we’d like to direct you to letter &lt;a href=&quot;/39&quot;&gt;#39&lt;/a&gt; for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pymusa.com/donations&quot;&gt;The Palestinian Youth Movement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glitsinc.org&quot;&gt;GLITS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-uncertainty&quot;&gt;On uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when going to bars and parties was a regular occurrence, I got anxious and easily irritated whenever my boyfriend invited me to go somewhere with him but didn’t give me a specific time or place well in advance. I hated the uncertainty of not knowing where the night was going, not having a clear plan. I hated feeling unprepared. Some people have no problem making casual plans and seeing where the night takes them; I am not one of those people. Calendar invites are my love language. That’s how uncertainty makes me feel on a small scale, so you can imagine what the uncertainty of, say, a global pandemic does to me—or even the uncertainty of what my life will look like in five years. I know this is an anxiety that will probably stick with me forever, on some level, but I’ve gotten a little bit better at dealing with it: recognizing what is actually within my control in the present moment, exercising control over those things in a healthy and helpful way, and learning to let go of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m anxious and impatient but not very good at making plans, and so generally, I don’t. Logistics stress me out. I’m not very fun, because of this, nor do I do very much, but most of my near-future is understood. So, naturally, the uncertainty of the pandemic is fucking me up. Choosing to create certainty for myself means deciding to be pessimistic (realistic?) about how to continue and how the virus will continue, too. My future is working from home, sanitizing all of my groceries (I know technically we don’t have to but read the first two words of this), and wearing a mask every time I go out. It also means being reluctant to look forward to anything; my partner and I used to see each other every month, but now airlines are deciding to book full flights? So no? We’re both in terrible outbreak states? Will TV happen anymore? I don’t want it to if it means people aren’t safe? I’m just a year past graduating and having that spiral of uncertainty, contending with it, figuring things out. All of that figure-outing has kind of dissolved, though. I guess I’m okay with not knowing but mostly because I don’t have a choice but to be resigned to it. At least everyone is sort of in the same boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-pose&quot;&gt;📺 Pose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of uncertainty, I’m going to recommend a show I haven’t finished yet. &lt;em&gt;POSE&lt;/em&gt; on FX! I’ve consumed too much Ryan Murphy content this quarantine, but this show is definitely the best and has the least amount of frustrating trademarks of Ryan Murphy shows. It’s shot beautifully, the cast is stunning and talented, and there are hardly any white people in sight. :) When an episode is feel-good, I cry, when an episode is heart-wrenching, I cry, and if there’s anything I need during quarantine it’s honestly different emotional triggers besides “general despair and hopelessness.” Season 1 and 2 are both streaming on Netflix!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-punisher-by-phoebe-bridgers&quot;&gt;🎶 Punisher by Phoebe Bridgers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phoebe Bridgers is and will always be my sad girl queen, and she has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/2xECuqnvvmVktV7UO8Dd3s&quot;&gt;new album&lt;/a&gt; to help you lean into your sad girl-ness, too. I don’t know how to write about music and I always get nervous when I try, so I will just say that this album makes me &lt;em&gt;Feel Things™&lt;/em&gt; in the best way. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/4BNew3AqFCvABdFsYMRiyB?si=SmZThXRySQ-4DXq0ku-UUQ&quot;&gt;Savior Complex&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite song of the moment and I’m looking forward to seeing it at the top of my most-played list in my Spotify Rewind this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-apricot-season&quot;&gt;🍽️ Apricot Season&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truthfully, I’m not doing many new things these days, just playing the same video games, watching reruns of Food Network shows, and fucking around online until it’s time to sleep. Time is super warped in quarantine but you know what’s a beautiful marker? Seasonal fruits! Go buy apricots! They’re one of my main sources of joy these past few weeks! They are so little and far less messy than other stone fruit. A perfect snack. If you’re allergic I’m sorry! I’m gonna eat the last one in my fridge right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-quaranzine-by-conveyor-studio&quot;&gt;📖 Quaranzine by Conveyor Studio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://conveyor.studio/shop/qz-subscription&quot;&gt;Conveyor&lt;/a&gt; is a very nice indie book studio, and they’re currently publishing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://conveyor.studio/shop/qz-subscription&quot;&gt;six-part zine series&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with some cool creative folks. You can subscribe to get all six zines, or you can buy each one individually as they come out—and the profits are being donated to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nynice.org&quot;&gt;NICE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nychealthandhospitals.org&quot;&gt;NYC Health + Hospitals&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve gotten two of the zines so far, and I love them both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🎶 Music" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><category term="📖 Read" /><summary type="html">Before we get into this week’s letter, we’d like to direct you to letter #39 for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend The Palestinian Youth Movement and GLITS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 40</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/40" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 40" /><published>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/40</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/40">&lt;p&gt;There’s no personal note from either of us this time. Instead, we’d like to direct you to letter &lt;a href=&quot;/39&quot;&gt;#39&lt;/a&gt; for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theokraproject.com&quot;&gt;The Okra Project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glitsinc.org&quot;&gt;GLITS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-last-black-man-in-san-francisco&quot;&gt;📽️ Last Black Man in San Francisco&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This movie had been on my list for an achingly long time, and I finally watched it on my birthday. It was so fucking good, and so different than what I expected. The &lt;em&gt;energy&lt;/em&gt; of this movie. Time can pass and you don’t really notice it, or time can drag on and you notice it, but this film pulls you in such a way that you feel like viewing itself is momentum. What a tragedy it got so little awards recognition. I don’t know a person that watched this movie that didn’t think it was spectacular. The cinematography is ridiculously cool—there are so many weird, surreal shots that make the weirdness so stunning? The performances are endearing and just spectacular. Highly recommend, especially for folks in the bay, especially if you’re a transplant. You can watch it on Amazon or Kanopy if your library participates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-cardcaptor-sakura&quot;&gt;📺 Cardcaptor Sakura&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched all of Cardcaptor Sakura for the first time a few months ago, right when the city was starting to shut down and I suddenly had a lot more time to myself. I was contemplating a rewatch of Sailor Moon, which I have always found comforting to have on in the background while puttering around in my apartment, but started watching Cardcaptor Sakura at the suggestion of a friend instead and quickly fell in love with it. It’s cute and fun and joyful and I promise it will make you feel good. And it’s on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/70309056?trackId=200257858&quot;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; now, so you really have no choice but to fall in love with it, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-permadeath-by-marlin-m-jenkins&quot;&gt;🔗 Permadeath by Marlin M. Jenkins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://therumpus.net/2020/06/permadeath/&quot;&gt;This essay&lt;/a&gt; is exactly the type of writing I aspire to, and the type of writing I want to see in the world—Marlin is always so good at identifying the &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; in a game, that &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; that makes you attached and emotional, and making you reflect on what those attachments look like, what they mean—whether or not you’ve actually played the game being discussed. The prose is also just so fucking beautiful. More good video game writing! More treating video games like the art they are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;️-eat-a-snack&quot;&gt;🍽️ Eat a snack!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I struggled a lot trying to think of a second recommendation this week. We always tend toward recommending media that we’re enjoying, which I love, because sharing a book or a movie or a video game with your friends is one of the greatest joys there is. But right now I want to recommend that you eat a snack, because that feels like the most honest and true recommendation I can give—eat a snack, or drink a glass of water, or take a shower, or go for a short walk outside, or do whatever other tiny thing you can do right now to take care of yourself. (My favorite snacks today have been cheez-its and blackberries. In case you wanted to know.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Jillian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="📽️ Movie" /><category term="📺 TV" /><category term="🔗 Link" /><category term="🍽️ Food" /><summary type="html">There’s no personal note from either of us this time. Instead, we’d like to direct you to letter #39 for some resources on how to support the Black Lives Matter movement right now. If you’re looking for a few additional places to send your money this week, we recommend The Okra Project and GLITS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letter 39</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/39" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter 39" /><published>2020-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/39</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/39">&lt;p&gt;We’re forgoing our regular format this week, since what we’re doing recreationally isn’t important right now. Instead, we’d like to encourage you all to donate to folks on the ground protesting the murders of George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and the countless other Black folks who have been killed by police violence. Educate yourselves and your loved ones on police abolition, and take care of your communities however you can. We’d also like to emphasize that police violence in the US is ongoing and not just something happening in this moment—the violence that Black folks face is not trendy! Hold onto this energy and continue to donate to anti-racist organizations and bail funds even after the protests slow down. Become aware of community organizations dedicated to fighting oppressive structures. Find your niche in how you can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-recommend&quot;&gt;We recommend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send emails to your government officials.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.email2act.com&quot;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; has several easy-to-use email templates that you can use to email officials in different cities about the actions of their police. All you have to do is plug in your name and hit send. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://defund12.org/nyc&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; has email templates for urging your representatives to defund the police department and redirect those funds to education and social services.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate to bail funds.&lt;/strong&gt; Protestors are doing extremely important work right now, and local bail funds ensure that they can continue doing that work. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bailfunds.github.io&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a list of bail funds across the country that could use your help, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.actblue.com/donate/bail_funds_george_floyd&quot;&gt;here’s&lt;/a&gt; a link to split a donation between over 70 of them at once. Several cities that have gotten a massive amount of support over the past week are asking folks to send their donations elsewhere, so please make sure to do your research first!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate to mutual aid funds.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t forget: we’re in a pandemic. People need supplies, and people on the ground need to be safe, too. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thegirlwithfood/status/1267572248149442562&quot;&gt;This thread&lt;/a&gt; has links nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refrain from spreading cop propaganda.&lt;/strong&gt; Officers at various marches have joined protestors, but without actual actions/consequences, this is meaningless because the harmful structures that led us here stay in place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join or support abolition organizations.&lt;/strong&gt; Here are a few to start: &lt;a href=&quot;https://survivedandpunished.org/about/&quot;&gt;Survived &amp;amp; Punished&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area &amp;amp; NYC), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antipoliceterrorproject.org/&quot;&gt;Anti-Police Terror Project&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area), &lt;a href=&quot;https://humanimpact.org/&quot;&gt;Human Impact&lt;/a&gt; (does work through a public health lens), &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peoplesbreakoak?lang=en&quot;&gt;People’s Breakfast&lt;/a&gt; (Oakland, also does free meals program), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.api-rise.org/&quot;&gt;API Rise&lt;/a&gt; (Los Angeles), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asianprisonersupport.com/&quot;&gt;Asian Prisoner Support Committee&lt;/a&gt; (Bay Area), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom-inc.org/&quot;&gt;Freedom Inc.&lt;/a&gt; (Madison). These are geographically centered on just a few places, and some culturally specific—please send us organizations in your location and we can include them in future letters!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue to educate yourself on abolition.&lt;/strong&gt; Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1HUpCPvOwUJElxtUP4mCysAY9GyZrSmUk&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; with flyers that present alternatives to policing. MPD15, an organization working toward a police-free Minneapolis, has a helpful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mpd150.com/faq/&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; on their website. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usprisonculture.com/blog/essential-pic-reading-list/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; are some other essential readings to get you started! &lt;a href=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/59ead8f9692ebee25b72f17f/t/5b65cd58758d46d34254f22c/1533398363539/CR_NoCops_reform_vs_abolition_CRside.pdf&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a helpful graphic from &lt;a href=&quot;http://criticalresistance.org/abolish-policing/&quot;&gt;Critical Resistance&lt;/a&gt; that breaks down the difference between reform and abolition.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep going!&lt;/strong&gt; This work doesn’t end today. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blacklivesmatters.carrd.co&quot;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; has tons more resources and ways you can take action. Call and email your representatives regularly. Set up recurring donations. Attend protests and vigils in your city if you can. Share helpful, informative posts with your friends, family, and followers. Continue to listen, and continue to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="💡 Idea" /><summary type="html">We’re forgoing our regular format this week, since what we’re doing recreationally isn’t important right now. Instead, we’d like to encourage you all to donate to folks on the ground protesting the murders of George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and the countless other Black folks who have been killed by police violence. Educate yourselves and your loved ones on police abolition, and take care of your communities however you can. We’d also like to emphasize that police violence in the US is ongoing and not just something happening in this moment—the violence that Black folks face is not trendy! Hold onto this energy and continue to donate to anti-racist organizations and bail funds even after the protests slow down. Become aware of community organizations dedicated to fighting oppressive structures. Find your niche in how you can help.</summary></entry></feed>